All
right, everyone. What is going on?
Welcome to the show. How y'all doing?
You good? You ready to start? Yeah,
we're ready, right? I know. We had a lot
of fun. You know, we didn't pray to the
demo gods or the uh registration gods,
apparently. And they did not take pity
upon us. So, thanks for the patience on
the getting in. You all got your name
tags or some of you got your name tags.
If you didn't, feel free to grab it
after or when you find a convenient
moment. Normally I don't give talks. I
just come and I try and entertain and
then bring the actual speakers onto the
stage. But every once in a while I do
have something to say. So normally what
I would do is I would go through and I
would say thank you to the sponsors.
Huge shout out to all of them. Everyone
check them out when you get Yeah. when
you get a chance. Make sure you go see
them all in their booths and you enjoy
their talks and maybe even buy some
software. That would be awesome. And
then I would tell you that there's a lot
of great stuff going on, right? And
you've got workshops. Hopefully, if you
signed up for the workshops, you know,
if you did not sign up for the workshop,
I can't guarantee that there's space,
but you can still try and filter in
during one of them. You should have on
your chairs all kinds of agendas if you
need it. And that would be it. Then I
would bring up the next speaker. But
today's different. For better or worse,
you got to listen to me for five minutes
because I got something to say. There
was something that hit me and it is
around this. We're going through a bit
of a Neo moment. Why is that? I think
you could all draw the parallel between
I know kung fu and I just give some
skills to my coding agent, right? And
now it knows kung fu. So
that happened. And if you think back and
you think like, wait, how did we used to
do software engineering? Like so long
ago in the ancient days, we would have
to talk to other humans and we'd have to
fiddle with broken environments, right?
And we would have to check out some
open- source code, try and understand
it, maybe even read some documentation.
And then you all remember this. What?
This? Wait a minute. I used to live in
there. I used to try. It was like my
badge of honor, right? We used to go in
there all the time. But now what do we
do? We do this. That is actual footage
of Sid, our first speaker, when he's
coding. That's what he's doing,
orchestrating his agents right there.
And he gets pretty intense. So, we'll
ask him about that later. Because as
we're orchestrating all of these agents,
something inevitable happens. And this
is what I really want to talk to you
about today.
What happens is is that we get out of
our depth kind of quick. So maybe you're
an ML engineer and next thing you know
you're coding React. Or maybe you're a
front-end engineer and next thing you
know you're creating a recommener
system. And so you say, "Huh, what
happened there?" Well, whatever the case
happened, we have now come to the era of
the mythical land of side quests. That
is where we are right now. Right? And
let me explain the anatomy of a side
quest to you in story form because I've
heard that humans remember stories much
better than they remember just straight
facts and data and bullet points. Let me
introduce our protagonist, John.
He's He's there. If he bears a striking
resemblance to me, just forget about
that because we're in the mythical land
of side quests, right? Just get that out
of your head. Now, John wants to create
a simple RSS reader from for like
newsletters to summarize newsletters.
And he says, "Okay." He goes to his
agent and then he creates it within an
hour. He's got a little Python script
and he ships it and it's great. But then
he realizes, huh, this thing doesn't run
when my computer's not on. So he goes
down the rabbit hole of virtual
machines. And then he's like, you know
what? Actually, I want to share this
with some friends. So then he starts
looking at cloud and he starts using
Kubernetes because obviously
he's got seven concurrent users.
Time for some Kubernetes, boys. That's
what I'm talking about. So
then he goes, "You know what? All these
concurrent users,
it's kind of getting expensive with
these LLM calls. Maybe I should use some
opensource
LLMs and I should host it on my own
cheap GPUs."
Yeah, just kidding. There's no such
thing as cheap GPUs. We all know that.
But let's pretend in this mythical land
of side quest there is. So you see my
point though, right?
John started with a script and he ended
up accidentally becoming an
infrastructure engineer. That is the
land of side quests. But this path right
here, this problem, frustration, skill
acquisition, that's not new. That's
something we've been doing for ages.
That didn't change. What changed is how
fast that happens. The speed. What used
to take John six months and a whole lot
of learning tax now takes him a weekend
and a max subscription plan.
So the trough of disillusionment, it's
littered with bodies.
But we are less likely now to get stuck
in it. And that's not just because we're
asking agents to do everything and then
we go and have my ties on the beach,
right? That's because we now have a new
form of interacting.
We now can before diving into Kubernetes
say what are the key things that I need
to know as someone who doesn't
understand Kubernetes so that when I do
dive into a new technology I'm able to
get to the tip of the spear much
quicker. And then after I go through and
I have a session with my agent, we can
have it summarize the biggest pieces,
the biggest key learnings so that we can
interrogate that too and we can better
understand what's happening.
We can relentlessly, relentlessly
interrogate agents about our codebase,
about design decisions and they do not
tire and that is beautiful. So, we get
through this trough so quickly and now
something beautiful is happening because
we're starting to experiment and we're
starting to get a little bit out of our
depth, but we're all becoming our own
little mini R&D department.
So, when we talk to our friends, that's
what we look like, right? In the last
two weeks, how many of you, let's just
get interactive real fast. How many of
you have gone on a side quest like John?
Everybody, right? We've all done that.
So, how many have learned something new
with agents or you've tried something
new while coding that you wouldn't have
tried? Yeah, these are rhetorical
questions now. You can keep your hands
down. It's we know, right? So, my point
is that everyone in the room is
exploring. You're learning. You're
pushing the limits. And that's why I
wanted to organize this event today
because we're all seeing things in
different ways. And I implore you to go
hang out, talk with people. The best
parts about these days are that all of
us in here is our little mini R&D
department. And so we get to share what
we've learned with others. That's why
you probably saw an email from me trying
to introduce you to somebody. I want to
make sure that everybody has a friend or
a buddy by the time that they get here.
And you get to exchange what's been
working for you, what's not been
working, right? Because now you are
learning new tricks. And I just want to
say enjoy the side quest. That is my
spiel for the first five minutes. And
that's enough of me. I'm gonna bring on
our first speaker, Sid, who created a
tool that can take a 1x engineer and
make them a 10x engineer. And as we all
saw yesterday,
he can take a 10x engineer and then
downgrade them to a 1x engineer.
Claude code, please work. Please work
today. The productivity of the world
depends on it. Please. All right. So,
let's get a big round of applause for
Sid from Anthropic. Get up here, man.
All right. So, I've got all kinds of
questions for you. I know that my friend
Janette told me, he told me, "Hey, make
sure that it is actually Wait, can we
set the mood real fast?" AV team, you
all can, can you throw up? There we go.
That's what I like. Thank you.
So, if you thought this was going to be
like professional in any way, think
again. Huh? I think hopefully you all
are feeling the vibe. My friend Janique
told me, he said, "Oh, so it's like a
highlevel fireside chat." And I said,
"No, we're going deep. Sid is not about
to stay high level with me. If at any
point you want more from what Sid just
as just said, just say go deeper." And
this is a bit of a social experiment. So
if it turns out to be a show,
I'm sorry. However, we're going to pass
around a mic later on too, so that you
all have the chance to ask it any
questions that you may. All right, let's
start with this being ambitious with AI
these days. How much can one person
actually do and where are the
boundaries?
>> Yeah, sure. First of all, thanks for
having me. This is this has been a
blast. Uh but I think that that's a very
interesting question because how much
can one person really do changes every 2
months with a new model release. Uh so I
think you have to constantly recalibrate
how much can you really do and it's
quite tough because like by the time
you're really used to exploring the
boundaries and edges of one one model
the next model's already here. So I
think most people constantly
underestimate like how much they can
really do.
>> Yeah. Um for me personally, I've been
constantly surprised by how much I can
do. I think I can safely say like
looking back at my career and the
projects that I've done, uh those
projects usually about four to five
people took like 3 months each. Uh
everything included like infrastructure,
back end, front end. I think those
projects can now be like one person
projects for a few weeks. Um so it's
it's it's really like my the thing I say
to everyone is like be more ambitious
with what you can do. Uh if you if you
think you you need another person to
come join you or if you need an expert
you know infra expert as you said to to
run your Kubernetes cluster for six
concurrent users uh you you can do it
yourself.
>> So what can we not do right now? Where
should we be thinking about like not
trying to push the boundary?
uh I I think you can do everything. Uh
the only thing that that it falls apart
is really reliability, right? So I think
in my in my view today's systems,
today's models where they are today, uh
they can pretty much do anything that
you can you set them to the only problem
is with some tasks that are more
complex, uh the reliability is not
there. So you may have to steer the
model. You may have to point it towards
resources or you may have to tell it to
read a doc or like fetch something from
uh from your like uh uh from your doc
server. Um but it can do it right. So I
think the thing the the way to think
about this is like how reliably can an
agent do task X? Uh and that differs
from task to task. Um yeah. So
verification has always been a
interesting one and being able to know
without me as a human going and clicking
through does this stuff work that I just
told it to do. Have you found any tricks
there?
>> Uh I think optimizing your stack for
verification is really helpful. Uh like
>> how do we do that?
>> Like one example that comes to mind is
like uh a lot of companies use remote
dev environments. Uh and I think
Enthropic has also started to use some
of these. Uh and when we first started
using them, uh what became really tricky
was uh verification using using browser
agents, right? So cloud code has a
/chrome plugin where it can like open up
your chrome or you can use playrite or
whatever other MCP server to to use
that. Um but as soon as you use a remote
dev environment like that breaks, right?
Because you now you don't have a a
Chrome instance running on your on your
on your dev instance uh on your dev
server. Uh so the first thing we did was
we changed that so that there's like a a
proxy that proxies to your local laptop
opens up chrome there and gives clot
code access to that chrome.
>> So it's uh I mean that's for like that's
a simple thing for like UI stuff but u
the other thing that's really helpful is
giving clot access to your log server.
So data dog or GCP logging or or things
like that like anything that you can see
as a as an engineer uh and you can use
to verify whether something's working.
cloud can do that too if you can use if
you can give it the the tools to uh to
access those things.
>> Now working on teams I know there's a
lot of folks that have come with a team
or are here and
are trying to figure out the most
optimal way of having the right amount
of I I know governance is kind of a
boring word but when do I make a skill
ready for the whole team? when is it
just for me? When do I use a rule? When
am I trying to say, "Hey, this is how we
optimize prompts." Like, how have you
and your team been able to really figure
out the best ways to disseminate the
knowledge across the team?
>> Uh, yeah, this is something that comes
up a lot. Um, and I think the answer to
this is really let everyone do whatever
they want and go as fast as they want
and quite quite quickly patterns would
will emerge for like what what skills
are being used, what plugins are being
used, uh, what is resonating and what's
not.
>> Um, and you know this this is it is an
exploratory journey. um you know as the
models are getting better uh maybe you
have to simplify your skills now right
because you know the models can infer
things from your codebase and you don't
have to explicitly tell them so this is
going to be constantly changing it's not
like you have one set of skills that
you're using now and your team can use
that for the next year like your team
can probably use that for the next few
months
>> um so one thing that's worked really
well for for companies that that we work
with is just having some sort of like um
uh a plug-in marketplace. Uh, and then
just tracking the number of uses or
downloads for each plug-in and how often
they're being used. Um, and that's like
a pretty clear signal on like what's
working and what's not working. Um, team
governance in general though is is an
interesting topic.
>> Before we go down that route, more on
that skills.
>> Yeah.
>> Is it all skills? Is that the main thing
that you're doing? You're not doing any
kind of like cuz there's a lot of knobs
you can fiddle with, right? But skills
tend to get you the most bang for your
buck.
>> Uh it's a combination of skills and MCP
servers and then um kind of like
you know memory systems that people
create for themselves. Um and I think
skills are interesting because
essentially they're just like context
blobs, right? They're just like bags of
context. You can dump anything inside
them. Um they're like a more
generalizable version of cloud MD or
agent MD files in some ways, right? So
it's like um they and more and more
we're seeing that the the all the models
need are like access to the right tools
which is MCP servers and instructions
for how to use those tools and where to
find information that it it's not that
that is not easy to infer and both of
those things can be accomplished with uh
skills and MCP servers. So yeah, I think
uh a lot of the a lot of the like the
you know the cool like harnesses and the
complicated harnesses that people are
building can just boil down to these two
things.
>> Any harnesses you have seen that have
been very interesting and you want to
shout out right now since you mentioned
it.
>> Uh
>> I know I put you on the spot. I didn't
preempt you with that question. No. Uh I
think well I I haven't experimented with
a lot of like open source ones recently
but one concept that really appeals to
me is uh kind of having this concept
like adversarial agents. Um so
essentially the the idea is that you you
tell one agent to do something and then
you tell another agent to critique it.
Uh and this can you can kind of go as
far as you want with this. So you can
even once you've built something you
tell one agent to review it and then you
tell the other agent to critique the
review. Um, and so it's I think this
goes pretty far and I think harnesses
that are kind of doing this uh are quite
effective. Uh, the thing is you don't
need a harness for this. Again, you can
just have a skill. Uh, and as the models
get better, um, you know, it kind of
takes away the the custom boilerplate
code you're building for for the
harnesses.
you bring up a great point which is
running agents in parallel and I try so
hard but by the time one agent is done
or one agent is up and running and then
I get the second one up and then the
third one the first one's already it's
like done already and so I've been
having the hardest time really figuring
out where to leverage that. How are you
doing it? Because that is one of the
things where you see your boy Boris is
like run more in parallel. And I'm like,
I'm trying here.
I can't figure it out. How have you been
doing it? And what do you got for us?
>> I guess having ADHD is a good thing,
right? Like that that probably helps the
most. But um it's it's hard. It's really
hard. Uh keeping track of all the
different streams of work that you're
doing is really hard. Uh personally I I
try to make it a little bit easier on
myself. Like I have a system for my work
trees and then I have a system for like
my remote sessions. Uh and the way I do
it is like my I have five predefined
work trees on my local laptop. Um and I
have some like magic Apple scripts. Uh
it's kind of it's kind of silly, but I
have some kind magic Apple scripts where
like I can uh I use Alfred, which is
like the um um the search uh the search
thing and I have a few commands where uh
I'll say like work tree one and it opens
up a new iterm window with three tabs.
Uh it creates a new branch for me uh you
know gets on the get gets cloud code set
up there. Uh and then as I'm working it
also goes and changes the the tab the
window name and the tab name for the tab
that I'm working on. So if I have five
work trees I basically have five iter
windows each on their uh own branch
which is named appropriately and each
with a window title that is uh named
appropriately. And so it's a little bit
easier for me to keep track of what's
where. But it's still hard. I mean it's,
you know, he's kind of like constantly
like uh shifting between uh between
terminals or between windows. Um and the
other thing that's that kind of makes
this even more complex is is like remote
sessions. So like I've started using
cloud code on the web a lot more. Um so
and and I use it from my phone. So like
any anytime I have an idea or if I'm
like talking to you and then this
conversation and I think of something,
I'll just like go back and just like be
like, "Hey, like build me this." Um, and
it's it doesn't oneshot everything, but
it's it's a great it's a great way to
just like in increase agency by just
telling your agents to do something and
then you can come back to it and review
that code and it just spur if nothing
else it just spurns more ideas. Mhm.
>> So at any point in time I have about
like 5 to 10 like cloud code on the like
web sessions running uh doing random
things random ideas uh that I've had
through the day and then I have about
five work trees uh on my local laptop.
So that's that's kind of what my session
my setup looks like but it's hard like I
struggle with just too many things
happening at the same time too. So some
organization there is useful. I'll ask
the audience. Has anyone felt like they
fully have gotten the parallel agents
down yet? Anybody with their hand? I Oh,
I like it. All right. Later we'll chat.
Maybe we can do a podcast. That's
perfect. So, okay. I cut you off when it
comes to the governance piece, right?
Tell me more.
>> Uh, yeah. governance is
so I think what we're seeing now is like
with with agents and with cloud code
like the number of PRs that someone like
that the average person on the team uh
submits and merges is kind of going up
exponentially. Um and a lot of things
kind of happen when when you know when
something like this kind of sudden shift
uh takes place in a small compressed
amount of time. Uh and the most
unexpected thing that happens is like CI
fails. I don't I don't know if people
over here have experienced this, but
like if you have just that many more PRs
kind of going into your system, your CI
systems are overloaded. Uh so you have
to kind of like scale those out. Uh I
don't know if I think GitHub has has
been having a bunch of outages recently
too. So like GitHub has been failing. Um
and I think they put out a stat that
like on average they're getting seeing
like 40% more PRs uh a day or something
like that, which is crazy. M
>> um so
the other thing that happens is like as
people can do more like it's more
important that your product has a vision
that you're building towards uh because
if everyone's sprinting you want to make
sure everyone's sprinting in the right
direction. Um reviews become an
interesting part of the cycle like um
how do you keep up with the volume of
reviews coming into your system? um you
know how do you make sure that everyone
on the team is aligned for how what is
the future direction of the product um
so I think we're still grappling with
all of these things uh the number of
like bugs that your system has also
increases just because I I think at some
level the base failure rate per PR
remains about constant so if you just
have like you know 5x more PRs going
into your system and your failure rate
is about the same you can expect a lot
more bugs and a lot more like um
incidents kind of that that start to
happen. So there's a lot of things to to
still figure out and we're still in the
process of figuring it out right now. Um
but
I think like you my personal perspective
and and our team is quite divided on
this to be honest. But my personal
perspective is that you kind of have to
offload more to cloud. So we rely really
heavily on uh claude
reviewing our code in our like on
GitHub, right? So every time we submit a
PR um there's like a custom kind of
harness with using cloud code uh that
reviews the PR three different ways. Uh
it has like some measure of like
confidence intervals for the bugs it
finds so that it's not too noisy so that
you know got to do a lot of tuning
there. Um and what we find is that like
cloud reviews our PRs really really
well. um you know it ends up finding a
lot of bugs that would have slipped
through u and the human burden of like
okay I got to scrutinize each line to
see every edge case like that is reduced
uh and then what the humans in the loop
are then doing is like making sure that
um you know the from a product and taste
perspective uh the PR is kind of
accomplishing what we what we wanted to
accomplish. So um it it's also about
like giving each member of your team
just more agency in terms of um you know
what they're what they can affect right
like everyone is kind of a mini owner of
of the whole product itself. uh like
you're no longer just a front-end
engineer or a backend engineer or
infraineer like you're everyone's a
product engineer, right? You're
ultimately building a product for people
to use and the most important thing is
that the product that the users like
your product and they and it's useful
for them. Um and so everyone has to
approach everything they're doing from
that perspective and not from like a you
know I'm going to pigeon hole myself
into this one specific thing and just do
that. So I think some of it is just like
a cultural thing where like if everyone
on the team has that ownership um then
life becomes a lot easier. Um yeah I
want to know what this custom harness
is. I've heard the best tack for
reviewing
cloud code
is you tell it hey codeex just went
through this whole database or this
whole codebase and introduced a bunch of
bugs. Go find them. and then it will go
back and will be on a tear.
>> I've never tried that before to be
honest, but uh it's it's not it's not
it's using cloud code under the hood. So
we actually have docs on like how you
can use clot code in your CI systems and
um and maybe even use remote sessions.
Uh but it's it's just a long prompt
which is appended to the system prompt
which you can do today in blood good.
It's like d-append system prompt or
something. Um and it uses like some sort
of like adversarial agents to be like
hey like make sure like you spin up sub
agents to um critique your own review
and only only give back um like high
high confidence kind of things. So it's
like yeah
>> how are you adapting to new
forms of coding when it comes to the all
the stuff around the code like you
mentioned GitHub. I know that I think I
saw something about how Meta has prompts
that are now submitted with PRs.
>> Have you guys gone to showing the
conversations that are happening with
cloud code when you check those into Git
or anything of that sort?
>> We've experimented with some of this
stuff before. Um it's what's most useful
for me is uh is the plan that you come
up with before you before you get
unleash clot on on your um on your task.
So we have a folder called uh plans uh
or I think it's like docs or something
like that in in in our code base where
um every time you're you're working on a
larger feature that might span you know
multiple PRs or require you know could
it could use some documentation for
other humans to understand how it works.
We also tend to check in our like claw
generated plans. Um and I'm a huge plan
mode fan anyway right I I I use plan
mode for everything. I think it's
probably one of the most important
things you can do when you're starting
up a session. Sometimes I even spend my
entire context window on just working
through the plan. Like I'll ask Claude
to interview me. I'll ask Claude to find
edge cases and that's gives me the most
bang for buck. But then what do you end
up with like this final plan file? It's
really high high density um information
that that that's very relevant to the
task you're doing and has a direct
correlation to the um success metrics
for your for for your clot session. And
so we tend to check these in and these
seem to be uh quite useful not just for
humans but also for clot in the future.
Mhm.
>> Um, so if you're like revisiting the
same thing, you know, a couple months
down, um, you still,
you know, I I, you know, my my memory
sucks. So like, you know, I I need I
need Claude to kind of help me out with
>> all the time.
>> Yeah.
>> All the time. All right, I want to open
it up to the audience. We've got a few
minutes. Anybody got any questions for
Sid? We've got one right here. You're
close, so I'm going to give you my
microphone.
>> All right. Yeah. Thanks. Uh, hi. Uh I
was just wondering um you know with all
the different uh points that you can
like put in hooks or scripts or
automation to prevent you know like your
tests from failing or your builds from
failing or your linting and and as the
agents iterate and especially if you're
like having multiple passes or you know
working in parallel and stuff like have
you found like a consistent pattern to
apply across code bases for like when to
actually either apply that or to prevent
it from Like I've just seen cases where
it doesn't uh you know depending on the
way it makes it the edit to the code it
doesn't apply the linting right away or
if it does it I don't know it just
causes a lot of friction and it it works
ultimately the way I have it set up but
I you know I'm just wondering if there's
a more frictionless kind of pattern that
you're following.
Um I think especially with linting and
like uh and testing these things are so
codebase dependent and like framework
dependent that ultimately it's not a
one-sizefits-all solution. Um like like
for like we have multiple different
repos and they all have like one's a
TypeScript repo, the other is like
primarily Python and Go. Um and the
hooks that we have there are are are
different. um they they do tend to like
you probably already have the existing
infra for this. It's just about like
setting up those hooks to uh to to to to
hit into your existing infra.
>> I was just wondering at what point you
put in the like at which places you do
abstract it like because you could
abstract this this technically in
multiple different places you know even
within the hooks at one step in the hook
pipeline you know the different hook
events or pre-commit post commit or tons
of other events that can happen
throughout the pipeline with the file
being edited and closed. it could be
linked automatically separate or you
know things like that. So I was just
wondering you know but hooks are the
primarily the abstraction point that
you're still like using for most of
this.
>> Oh sorry uh are hooks the primary method
that you're using for automation?
>> Uh yeah hooks are quite effective for
for that type of thing. Uh my
>> pre-commit post commit and other methods
of injection or events that happen
during
>> life. Um, we also there's also like LSP
pug plugins uh for for cloud code and
like those can those I think work on uh
file edit hooks. So every time cloud
edits a file the LSP runs and it gives
it immediate feedback.
>> Well, there's just so many ways to do
this. I was just wondering if if you
guys have, you know, kind of fallen into
your favorite ways or things that you
found that you didn't like. Uh I think
for me personally I like the pre-commit
hooks because I find that sometimes if
it's if it's per edit or like it's a
file edit hook uh you can confuse claude
by giving it too much information while
it's in in its like you know in its zone
and and building things. Um but the
reason why we have hooks in in some ways
is because we we understand that like
every project is different and
everyone's requirements are different.
So you can kind of hook in according to
your your project's uh kind of
requirements.
>> Thank you.
Um how
>> hey Sid Sid um
every tool that gets created to solve a
problem obviously creates new sets of
problems and the intent behind this
question is as a production engineering
manager my job is to sort of anticipate
these problems and you know get ahead of
it and we have talked about the most
obvious ones how to run this at scale uh
how to run agents as teams what have you
but what are the non-obvious problems
you think you know I'm asking you to
read the crystal ball here But what are
the non-obvious problems that you think
that most people don't know about and
what problems do you envision these
tools being created that we need to
start looking at?
>> Yeah, it's a good one. Uh I think CI was
a non-obvious problem that at least for
me I I didn't uh I didn't out of
everything that could break, I I didn't
think that CI would start breaking um
just because of how many new PRs are
going in. Uh I think more generally
speaking though uh I think the kinds of
problems that emerge now are more about
like product and vision problems rather
than like coding problems right I think
coding and the actual execution of your
tasks is is getting abstracted away
quite quickly and then kind of what
happens next is like okay if you can
build anything uh and the cost of
building something is close to zero or
trending towards zero uh what matters
now is like what you choose to build uh
and and and I think That's kind of where
the problem is going to be. Um,
you're going to switch the problem from
like how fast can I build this and how
to build this to what should I build.
Um, yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Um, Sid, I was curious about uh your
take on context window capacity. Sorry.
Yeah.
>> Um, you mentioned, you know, sometimes
you use up the whole context window in a
plan mode and I think most of us who
have experimented are aware of like the
dumb zone where the agent starts to tip
over and give you bad outputs. I was
curious as we're moving towards larger
models that have like the million token
window. Do you feel like there's still a
point which you should kind of avoid? Is
it still 60% which I kind of understand
is the the given best practice today or
you know what's your thoughts on that?
Um yeah I think like as the models get
better uh they also get better at
utilizing their context window more
efficiently. Uh so if I look back at
like I don't know sonnet 35 or something
like it it definitely it was there was a
very clear mark around like the 100k
110k token window where it was like it's
falling off the cliff let's like do
something else. Uh I think uh the models
are progressively getting better at
that. So and I'm hoping that they
continue to do so. Um, my personal
experience with Opus 46 has been that it
it's a it's like a vibe thing. Like
sometimes it's in the zone and it's
building things and it's like going down
the right it's it's it's chosen the the
right way to go solve a problem and I'll
just like let it fly and it like autoco
compacts and does it thing. Uh,
sometimes I I find that I have to fight
with it a little bit, you know, like I'm
steering it, I'm, you know, going back
and forth. I'm still ideulating. I I
myself don't really know how I want to
build this and in those cases I still do
find that sometimes it kind of gets
confused later and in I think that's
when like having a plan file is really
really helpful because this plan file
can kind of have keep your most
important state and then you can just
clear the context and start again from
the same file. Um so it's it's a it's I
don't have a hard and fast rule around
like oh 70 70% like you know clear it.
It just depends on on the use case and
it's it's it's kind of vibe based.
>> Last one.
>> Yeah. Hi. Uh yeah, I was curious. You
you mentioned using agents for code
review and like we're doing that
obviously, but like there's trust issues
with like do you trust the code review?
And so I'm curious, that's a real
bottleneck. Like what do you view today
the role of humans for code review and
where do you see that going?
>> Yeah. Um,
some of this is uh prompt tuning, right?
Like what we've we've been through many
many iterations of our like code review
uh agents as I'm sure like a lot of you
have too. Um, and improving the prompt
and like improving maybe the harness for
the for the code reviews has material
impact on the quality of the code
reviews. Uh when we started off we were
we were seeing that clock like we would
get three four five comments on every PR
and and people would just lose trust on
those comments. Um it was too much
signal too much noise not enough signal
right uh and as soon as you for any
product like as soon as you have that
like you lose trust immediately. Uh so
the number one thing that we we focused
on was like how do we reduce these like
five to 10 comments into just like two
comments right like let's say we we we
we only focus on the high priority ones
even if we have high certainty but low
priority we like let it go u so some of
it is just like prompt tuning and also
the models getting better I think like
Opus 46 is much much better at code
reviews than uh Sonet 35 was and I I I
presume this is going to continue to to
be the But do you do you have other
humans reviewing like the the human who
wrote the code and generated the PR, do
you have a different human that's
reviewing those comments and are they
doing a thorough job? Like what's the
responsibility there and and how do you
see that trend?
>> Yeah, I think like for for the cloud
code team, everyone's really good about
taking ownership of the code that
they're writing. Uh so effectively if my
claude wrote something that broke
production it's it's my claude's job to
go and fix it later right so like uh
it's
but that wasn't Jess but really though
like it's it's if you're submitting
something I I think okay let me rephrase
this I think the bars for approving PRs
has gone down in my opinion right like
people are people are more willing to
accept things than not, especially if
it's been reviewed by claude and they've
like unleashed their claw on it. Um,
however, the buck stops with the person
who wrote the code. So, I think you need
like the person who's writing the code
needs to be more responsible for like
let's assume that you had no PR reviews
and you had no branch protections in
your codebase, right? Anyone could just
push domain whenever they wanted to. And
that's actually how the cloud code repo
was for like the first like two or three
months when we were building like we we
were just like yoloing changes in it.
Uh, and our velocity was incredible. we
would break things but then we would fix
them immediately after. Um and something
that like Adam one of Adam Wolf who's on
our team um he he says is uh quick
remediation is much better than
proactive um proactively trying to catch
bugs like you will have bugs no matter
what happens 100% or like there's
nothing you can do in this world that
would like prevent any single bug from
getting in but what's most important is
like how are you quick to to to to
rectify it and fix it going forward. Um,
and so I think that's some of the kind
of a thing that we've taken as well.
>> Amazing. Sid, give it up for Sid. Thank
you.
>> Thank you, dude.
>> Awesome.
Hey, he's there. You give a big round of
applause for Scott.
>> Yes. There you go.
Come on up, man.
>> You got the pointer here
>> and it is all yours.
>> I thought you were going to make me grab
one of the chairs, too, so I was
preparing. Um,
>> you never know.
>> Cool. Thanks, Demetrius.
>> Um, hi folks. I'm Scott. I'm co-founder
and CEO at Kilo. We are the all-in-one
agentic engineering platform. Um,
there's a lot of slides. Um, so I'm here
to tell you about all the lessons we
learned. So Kilo we we started as a
company in March so this time last year
we launched in May and since then we've
processed over I think the agenda
originally said 20 trillion tokens but
since we submitted this talk a month ago
we are now at 25 trillion tokens. Um and
so our goal is just to kind of share
some of the learnings some of the
bruises some of the bumps we've had
along the way. Um we probably learned
maybe 25 trillion lessons but I will
keep it to a handful because I know we
only have like 20 minutes. Um but really
excited to share what we've learned.
I've got some time for questions at the
end. Um feel free to save them up and
then we can dig in. So uh before we dig
into the lessons, I really want to talk
about the transformation that we're
seeing within the entire industry and
this is this is pretty personal for Kilo
because this is the journey I've seen in
the Kilo team. Um what's changing is um
the the dev team is evolving. Uh if you
looked at what a team was capable of
maybe a year ago, this time in March, um
they were shipping one feature every two
to three weeks and kilo included. Uh
where we are today, it's orders of
magnitude different. We are shipping one
to two features a week. And what's
changing is not, you know, we didn't
quadruple the team. We didn't change the
deadlines. We're not 996ing. Um what
we're doing is we stopped working like
it's 2023 and we started working like
it's 2027. Um and that's just that kind
of fundamental shift uh that I'm going
to unpack a little bit on the next
slide. Um what's what's really changing
and again we've seen this firsthand at
Kilo is um the role of the developers
completely changing. Um you know there's
some people that are already doing this
and there are going to be some people
that are going to take another five 10 5
to 10 years to get there. But this is
what high performing teams are doing
right now. Um the old paradigm developer
is code monkey. You are writing every
line of code. You're doing templates.
You're doing boilerplate. Um you're
collaborating. There's an alignment
meeting and there's a review meeting and
then there's like a dock that you know
with the product requirements that sits
open for two weeks that someone
everybody has to like touch before you
even start coding. Um, and then you're
always just kind of waiting on someone
or context switching like I'm doing a
task, I'm sending it, you know, for an
input and then I got to switch to
another task. Um, what's happening
instead is that um the developer is
becoming the orchestrator. They're um
managing AI agents. They're guiding the
vision. They're doing the things that
humans are are really really good at.
Um, and then what we're also doing at
Kilo, um, and take this, please take
this the right way, is like we try to
avoid collaboration at all costs. We are
very anti- collaboration. Um, big, you
know, shout out to the Post Hog team.
They have a great blog post on kind of
the downside of collaboration. Um, yes,
our our engineers do talk to other
engineers, but we make sure it's not the
default. We you only are supposed to
kind of collaborate with someone if you
really need to, and it adds value. Um
because I think a lot of times a lot of
this collaboration is kind of like
almost like a I know like a safety
blanket that that people do just to feel
comfortable and when you strip it away
it's like you really don't need it. Um
and then so you've got these you know
and I guess the other thing is just
because we're not collaborating we're
doing N10 ownership. So at Kilo every
engineer owns a feature. It is not a
team that owns a feature. There's only
one engineer per feature. Uh Sesh, for
example, owns code reviews from end to
end, from conception to coding to
deploying to actually working directly
with the end users to get feedback and
to iterate. And so we're we're we're
kind of avoiding those velocity killers
and we're instead leaning into these
velocity multipliers. And and what we
found is like in the age of AI, I guess
coding is the easy part and the
bottleneck is no longer the coding, it's
kind of all the process. And so those
are some of the biggest gains we've seen
at Kilo and what's really kind of
unlocked our speed. And you know, we
have a saying at Kilo, which is the
proof is in production. Uh, I encourage
you all to take a look at like our
product product release notes every
Friday. Um, we ship and we ship fast.
And I think we only have like um 15
engineers at the time. And, uh, just
kind of that's kind of showing you you
what's what's possible when um when
you've kind of gone all in on AI and and
minimizing velocity killers. Uh, but I
think what's important to remember is
that everybody in this room, I think, is
very bought into everything I said. Like
I'm sure you were nodding like uhhuh
uhhuh uhhuh we do that we do that we'd
like to do that but not everybody is um
over kind of half of engine around half
of devs don't even use AI
every day uh threearters aren't using it
to do kind of monitoring and deployment
and you know at kilo we've seen some of
the biggest gains and honestly some of
the most boring things have been
automated away in terms of monitoring
and deployment and yet 75% of people
three quarters are not doing that um and
And then you've got the kind of 16% that
I call like, you know, putting their
head in the sand. Um that's that's real
like outside of the bay, outside of this
room. Um there's a lot of people in the
world that are still kind of getting up
that learning curve. And um you know,
I'm going to talk to you about how we've
at Kilo have ourselves got up that
learning curve and um how we've seen our
end users uh get up that learning curve.
Uh and we speak from experience. We've
had 25 plus trillion tokens processed
since we launched in May. Um, and over
1.5 million developers. And so what
we've done is we've kind of combined
some anecdotes from talking to users and
actually the the data we min to to pull
some lessons on kind of what mistakes we
made and maybe uh you can avoid making.
Um, I think the first thing is that
developers don't just like jump into AI.
They're not like, you know, um, the
Matrix. It's not like I know gung fu
right away. You plug in. Um, it's a
journey. You have to climb and you have
to earn it. And so I kind of think of it
as like autocomplete is that like
gateway drug. You know, you're in
control. You're tabbing. Um, you don't
even think of it as like AI. It's just,
you know, autocomplete. Um, and again,
you don't have to think about it. Then
you start to chat. You're you're still
in control. You're asking questions.
You're you're kind of giving it the
right context. Um and you know and then
you've got um like single agent you're
delegating you know one task and you're
kind of watching it and like honestly
that's where we were probably August
September is single agent. I kind of
think of that as you know when you were
kind of getting your driver's lesson
when like you're in a car but there's
like you're in the driver's seat but
there's also like the instructor has
their own steering wheel. That's like
you give AI the steering wheel but you
also have a secret steering wheel and a
secret brake that you can stop at any
time. Um, and then the last step is is
orchestration where you're kind of going
deep. You are actually your role has
changed to being very hands-off and
letting the agents run. Um, and at that
point, it's like AI's got the wheel, you
better pray. Um, and in order to get up
that that kind of ladder, you have to
give more and more trust. And we saw
that even at Kilo when when a developer
you know we will often have developers
join Kilo and um they'll come from a
traditional company that's operating in
2023 and we'll see that journey is you
know usually it takes a week but you
know at first they're kind of very much
in control and then they start to see
the people around them moving faster and
faster and kind of see what's capable
and then they earn the trust and they
get up to orchestration and so now at
Kilo at any given time our developers
are using two three four um parallel
agents breaking up what their tasks are
and and kind of their role is is
essentially orchestrator of agents. Um
but I think on that ladder what we
really learned from kind of looking at
user data from our experience is that
like at any point the the the trust can
can be broken and you kind of just fall
down the ladder. Um, you know, for
example, if you're getting a few set
slow suggestions in a row, I'm turning
off autocomplete. And you know, we even
noticed that when our latency peaked at
uh 200 milliseconds, usage went down.
And I mean, I think that's what we've
been obsessively focused on is
monitoring how how usage is kind of
trending and obsessing about how to make
it faster and faster because latency is
real. If you're t typing and it's like
suggest something and you've already
moved on or it's not relevant again,
trust is lost. Um, if your agent is
editing in the wrong file path, you're
just like, whoa, this is scary. I'm not
going to do it. Um, and then if you have
an orchestrator and you know,
everybody's like, "Yeah, you just tell
AI and it just does stuff." Um, and then
every 30 30 seconds it's like, "Hey, uh,
can I have permission or can you review
that?" or maybe it's just coming up with
terrible suggestions and therefore you
feel like you have to review it and you
you end up actually moving slower
because you're using AI. Again, that's
an opportunity where like trust is lost.
And so what we found is really important
at Kilo um for the kind of engineering
experience is like we need to be very
careful about these moments where trust
can be created or it can be lost. Um and
and we we we consistently see AI, you
know, adoption breaking at the same
three points. It's it's context. It's
just making sure that AI, you know, the
your agentic engineering tool knows what
it's talking about, has the right
information. Um, and again, you know, we
were chatting about context in the in
the in the last talk. And I mean, just
context is so important. And again, you
got to get it right. The next is having
the right model for the job. We're big
believers that you need the right model
for the right task and you need a tool
that helps you, you know, again, there's
some people that want to know all the
dials and and kind of select which
model. I think most of us just want it
to be done and it to find the right
model for us. Um, and then the last bit
is, you know, AI is changing so fast in
AI tooling. You you want a tool that
just gets better every day that like,
you know, there's, you know, AI is
moving fast and so your tool might have
a sharp edge, but you're the expectation
is that sharp edge is gone later that
day, the next day or the next day. And
so you want to we've we've been really
focused that whenever we kind of get
feedback um we're learning from it and
we're like the autocomplete we're making
it faster and faster every single time.
Uh, and so what's what's kind of the
ironic thing is like for you kind of got
to give trust to get trust, which is
essentially like saying as you get
deeper and deeper down that AI rabbit
hole or further up the ladder. What's
really important is as a user you need
to be kind of opening up the books kind
of giving more and more information to
your agentic engineering platform uh to
your AI tool to be more and more
effective and therefore it will have
more effective results which will then
kind of lead to more trust. So it's kind
of that trust cycle and so when you
first start autocomplete you don't
really have to give it much context. It
has to look at the file, maybe some
imports, may maybe some some relevant
files, but it it's you don't really have
to open up the books. When um you're
looking at chat, then you're starting to
kind of have a look at multiple files,
the broader repository, related files,
the docs. Um and then, you know, when
you've got agents, full repo,
dependencies, upstream, downstream, they
it needs to know the ecosystem. And then
lastly, when you're doing orchestration,
it's not just it needs to know uh the
agent just needs to know one repo. it
needs to know all your repos. And so I I
I'll give you an example. Um I'm a data
guy by background. Uh and you know,
we've got an amazing data team at Kilo.
It's a like all teams at Kilo, it's it's
like a team of one. Um his name is
Pedro. He's a oneperson army. Uh when he
came into Kilo, we did not have much in
terms of kind of data infrastructure.
What he did really effectively was he
built in a week or two from the ground
up um our whole DBT data model. um it
would have taken I don't know six months
in a previous world and how he did it
was he didn't just interrogate the data
he gave he did it all in kilo he gave
kilo the repository that he was working
with the project he was working on he
gave it access to the actually the
repository that had the application code
so what was important is his agent that
was developing transformations for a
data warehouse actually was aware of the
application itself and how it was
structured the application that was
creating the data
Um, and that was the huge unlock for him
is that kind of he went deep in that
orchestration um, kind of tier because
he really embraced and said, "Hey, I
want this agent to have all the context
about the entire organization." Um, and
it it meant that he could move 10 times
faster than he would have because it
knew where how the data was created. It
had the origin story. It didn't have to
ask.
Um,
another kind of philosophy that that is
really important for us at Kilo is is
picking the right model for the job. Um,
and I I'll be honest, like we messed up
here when we were first started. We were
just like, "Fuck yeah, let's like send
it to the most expensive model. I'll get
the best result." And sometimes that is
the right way to go. Um, Opus is a
phenomenal model. Great to start with
architecture, but some of these big
models are expensive. Um, and a little
slower because they're big and complex.
Uh, and so you might kind of get in a
state where you if you throw everything
at the latest state-of-the-art model,
um, you spend a lot of money. you're
essentially heating your home with
inference. It's just like churning. Um,
and it's slow and you're not moving
fast. What we're big believers on is um,
picking the right model for the job. You
know, for those complex architecture
tasks, yeah, start with a
state-of-the-art model for when you're
coding, debugging, and you want to move
fast. Use one of those more
cost-effective models like um, Kimmy or
Miniax or GLM. And I think what the
power is and what we've seen across all
of our users is not when they use one
model or this model. It's when they
combine the models and use the right
model for the job.
Um the the the other thing that we've
learned is that you know trust is
measurable. It's not like this like oo
like in the air like it's trust. It's
actually trust is it's measurable to see
if people actually are using the feature
um and kind of trusting the result. And
it, you know, to be transparent, gets
harder and harder the further someone
goes up that level of advancement in
agentic engineering. Um, when you first
start with autocomplete, we're like, you
get great signal uh to noise. Um, you
get like is someone accepting your
autocomplete or is it not? And I think
that's like that's the scoreboard and
that's the thing you optimize for and
you get huge volume of it because like
just you know tab autocomplete is the
kind of the biggest um kind of request
quantity versus kind of just chat or any
other category. Um what happens though
when you start to get into chat is that
like you know someone will um you know
make a uh make a request uh they'll get
back a result. Um are they copying it?
Are they ignoring it? It's not
necessarily clear if they're moving
you're they're taking action on on it on
it and it's there's a little bit of a
delay. It's seconds and so you still we
still get signal. We still get signal if
if our agent is the prompt is right, the
model's working well, but it's not
nearly as effective as autocomplete. Um,
what starts to get tricky is when you
start to get an agent, someone that's
running kind of long-term autonomously
or multiple agents because you may find
that like the task that's running and
the result happens, you know, minutes,
hours, days later. Um, we found that's
kind of when it starts to get really
really challenging in understanding if
you know the request uh to to the
orchestrator, the request to that agent
was effective. Um, and so we've really
spent a lot of time on instrumentation
just to make sure that we're knowing and
getting as much signal as we can on
whether the features um in kind of kilo
are are trustworthy and people are using
it. And it's been really really helpful
in refining and finding areas where we
honestly need to improve. And what's
great is because we ship so fast, we're
able to quickly quickly get rid of those
rough edges.
Um, let's see. Uh the the the other
thing I want to chat about is and I've
seen this at at uh in Kilo at our team
is
the the work is not going away. Like
it's not like people are working any
less at Kilo. Um and and kind of the the
users of Kilo. It's it's shifting. And
so I kind of think like if before your
world was 20% really deep brain thinking
and 80% coding. And again coding is work
in its own. But what's what's shifting
is you're going to like 80% thinking,
20% coding or even less coding. And
that's quite taxing. I mean, I think
what what I've what's been really
interesting to to observe is as someone
joins the kilo engineering team, how
they kind of have to like warm up their
muscle to the brain to like be spending
that much time thinking. Um it's a real
shift and I I I I think like we all as
an industry need to figure out how to
adjust because it is much harder to do
40 hours a week where you are the
architect and orchestrator and you know
you are supporting it's called 200 hours
a week of someone an agent coding versus
4 hours a week of architecture and
thinking uh and kind of 36 hours of
coding. And I think that's that's
something that we've been really
conscious to support our engineers as
they kind of get used to that balance.
But it is something I think we all need
to be aware of as the world shifts and
the the role of an engineer shifts. Um
and so ultimately what does the shift
look like? The developer is the
conductor of an orchestra. Um they are
the tastemaker, the architect, the
they're deciding the quality gates and
then the agent is just handling all the
execution. It's doing all the typing the
boil the boiler plate. It's hunting for
that missing comma or semicolon. It's
looking up the documentation. It's
writing your documentation. And again,
at Kilo, everything is reviewed by a
human. Maybe not every single line. We
leave it to the discretion of the
developer to to kind of conduct the
level of review that's needed. But what
happens when you get to this world, um,
you're seeing that's when you're seeing
the the 10% improvements in shipping
velocity. And again, like I said, we
have a saying at Kilo, which is the
proof is in production. Um, really don't
believe me on these stats. Just take a
look at kind of our product road map and
see how quickly we're shipping features.
if you really do embrace this new role
of a of a developer um velocity follows.
And so just you know here's here's a
quick example um of the five out of the
box agents that come at Kilo. We've got
our orchestrator, we've got our
architect, code agent, ask agent, debug
agent. And so, for example, Sash who
ends who owns uh code reviews end to
end. You know, as soon as he joined
Kilo, he used ask agent. He's like,
"Yeah, tell me about Kilo. Um, teach
me." Like, he wasn't going to a
colleague to get briefed on the
codebase. He was going to the ask agent
and then he was going to the architect
agent to help them help him construct
and design the features he wants to
build. And then he went to the code
agent to actually implement. And then as
he felt those sharp edges, he was
debugging it in the debug agent. And
then you know we also have a lot of
custom agents and custom modes that
developers have made within Kilo. Um one
of our engineers called Brian and so he
made Brian mode. Um and so a lot of our
developers use Brian mode which has
Brian settings. And so what's really
important is to customize your team. You
know in a world where where the
developer is the manager of a team of
agents, you really need to have the
right team. Uh and so just to review
where we're at. Um, you know, you got to
meet users where they are. You can't
kind of shove AI down their throat. You
know, if they are just just starting,
you know, start them on tab
autocomplete. Get them start them to get
into the chat. Build the trust and be
very conscious of those opportunities
where you can lose trust. Um, solve
those infrastructure uh, you know,
issues early. Again, if you are not, you
know, solving the issues where people
might potentially lose trust, you can
very very quickly lose people along the
journey. Um, and then trust is key. I
mean, you got to build it to be
successful. You've got to have that
feedback loop. Um, and yeah, I mean, if
you do that, I think what we found is
that's helped us move fast, helped us
get our kind of 1.5 million users up
that uh up that learning curve. Uh, and
it's been something that we've been
really focused since day one at Kilo.
Um, cool. That's it for me. I think
we've got four minutes of questions.
Maybe Demetrius is giving one and a half
thumbs up.
>> Two thumbs up. Okay, cool. Um any
questions?
>> Hi. So you mentioned that now um one
engineer is responsible for multiple
features.
>> What one feature? One engineer, one
feature.
>> Okay. Um when it's not a team and just
one engineer, how do you deal with
things like vacations, other times off,
maybe they have an emergency from an
organizational perspective?
>> Yeah, I mean a great question. We don't
allow time off. No. Um no, it's it's a
No, we do. We do. But it's really
interesting. So, I'll tell you what,
we've got a whole product road map inapp
key, though. And what's next to it is a
lot of our new features is just a blank
line. And the single thing that's gating
us starting that feature is hiring a
person. And honestly, when that person
goes away for a week, that product might
not move for a week. And we're cool with
it because the gains we have when that
person is on is so much more. Um, yeah,
we'll make sure we have coverage. we
always haven't won call but I think you
know it's it's one person team and um
you know when they they're off for a
week you know that if code reviews
doesn't progress for a week SES was
probably on vacation that week but yeah
great question
>> oh thank you uh what if it's a
production issue
>> a production issue so we always have one
on call engineer at all times and so
night or day they'll jump in if it is
during the day and it is related to that
person's feature, they might jump in as
well. But what's great is um we've got
great um proactive monitoring. So we
discover these issues ideally ideally
before they become big issues. Um and
then you know the uh the kind of on call
developers using the ask agent to kind
of understand the problem literally and
what's the most one of the most popular
features at kilo is our slackbot. You
know if I'm making a change to our
website I just I don't go into kilo
anymore. just say kilo extend this
promotion one more week or change the
color on this page. Um the first thing a
lot of times the the on call engineer
will do is like at kilo analyze the
problem tell me what's going on and I
think that's it's been like a huge
unlock because they don't have to search
around the you know search where the the
right context is the agent is kind of
pointing them in the right direction
from day one. Um but yeah great great
question really really great question
cool is it
>> uh yeah uh you talked about say uh from
agent then to orchestration um for many
people they may just use maybe a single
agent say for building for debugging for
many things uh how how will you really
do like the orchestration say maybe by
hand say I use several agents and I try
to orchestrate by a person or you may
build some workflow to really you know
do the orcation
>> so out of the box our orchestration
agent you run like ask the orchestrator
it will break up the task and give it to
the right agent and so you don't even
have to think of like I want to go multi
multiple agent you'll just say or like
orchestrator this is the thing I want to
do it'll come up with a plan it will
kick off several agents and it will just
do it so I mean it's just the idea is to
make it seamless but really great
question
>> I have a question on uh PM to engineer
ratios I think to use the uh 2023
mindset to use your term We usually, you
know, if we think about it, one product
would be like six to eight engineers.
Um, it sounds like you guys are more
towards like closer to a one to one. Do
you see that one to one is sort of like
the ideal where it gets and and in and I
guess a second part of the question is
for the your customers that are using
your product um are the best ones
getting like what do those ratios look
like?
>> Yeah, that's a great question. Um, we
don't really believe in PMs at Kilo. Um
so that's like you know every engineer
is their own PM. Um they are they
setting the product roadmap they are
kind of u they're doing the building
they're implementing they are kind of
everything. Um so we we have actually we
have one PM in in the entire company and
you know this is a great question to
kind of you know when it was a
production issue question um over there
it's like where we found the value of
having a PM is kind of on that platform
on the horizontal. So if you can imagine
all of the kind of the the developers
own these kind of vertical type features
that are owned by a broader kilo
platform. That's where we've seen the
value of having the PM is focusing on
that that kind of horizontal underlying
platform that kind of supports all of
the features that each of the engineers
own. The ratio I think it's all over the
place. I mean I think like we've
definitely drank the the bright yellow
Kool-Aid of Kilo and like are all in the
one one. I think we're probably in the
1% of folks like most of our our of you
know we're we're very big on encouraging
all of our um our users to be kind of as
full stack as possible but I I think a
lot of organizations are somewhere in
that journey between peanut buttering AI
on the existing like you know org
structure to making a fundamental change
and like somewhere in that journey but I
think we're we're definitely on the deep
end on that one but happy to I'm I'm
going to hop but happy to chat about
that I'll be in the back after this. All
right,
>> cool.
>> Thank you. Appreciate it. That was
great.
>> Thank you.
>> That was great. All right, so we're
going to keep that applause going.
Please give a warm welcome to Jess from
Brain Trust.
>> Thank you.
>> Awesome.
All right. Hi everyone. Um, so I'm Jess
from Brain Trust. Um, I'm a bit shorter,
so I'm just going to stand over here.
Um,
so, um, Brain Trust is a platform that
lets you do observability and eval
tooling. So, pretty much in this talk,
I'm going to talk about, um, what eval
are, why they're important, and then
I'll talk through a real life pretty
complex eval that we ran a couple weeks
ago.
Um, okay. So, I have been in legitimate
calls where um teams have told me that
they've shipped AI features um either
one because the engineering team told
them that it was ready um or a PM tried
a couple of prompts and they said it
looked good. Um that's very problematic
uh because you're essentially making
ship decisions based off of vibes, which
is not good. Um, ideally, uh, you would
like to be able to quantify when you're
shipping, uh, by saying things like, "We
ran 200 different test cases and 94% of
them passed and so therefore we're
shipping it." Or, um, to be able to say
nuance things like, um, we shipped this
change and it improved the tone but
decreased accuracy by 5%.
This is why eval are important.
Actually, can I get a raise of hands of
how many people have heard just the term
evals or Okay, good. Okay, glad. Glad
we're on the same page. Um, okay. So,
evals are important for a couple of
reasons. They can answer questions. So,
which LLM is the best choice for our
needs. Um, especially when new models
drop. This is always a big question in
our minds. Um, how does the AI perform
across diverse real world scenarios? So,
for example, it could perform really
well on Python code bases but not
TypeScript code bases. Um, it could do
really well with English inputs but not
Japanese. Uh, cost efficiency. Can we
achieve high performance without
excessive costs? Um, does the AI
reliably reflect our company's voice and
standards? Are we learning from users in
improving iteratively? And how do we
know when something breaks or gets
worse?
Um actually this is a really interesting
real world scenario that happened. So in
April of 2025, so about a year ago, um
OpenAI actually had to revert an entire
model update um because the changes that
they made um to make it more helpful
actually made it too agreeable and
therefore not very useful. Um and so
this is an example of when it's very
easy to overtrain models. Um and so you
want to be able to catch these nuances
early on.
Okay. So there are four major parts to
kind of creating an eval. The first is
you have to create a data set. So a data
set is going to be a collection of test
cases that you are going to pass into
your system. Um these are usually going
to be um your golden use cases, your
edge cases and then failure modes.
Um then you need to write a task. So a
task is going to essentially tell your
system how you want it to behave when it
takes in an input and gives you an
output. So this is usually in the form
of a prompt and then also picking a
specific model to do this task with.
Uh then you want to write a scoring
system. So, um, for your scoring system,
essentially, it is what tells you
whether the, um, AI's output is good or
bad. Um, there's a couple, if you've
heard of them before, there's
deterministic scoring, there's LM as a
judge, and there's human and review. Um,
but essentially you, who are writing the
scorer is, um, defining the criteria of
what comprises what good and bad is.
And then the last thing is you want to
experiment. This is the most fun part
but essentially um one run of this
specific configuration of your data set
your task and your score is equal to one
experiment run. So as you are testing
out different hypothesis and um trying
to tweak things in your system these
will all turn into different experiment
runs.
So then once you have a bunch of
experiments um you can actually start to
compare them. So um you can essentially
see if there are any regressions or
improvements across your experiment
runs. Um and you can also click into
individual rows to see which test cases
have changed.
Uh brain trust also has a feature called
loop which um allows you to query your
experiments using natural language. So,
um, essentially I can ask it, um,
highlight problems in my experiments or
highlight specific patterns that you're
seeing in my experiments or if you ran a
bunch of different experiments, you can
ask it which experiment performed the
best. Um, I was honestly really
skeptical of Loop when I joined the
company, but I use it a lot now. Um,
mostly because traces like long traces
of like like an LLM does a bunch of
turns and it hallucinates or it drifts
is really really hard to manually read
through. Um, and so I find that lube is
just better. It's faster than what I can
do and it's better at detecting these
patterns than I can. Um, yeah.
Uh, and then the last thing is you can
log. So you can just wrap your code
using the brain trust SDK and you can
start to get live production logs.
So the way that we chain this all
together is um essentially you have some
sort of application. So for example,
let's say it's a documentation page with
um a chatbot on the side where people
can ask questions about documentation.
Um so what happens is you have users or
customers that use the chat bot or the
chat panel. Um, and so they um you start
to get live production logs that have
the uh user question as well as what the
LLM responded with. Um, and then
whatever metadata that you want to um
pass into those logs as well. Um, then
you can take those logs and sample um 10
to 20% of them depending on how much
traffic you're getting in production and
turn that into a data set. Um, using
that data set then you can start to
write evals. So you can start to tweak
the data set or tweak your score or
tweak your prompt. Um and you might try
to write a prompt that is more concise
or you want the AI to answer more
enthusiastically um or things like that.
Whatever you and your team um think is
correct for a response. Uh, and then
based off of how the eval do and what
you learn from them, um, you will then
bring that back into the app and ship
code changes and tweak the app, uh,
based off of what you learned from the
evals. So that's usually how it works in
a loop.
Um, if you are the type of person who's
taking pictures on your phone, this is
the best slide in the deck. So
it's the one slide I did not make. So um
but I my co-orker made this slide and
it's just so good that our entire team
has been using it over and over again.
Uh so eval are a team sport. Um I really
like this. Uh eval uh on the right you
can see they comprise of a lot of
different steps. If you've ever done an
eval before you'll understand that it's
a living breathing machine and it
requires a lot of um components. So um
you have like the AI engineer engineer
that is bringing data to the platform as
well as obviously making the uh bug
changes and feature uh feature changes
as well. Um then you have the product
manager um who uh
you know if you work at kilo codes might
just be the same as engineer because
they don't believe in product managers
but um I mean the sorry that was not
that did not that came out aggressive.
Um but like they could be the same thing
which is totally fine. Um but they are
the people who develop hypotheses or um
also tell you what the success criteria
is. Um then you have subject matter
experts um who help label the data or
tweak the prompt. Um this is especially
useful um I've seen in like medicine
fields or law fields or insurance fields
where they are very niche subsets of
knowledge and you need subject matter
experts to help you like label data. Uh
and then you have data analysts that
help you um define the scores and
obviously analyze data. So eval are a
team sport.
Okay. So now that we've kind of gone
through a lot of the concepts of evals,
um I thought it would be interesting to
uh tie it to a real life scenario, a
real life eval. Um so I wanted to talk
about an eval that I ran to measure
which one is better, a gentic search or
vector search.
Uh this was actually an idea from our
CEO Anker. Um he often pings me with
things I should eval. I do ignore him
about 99% of the time. But this one was
interesting. So he is on Twitter a lot.
Um and he sent our Slack channel this
article from Cursor um talking about how
um they use semantic search also know I
call it agentic search um to
significantly improve their coding agent
experience or performance. Um and uh
after a quick search online I did see
there was a lot of discourse about
whether aentic search or vector search
was better. Um, and I just thought it
would be an interesting thing to
independently eval. So, we did that.
Um, okay. So, because we were comparing
aentic search and vector search, I just
thought it'd be good to get us all on
the same page about what vector search
is. So, um, vector search is essentially
the process of converting data uh like
text or code into numerical
representations called embeddings. Uh,
these embeddings capture semantic
meaning. So similar items will live
closer together in a very
highdimensional space. So if you look at
the chart on the right, you'll see that
um words like wild west and broncos are
close together. Uh basketball and soccer
are close together and antelope and
wildbeast are close together. Um
obviously this is a 2D representation,
but you can kind of imagine this in an
nspace dimension. Um and then what
happens is that these embeddings get
chunked up and stored into aector
database like pine cone. Um so for
example if I were to ask uh where does
the database logic in my codebase live?
Um essentially my codebase would be
vectorzed and embedded and stored into
my vector DB. Uh and then the vector DB
would find the closest embeddings that
match my query. So words like database
or logic.
Okay. So then what is agentic search? Um
also known as semantic search. Um so
agentic search is what tools like cloud
code uses. Um and essentially what
happens is the LLM has access to CLI uh
command tools like GP or find ls cat
things like that. And it basically reads
the code very similar to how a human
would. Um, so it would search for a
function name, open the file, read the
file, sees that the file calls another
piece of logic or another function, uh,
and then follow that reference and
repeat until it finds whatever it needs
to. So it's more like how a real human
would act. So that's the difference
between agentic and vector search.
Okay, so now that we understand the
differences, um, let's build an eval to
see which one worked better or works
better.
Um okay so for this uh experiment design
I created um two different data sets. So
the first one uh was using Microsoft's
TypeScript Go repo. Uh essentially what
we did is we pulled merged PRs from that
codebase. Um anything with the word fix
in the title. Uh and then from there we
checked out the parent commit so that
the codebase was in a known buggy state
essentially before the fix. Um and then
we used claude to synthesize a bug
description for that PR diff. So
essentially we're trying to get like a
format like a linear task or like bug
ticket. Uh and that way we can uh pass
it into the agent and tell it to find
the bug and fix it. Uh, and then we used
the Go test suite um, as kind of our
like if it passes the Go test suite,
then it passes the EVO. So hopefully
that makes sense. Um, and then the
second data set is essentially using the
same thing, but we basically pulled a
couple rows from the industry standard
Swebench verified. Um, have people heard
about do people know what SWEBench
verified is? Okay, a couple less people
who knew what eval. It's if you read
like any sort of it's it's what like
anthropic and open AI use to like uh
benchmark their models. So it's like
more of an industry standard. Um so we
pulled uh 25 rows from that uh
specifically from the the Django related
um data rows but the idea is the same.
Um, and then the reason why I used two
different data sets is mostly because I
just wanted to have some variety and I
wanted to test agentic search and vector
search on two different uh languages and
two different code bases. Um, so Django
is much more of a massive legacy
codebase and TypeScript Go is newer and
more modular. So I just wanted to see if
there was any difference in how they
performed across two very different
types of code bases.
Um, okay. So the next thing we had to do
is implement vector search and agentic
search. So implementing agentic search
was really easy because uh cloud code
uses agentic search by default. So all
we did was just set cloud code on all of
these tasks. Um for the vector search
variant that was a little bit more
difficult. So essentially what we did is
we um implemented a basic vector search
uh and had the agent call that through a
script. Um but the problem was uh we
still wanted to use cloud code to keep
the eval experiment as consistent as
possible. Uh but the key constraint is
we actually had to prevent cloud code
from falling back to agentic search
which it really wanted to do. So this
took like a couple of days. I had to um
really block it from using agentic
search um and try to call that vector
search script every time. Um to do this
we basically did two things. So I used
um cloud codes disallow tools flag to
block any agentric search. So block uh
calling gp or find or things like that.
Uh and the second thing I did is I very
explicitly said in the prompt uh that
anytime it wanted to use search it
should use vector search. So I believe
this is a screenshot of the prompt I
used. Um but yeah without these two
things it would continue calling agentic
search which would have uh screwed up
the whole experiment. So we really had
to make sure that it was only using
vector search.
Okay. Um one other thing that was
difficult when we were doing this eval
is um that cloud code runs as a
subprocess which means that the traces
were orphaned and they weren't actually
being connected to the parent trace um
ID. So the fix that we did here was
passing in the parent span ids as
environment variables so that the
subprocess could actually attach itself
to the right trace tree. Um if you don't
know what that means don't worry I
brought pictures. So here is what it
looks what the trace looks like um
before we did that fix. So you can see
it says uh run claude agent but you
don't actually get any visibility into
what the cloud agent is doing like what
it's actually trying to do.
And here's what it looks like after we
implemented the fix. So you can see that
now every single LLM call and uh command
line uh execution is logged in the trace
here. So you can see it's calling claude
sonnet and it's you know running things
like find um and read and things like
that. Um and you can also see like in
the LLM call like what is actually
inputting and outputting um to the LLM.
So yeah this was really critical for us
to implement um because it allowed us to
actually debug why certain things were
failing or passing.
And then in terms of the scoring, we
just implemented kind of just one scorer
um which is essentially did the um fix
pass all the repos existing tests. So if
they passed then the eval run got 100%
and if they failed um it got a 0%.
There is one interesting nuance here um
for the SWEBench data set. Uh so
Sweetbench actually uh gave us a test
suite called pass or sorry called fail
to pass um which is essentially um a a
list of tests that were failing before
the fix but should be passing after the
fix. But the interesting thing is if the
fix passes everything in fail to pass
but then fails another test that's not
in that test suite um it still passes
the eval because technically it it did
fix that specific issue. Um so that's
just an interesting nuance I wanted to
note there. Um and then we also tracked
met metrics like uh duration um total
tokens and cost.
Okay, so here are the results.
Um, so for the Sweetbench data set,
which was again the 25 uh Djingo um
related code bugs, um the vector search
got a 60% uh accuracy. So it passed 60%
um and then Agentic got a 68% accuracy.
Uh and then for the TypeScript Go uh
code bugs, the vector search and agentic
search actually both scored 70%. Um but
as you can see here, um vector search
spent a lot more tokens and money. Um
when you look at these results, um I the
one thing I'll note is I would take this
with a grain of salt. Um, I highly doubt
that vector search cost me over $4 per
run because if you do the math, that's
$40 and it didn't cost me $40. So, I I
think the exact cost is probably off,
but what I would look at is the
comparison between vector search and
agentic search. Essentially seeing that
agentic search is X multiplier cheaper.
Um, so another thing I'll call out is um
the reason why I don't have the metrics
for SweetBench is because I was running
this eval last night and um it takes a
really long time to complete and so I
just didn't have time to get the numbers
for uh SweetBench but um yeah
doing this last minute. Um okay so there
are three main takeaways that I got when
I looked through the results and also
the the cloud code traces. Um the first
interesting thing was that vector search
uh returns a lot of chunks of code. Um
so in these chunks of code um there
might not be like the relevant imports
or relevant type definitions or the
relevant um code uh calling code above
it. Um and so essentially the agent
doesn't get enough signal for what else
to look for. Um so for example in the um
SWEBench data set one of the runs um the
agent made 26 different vector search
calls um essentially it was just trying
to like guess and check so many times
and it just couldn't find the right
place in the codebase where the bug the
bug was happening. Um and the contrast
is you know in agentic search the agent
can essentially look for the function
name read the entire file top to bottom
um see the import chain and then follow
it and solve the task um a lot more
quickly that way. So the way that I like
to kind of think about it or conceptual
conceptualize it is that vector search
gave the agent a lot of proximity to
relevant code but didn't um but didn't
give the connective tissue between the
code for it to actually implement a fix.
The second thing is agentic search um
enabled or was able to do a lot of chain
of thought exploration. So, it's kind of
what I mentioned before where it's
actually able to look at the function um
and see what calls it and actually be
able to travel to different files to
follow the logic whereas vector search
can't really do that at least in the
traces that I saw. Uh and the third
thing is the more searches the more
expensive. So the reason why vector
search uh took so many more tokens and
took so much more money is because um it
was making so many more calls um because
it just couldn't find exactly where in
the code um the bug was happening. So
that's why it was so much more
expensive.
Now um the last thing I'll say is I
don't consider this eval close to being
done at all. Like I would not publish a
blog post about this yet. Um mostly
because just from a gut sense I actually
like this eval basically is saying that
agentic search is 100% better than
vector search which I don't think that's
the case. I think there are places where
vector search is better and so something
I would do is one I would run multiple
trials per task. um LLMs are very
non-deterministic and so I would not be
surprised if I ran this eval multiple
times with all the exact same criteria
that it might have a difference of 10 to
15%. So um that's one thing that I would
run multiple trials and kind of average
um the scores across them. The second
thing is um honestly uh I think this I
would improve the vector search
implementation. It was a very basic
vector search implementation. So maybe
that's why it's not performing that
well. Um I'm not an expert on vector
search, but I do think there's things
like um like chunk overlapping or
splitting the text or retrieval models
that can be implemented to improve
vector search. So it might just be that
my vector search implementation was just
bad. Um and then the third one, which is
not really a blocker, but it would be
interesting, is to try a hybrid
approach. I do think a lot of companies
now are doing a hybrid between vector
search and agentic search. Um and then
the fourth is to expand the data set. So
obviously a data set of 10 um 10 rows if
it fails one of them that's a swing of
10% in the score. So just expanding data
set um adding more rows and also adding
potentially more languages or more uh
code bases.
And that's it. That's kind of eval and
also example of how to use an eval in
real life. Um, yeah. I I think I only
have one minute for questions. Um, but
we can do like one or two if that's
helpful. Um, yeah. Does anyone have any
questions?
>> Thanks.
>> Hi. I uh I wonder if you did anything uh
to to try and isolate or characterize
the uh the token usage from
restricting Claude from going into
agentic mode.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um that is so that would be
something I'd add to the improvements.
It was something I thought of. Um the
the short answer is no, I didn't, but I
did think of it. That's
>> um so it was definitely something I
thought could be inflating the token
count. Um and so as I'm trying to
iterate on this eval, I would definitely
probably look through the traces like
the cloud code traces and see if it's um
inflating the token count every time
it's trying to essentially do an agentic
call but can't do it and then has to
switch over to vector. So yes. Uh yeah.
>> And one more question if I could. Have
you run against uh human respondents
>> like having a human
>> as a control group for uh for for a
similar set of questions or a subset of
the questions that you're asking the
AIS?
>> Wait, sorry, say that again.
>> As a control group for questions that
you're asking AIS, have you considered
asking humans for responses to those and
measuring differences?
>> Yeah, that's a good question. So um the
Swebench data set actually comes with a
golden golden answer. So SweetBench
because it's an industry standard
already has like the answer key
essentially that was like human coded.
So we could technically compare it
against that human like golden the the
answer set essentially for SWEBench for
the TypeScript Go ones. I guess
technically because these are merged
PRs, we can also just compare it against
the actual fix from the PR. So I guess
we could actually compare it against um
the actual code and probably use some
sort of like LLM as a judge to see how
close the code is. So I didn't I haven't
done that, but I think that's a really
good suggestion.
>> Yeah.
>> Um first of all, thank you for the
presentation.
>> I'm curious about this. Um I I work
closer to the users and uh one of the
things that we are seeing as we're
building a conversation conversational
product on top of data is that we are
starting to deal with a lot more people
who have smaller attention spans and
what that means in translation of the
product is they will start a question
for example thinking about where can I
get a matcha from there they will go to
where can I buy a Lululemon from there
they will go to the latest price of
Tesla from there they'll go to something
else about, you know, Elon Musk's latest
conspiracy, whatever. Now, what I'm
curious about is it is becoming
increasingly harder for me to think
about evals in that perspective because
the idea of a golden data set suddenly
doesn't make sense to me. I it's
impossible for me to emulate the thought
of this person, I've thought about maybe
getting a synthetic uh agent to like
think about this, but for a for a case
like this where there's no going to be
there's not going to be a straight chain
of thought. there's not going to be a
consistent golden data set. How do you
think about evals and are this something
that you may have published that we
should probably be thinking about or
reading about?
>> Yeah, definitely. So, I think if you are
seeing it in your application or if
you're seeing it in whatever product
that you're building, um that's enough
because essentially you should be able
to log that and turn that and add that
to your data set. Um, so if you're
seeing people who have short attention
spans or are jumping through different
questions or different parts of your
app, um, that should be logged somewhere
and you should be able to turn that, uh,
add that to your data set. Um, so that
would be my answer. Um then from there,
sure you can use AI to add more
synthetic uh rows to your data set based
off of that. But I think that's the
biggest thing is just to turn your
actual user journey into just something
in your data set. Yeah. Okay.
>> Awesome.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you so much.
>> How we doing right now? Quick vibe check
on the floor. How's it going? We're
doing all right.
>> Yeah. I like that. All right, we got
some good energy in here. That's cool.
Good people. So, spoiler alert, that was
me on your app there earlier, my man in
the front row. Uh, I'm your problem. So,
we can talk later. I can tell you too
much Tik Tok is the answer. So, I got
one more talk before we hit lunch. I'm
going to invite up from Union, Mr.
Nails. Where you at, dude? Here we go.
Put your
This is yours.
>> I got a I got a mic here. Okay, cool.
Hey, everyone.
All right.
So, I'm Neils Bentilan. I'm the chief ML
engineer at Union. And um I've been
building and maintaining a open- source
ML orchestration product called Flight
for the past 5 years. Um and through
this product I've been helping uh
companies like LinkedIn, Stripe, Spotify
and more recently uh Mistl help and
build and deploy production grade ML and
AI systems you know from fraud detection
to uh oh let's see oh here I am fraud
detection to recommendation systems to
uh LLM foundation model training systems
I don't do the hard work I build the
tools the our customers and our open
source users do all the hard work to do
all that. Um but today I want to share
with you some of the lessons that I and
we at Union have learned
uh productionizing agentic systems um
with with our orchestrator and in
particular I want to tackle the question
of what is the orchestration stack for
observable debugable and durable agents
and to tackle this story I want to take
you through my agent adoption timeline.
Uh, I guess just out of curiosity, who
here has installed Open Claw? I I
haven't, so I can't. Cool. Who is
willing to install it on their company
infrastructure?
Okay, no one. Cool. There there are the
more secure versions and I know I know
now like ZeroClaw, a few of them out
there. I haven't checked them out
personally, but basically in 2022, I
like probably many of you made first
contact with LLMs that have coherent
long range text generation. And we were
all like, "Oh, wow. It kind of working
now, right?" In 2023,
I went about sort of fine-tuning LLMs.
That was a big story back then. Open
weights models, fine-tune it on flight
code, see if it can generate flight code
well or any other type of DSL or subset
of a programming language. Also started
looking at rag as a system to overcome
uh the context window problem which I
guess is still a problem but you know
now we have 1 million to token context
window models. Um oops. Then in 2024 I
you know just I'm not an early adopter
in these things. I continued learning
and prototyping. So lang chain had come
out already. So I I tried building some
lang chain apps for internal use cases.
I started using cursor and at the time
long range or or endto-end tasks weren't
really working then. So it was mostly
like tab complete vibe coding with like
editing in the loop, right?
um also started using tools like
Perplexity and Claude Desktop and things
like that and that was starting to give
us an inkling of of agents that can do
more than just like turnbyturn chats.
Then last year we made the critical
decision to modernize flight and so we
set out to build flight 2.0 and this was
our answer to some of the things that I
and we as a as a company had learned
building these things internally. So we
internalized all the feedback we were
getting from users, our own internal
tastes of how we liked building agents.
And so flight 2 was our move to answer
the answer the question of durable,
fully dynamic, crash proof with some
caveats uh infrastructure aware uh
orchestration not only for agents but
also good old classical ML and data
science and ETL.
So this is where we built nodi. This is
an internal uh agent ambient agent that
sort of um uh reconfi configured uh
Kubernetes node poolool configurations
for our customers. So customer on Slack
would say hey I want this kind of node
pool and then nod would go and you know
it's kind of like the Rick and Morty
butter robot. All it does is change node
pool configs. Build a few more of these
internal tools. Started using cursor
agents and cloud code uh kind of at the
tail end of that year. So I was like
pretty much agent pilled at that point
where you can mostly do endto-end tasks
and then obviously you have to review
the code and fix all the crazy bugs and
things that it would introduce.
Um and now it's 2026 and it arguably is
the year of agents. And so what we're
doing now and what I want to share with
you is how we are thinking about
productizing all of our learnings. And
in particular, I am uh leading a team to
help build agents for the thing we know
and love uh the best, which is data
science, machine learning, AI
engineering, MLOps.
Okay. So the crux of the problem here
that I want to highlight today is the
agent infrastructure problem. So you
built an agent. Great. That's the first
step. You optimized its prompts. You
engineered its context. build an eval
harness and it works beautifully in
production. But what we found uh in
development, sorry, but what we found in
production is actually often times the
infrastructure gets in the way. Tools uh
oops this is not the latest version of
the slide, but it's okay. I'll make do
with it. So tools need secure and least
privilege access to your and I'm talking
not personal use on your laptop, right?
is like you're building stuff agents
that have access to your organizational
data assets and databases and data links
and whatnot.
Oh wow, it fixed itself. Great. Uh wow,
what was that? There's an agent loop in
there. Uh tools and agents that require
variable compute resources. So if you're
building a machine learning agent, you a
single node runtime is not going to cut
it. You know, the agent may run on a
small CPU box, but it's going to train a
model that's loading a several gigabyte
data set, right? So, the agent needs
some way to provision its own compute
like in its inner loop, right?
Same thing with paralyzed sub aents and
tool calls. Uh, if you have a single
node or some like fixed set of nodes,
you're going to get resource contention,
going to get degraded performance.
Containers go oom. Anyone here who's
trained a model or done anything with
data has seen this type of thing. Uh the
your nodes are killed by theuler. Spot
instance are preempted.
Then ultimately these kinds of infra
failures lead to agent memory loss or
corruption and this wipes out precious
context.
So agents fail at multiple layers of the
orchestration stack. And the problem
isn't that agents fail. It's that
recovering from failure is challenging
without the full context of how infra
networking, logical, semantic layers,
all of these interact so that the agent
can figure out how to dig itself out of
the hole it's found itself in.
And so what agents are saying, agents
are telling us, help me, help you.
agents now are very capable of helping
themselves if they have the right
context even info infle failures if you
give them the right context and
capabilities
and so for the rest of this talk I'll be
sharing not like things that are written
in stone these are just kind of design
principles we've distilled down into six
of them uh I'd like three or four but
you know got got six um and these are
more like rules of thumb things that you
should think about when you're building
agents and so I'll dig into these more
but
use plain Python, TypeScript, JavaScript
or whatever like general purpose
programming language that an LLM knows.
So pick that and those languages will
have frameworks that you can you know
quickly build agents on. But what we've
found is for us for example flight 2
works with plate and python that's just
really easy to to access all the
constructs programming constructs for
the human and the agent to use in
building.
Uh the second design principle is
providing durability and observability
hooks. Then make failures cheap so that
when you do fail that your run your
agent roll out can recover really
quickly and and continue where it left
off without having to recomputee all the
other stuff. Um provide infrastructure
as context. This is a a key thing that
um that we found that's quite quite
important when you're building sort of
variable compute uh agents that require
variable compute in the inner loop. uh
providing agent self-healing utilities.
Um so these are things that where the
agent can fix its inner loop which I'll
show you what what I mean exactly later.
Self-healing is a little buzzwordy but
it it's what basically how do you
recover from failure in the inner loop
and uh a utility in this case would be
sandboxes so that they can uh inject a
little bit more creativity in how they
solve the particular problem that the
user's given them. And then finally
human in the loop as the final recourse.
So agents break at as I mentioned
earlier multiple layers right. So from
infrastructure to network to logical to
semantic to tool execution and context.
Um and actually what we found is there
there are a lot of techniques and a lot
has been written about
how to handle network to context. Those
are those five levels. And it's it's not
no by no means a solved problem, but
there's I think we've found that there's
still a lot of pain in the
infrastructure layer of this. And I'll
show you an example in a little bit.
And I think one of the problems is that
there's a context and evaluation gap. So
your evals typically test semantic
correctness.
Does it answer correctly? Is it
hallucinating? Are I am I is the tool
call arguments formatted correctly? That
kind of stuff.
And likewise, agents typically focus on
recover recovering from these kinds of
logical and semantic failures.
But agents don't often directly handle
or reason about surviving a network
outage or a timeout or recovering from
system level errors or recalling state
across retries. And so the one insight I
want to give you today is that agents
can actually recover reliably from all
the errors in this this stack that I
mentioned earlier, even infrastructure
level ones, but only if you give them
the right context and the right
capabilities to dig themselves out of
that hole.
So context engineering is not just not
just you know shuffling tokens and
getting more data sources and and those
are important activities. These are like
the the key ones that you need when
you're initially building your agent.
But context engineering is also an infra
problem. If a failure wipes the agent
state, then all the hardearned contexts
that you've implemented in your agent
loop is is worthless.
And so we think about durability
as making it super easy to do the
following.
To immediately resume an agent roll out
where it left off.
to share to not re-execute sharable
compute and IObound workloads and to
save and restore
uh state and memory between tasks
through intermediate state persistence.
So these are just basic building blocks
that benefit not only agent builders but
MLEs and data scientists uh alike.
And so these three elements I want to
dive into before going into the design
principles just because I think they're
important. Um and they're the core
building blocks of flight and any other
system you may want to implement. Uh I
think
so what is a replay log? This these
aren't like official terms. This is like
what we call them. Um
but a replay log is essentially a
service that records the state of an
agent and its subtasks at a super
granular level at each step.
And the benefit of this is you can avoid
re-executing tasks, prevents memory and
context loss, even recovers from crashes
in the root agent process. So in this
case, you have an agent. Does that have
a pointer? That's fine. Agent that does
tool call one, sub aent call one, tool
call two, and it succeeds at the first
two steps and fails in the third one for
whatever reason, right? A replay log
will keep a log of all those steps and
all the intermediary outputs. So in the
case of a crash it recovers
tool call one's done already doesn't
have to do that uh recomput it sub agent
one tool call sub agent call one is done
don't need to recomputee now then it
just can pick up from tool call two um
and so imagine this is like a thousand
steps and uh I'll I'll tell you about a
case study of a customer who had you
know this type of very long running
agent with many many steps
So this is super important because at
this gives you this like fine grained
micro cache per run that if there are
any network or system outages that you
can just take for granted that your
agent is going to just going to pick up
from where it left off.
And this is similar to go global caching
but as opposed to this run uh runle
replay log global caching is as the name
suggests is work shared across all
agents and all agent runs. So in this
case you see an agent where I'm calling
it with the same prompt write a report
about lms. It does a web search that in
flight you can say I want to cache that
step.
uh does a DB read tool. I want to cache
that step, but then I want to disable it
for the composer sub aent, which then
synthesizes the outputs of the two
previous tool calls. Um and so, you
know, maybe the the AI builder says, I
want to inject a little bit more
creativity or entropy to that last step.
And so each time I call it, I wanted to
reuse the the research kind of
deterministic tool calls, but then
regenerate a new report each time.
And finally, you have intermediate state
persistence, which is the idea that you
can just take for granted that once you
use what I'm calling, we'll describe
later as these functional uh durability
hooks, these decorators you see on these
functions that you know when you call
the LLM the first time, the output of
that agent state is stored just to
object store in S3 or something uh
somewhere, right? So, you just take that
for granted. You don't need to write any
of your serialization des serialization
code. It's just there. You get data
lineage just out of the box. Same with
your first tool call. Same with your
second LLM call. So all of these under
the hood in flight will be stored to uh
uh your object store.
So then those are the three building
blocks that sort of unlock the
implementation for these six design
principles. And so I won't go through
these line by line. I'll show you a
little bit of code. I'm not sure if you
can read it too clearly, but the first
one is to use plain Python. And the
benefits of this I think are fairly
obvious. You get loops, fan out,
conditionals, try except uh async
synchronous programming in Python and
whatever the equivalents are in whatever
language you choose. There are no DSL
surprises. There's nothing new to learn.
But if you do choose to use a framework,
you can use it, right? It's it's pretty
straightforward.
And this is a point I'll I'll hammer
through the rest of this is that
exceptions are actually a perfect
delivery mechanism for critical context
about failures at all layers of of the
stack.
So this you can squint and you can start
to see, oh, what if I can catch an out
of memory error here at the that the
system actually bubbles up into my into
flight, right?
And leading to my next point, providing
functional hooks make it really easy
easy to add durability to your system,
whatever implementation that you choose,
right? So assuming that you're using
functions or whatever class methods that
these hooks give you the ability to
trace checkpoint and do the persistent
intermediate uh state serialization
deserialization I mentioned earlier
and so in flight the first thing you do
is you define your task environment I'm
mentioning this partly to show off
flight but partly to just show you how
we're thinking about this type of
problem right so this allows you a task
environment allows you to specify your
container, your image, your
dependencies, your resource requests
and tasks you can think of as these
containerized functions. These run on a
Kubernetes pod. These run on their own
container. So agents running multiple of
these tasks have container isolation.
You get a lot of security benefits out
of this as well. You give its own a IM
role. You get a lot of nice downstream
benefits of this. And fly trace you can
think of as a helper function so that
you don't have to pay the cost of
spinning up a new container. This is
just a helper function that gets you all
of those persistence and crash proof
guarantees uh that I mentioned earlier.
And this makes failures really cheap. So
if you have an agent that writes code
that runs the code
and then finalizes the answer. And so
this is our first iteration of an MLE
agent. you have all the tracing and
caching enabled to be able to have build
an ML agent MLE agent that just has all
of these crash proof uh guarantees built
into it.
And as an added bonus, failed runs
become training data or additional
context from the agent to learn from.
And not only is this an outofband
process where you can, you know, query
the flight database to grab all the
failures and create a training data set,
you can actually react to them in line
in your agent loop. And so this unlocks
infrastructure as context.
So this is where the agent can see
things like out of memory errors, uh,
system level ephemeral outages and retry
based on those without, you know,
totally crashing.
And so here you can catch an out of
memory error. You can have the agent
respond to that and provision more
resources based on the error in the code
that it wrote and make adjustments that
are sent back from in the for loop such
that the the platform can provision more
resources for for example in this case a
training job.
But not all failures can be done in such
a structured guardrail format. Right? So
in this resource example, you're just
outputting a dictionary of some
predefined outputs and and values.
What if you want the agent to
orchestrate the actual tools in its tool
belt? So this is there are two types of
sandboxes I'll talk about. There's a
third one that we don't quite quite
support yet, but code mode is something
that I think anthropic the anthropic
team coined. This is where you replace
all the context bloat associated with
tools and formatting tool arguments and
getting the results out of that. And you
have the agent, you give it a toolbox
and say write Python code that's
sandboxed. So you can't do IO, you can't
do network calls, you can't do extra
imports. You're writing pure function
calls and conditionals in your code mode
mode loop, right? So the agent writes
this pipeline.
The orchestrator can run this code
generated by the agent securely in this
limited subset of Python. Shout out to
Pantic Monty, by the way. I forgot to
put in my slide, but we're using that
here. Um it's a a cool project. Um check
it out.
And then you have this really tight
error iteration loop to fix the
orchestration code bugs.
So you're you're you know you're no
longer having to do an eval kind of out
of band, right? You could do that of
course definitely, but you have the
agent just fix its own errors.
But sometimes you don't want just
orchestration, right? So what if a user
asks the agent something that for which
a tool does just not just doesn't do the
job. So that's where a stateless code
sandbox is super useful. And so this is
where you can introduce additional
thirdparty libraries. You can do
imports. You could do limited network
IO. You could do limited readrs on the
file system. Um but so this stateless
code sandbox is not that. So this is
just a oneshot. The agent writes the
code. It runs end to end uh and then
produces some output. So it's it's kind
of like a pure function.
Um, so this is what I just said
and you can even do cool things like
have it write its own unit tests, right?
So,
and then finally, there are a class of
errors for which maybe the prompt is
purely poorly formatted or the system
prompt just uh doesn't work or there's
just the agent just does not have the
context it needs to solve the task. So
human in the loop recourse is uh
ultimate recourse to course correct an
agent when it's kind of gone off the
rails.
So in this case when the agent has
exhausted its max itter budget you can
just have a very pythonic way to say hey
I need more context. Uh and then in the
UI you can type in whatever additional
context you can upload a new file. You
can give it a a zip file of a directory
with uh more markdown files which is
apparently how we do things now.
And then you recursively call the agent.
So the flight supports recursion. Uh
there's a cleaner non-recursion way of
doing this, but I thought this was cool.
So you basically call the agent function
itself with the additional context,
right?
And this is the coolest slide because it
has Wolverine on it. What you get out of
all of these building blocks is an agent
with a healing factor, right? It's not
perfect. It's still going to fail. It's
still going to fall over. But in this
case, I don't expect you to read this,
but this first error was an out of
memory error. And then the red box
there, it adjusted the sandbox
resources. It gave itself more memory.
In this error, uh it had an import for
pandas that was not specified that it
did not specify in its dependencies. Um,
so then it writes more code. It updates
its dependency structure and adds
pandas.
Then finally for all those logical
semantic tool execution failures, uh,
here's just a a simple division by zero
error. So that's error. It just you give
it the error and it fixes the the code.
And so I don't have much time left, but
what does this look like in practice?
We worked with a customer called
Dragonfly who provides a basically a
deep research SAS product. So you go to
them, you say, "Hey, I want a Jira like
thing but not Jira." And then it'll do
research to figure out what stack you
want to use for your company, right? So
their challenge was to build an
automated solutions architect, an agent
that creates a living knowledge graph of
SAS products. And so these were 250k or
so software products. Each agent call
had about 200 steps. Each product call
each product had about 100 LLM calls
associated with it. Um
and so we help them with a kind of a
tiered architecture. And so this is this
is like scaling agents, right? These are
not the the agents you may be used to in
very tight uh chat interfaces. These are
agents that just run ambiently that just
power their database, right? So this
thing will just run at some cadence and
populate their database that powers
their their um their SAS product. And so
at the top you have the agent driver. So
you have four replicas. You have
research coordinators that have eight
replicas. You have underneath that 12
researchers. And yet underneath that are
tool 12 replicas of a tool layer that
each researcher has access to.
And so we help them do crossr run
caching. Right? So this is a global
cache I mentioned earlier. So they don't
have to re double pay for LLM API calls
given the same research prompt.
They did this really cool thing that I
need to learn more about, but it's
basically semantic conversion detection.
So every once in a while, the
coordinator layer would look at all the
research threads they were spinning up
and based on some similarity, semantic
similarity, they would group and
consolidate them. so as to avoid
duplicate work for their researchers.
Checkpoint based recovery. This is what
I talked about with the durability
piece. Uh they use spot instances
heavily to reduce costs and it became
basically a non-issue. Spot instances
would go away. They would come back a
few seconds later and you wouldn't lose
any progress.
And you have full auditability. Every
single LLM call or every single tool
crawl is traced.
And so the result is I actually
onboarded them. So I helped them and
within an hour they onboarded their
local BAML agent prototype into
production in about an hour. And this
got them two 2,000 plus concurrent runs.
And the onboarding was really because it
was just Python just like here's the
task config here's the decorators just
go do your thing.
Reduce their recovery failure recovery
time by 50%. Increase their development
velocity by 30%. and uh they save 12
hours a week on infrastructure
maintenance because of this. So in
conclusion,
if you're an agent builder or starting
to build agents, do yourself a favor and
your agents a favor. Um consider that
observability is necessary but not
sufficient. Durability helps rec agents
recover quickly. Don't aim for failure
proof. Aim for cheap failures, fast
recovery, and a very tight quick agent
loop feedback.
Think about infrastructure as context.
So when you begin, you're starting
probably with a single node, but when
you start scaling out this, you're going
to start feeling this pain. And secure
sandboxes facilitate self-healing in
that in the inner loop, the agent can
fix bugs and build itself new tools as
needed. Help your agents help
themselves.
Thank you.
We got time for a question. Who's got a
question around here? Anybody? Let's
see. Let's see.
I
>> think people are hungry.
>> We got one over here.
>> Wondering if you've uh got got an
opinion on what the right size and
number of agent tiers are. You you
showed an example of four tiers. Is that
typical or
that was special just because they they
had a pretty scaled out use case like um
as so as you saw it was like 200 steps
100 100 LLM calls per software product
and that's non-deterministic too like
for any given prompt highle prompt to
populate a particular SAS product you
don't know how many research threads are
going to happen right so I think that to
from my experience at least At least
that's kind of like the upper limit of
scale that I've seen so far. Um,
generally it's just an agent and a sub
agent. Like I wouldn't go generally
deeper than that. And even then just one
agent with a bunch of tools. Like I feel
like that's for for at least the
internal use cases we've built that
works really well. Um, especially if
there are uh like the butter robot. They
just do one the one thing and they just
do that one thing, right? But if you're
doing deep research and you're you have
like this coordinator layer and and I
think they arrived at that solution
because they were finding a lot of
duplicate research threads and so that
you know they implemented that semantic
convergence um algorithm. Yeah. But
generally I just start with one um and
then one sub aent
layer of sub aent so the sub agents can
do different things right.
>> Yeah.
>> Excellent. Let's give one more round of
applause for news.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, dude. Yeah.
>> Cheers, man.
>> Yeah. Thanks. Uh don't leave us here.
>> No. All right, folks. Go eat. We'll be
back here at around two, I think. Uh you
should have the agendas. You probably
know better than I do. Enjoy. Hopefully,
you make some new friends. You munch
your lunch with a new bunch. I don't
want to see anybody eating with anybody
they already know. All right. So, we'll
be reconvened back here and uh yeah with
everyone in the company because they
were streaming it in.
>> Oh, cool. Nice.
>> Uh
Yeah, I
Good morning.
Heat. Heat.
It's just like
All
right.
Hallelujah.
You think you are doing
All right.
highlight.
Hallelujah.
Heat. Heat.
All right.
You all were wild enough to join this
session that you don't know what it's
about at all. I'm sure you're sitting
here and you're like, "Oh, there's a
session now. What? Huh?" So, here's the
thing that we're going to do. And it's
only going to work if we get
participation. So, please don't leave me
hanging. And we can't do that trick
where it's like uh you expect the other
person to do it, so you don't do it. You
know, there's some psychological um
thing. I can't remember what it's
called, but
we're screwed if you do that. All right,
we need you to scan this here
QR code. That's step one. Scan the QR
code and it should take you to a
question. And this is the whole reason
we're doing this session is because
folks wanted a chance to share what's
been working with them. And it's less me
talking at you and us talking together.
So there's one question there. You
should see it by now. It says, what does
it say? It says, "What what's your best
tip for using coding agents?" So now
we'll take five seconds, 10 seconds.
I'll tell you a little joke and by the
time that it's done, you should have put
your best tip in there and you should
also be upvoting everybody else's tips.
Whoever has the most up votes comes on
stage and they defend or they explain
what their tip is. Okay. So, while you
are doing that, here's my joke.
Let's see how this goes. Huh? set the
expectations very low. Let's just bring
them down beforehand.
So, I was playing with Claude code the
other day and I said, "Claude, choose a
random number between 1 and 50." And it
said 32. And I went, "That's it. For the
next 32 days, I'm not going to talk to
you. I'm not going to engage with you.
I'm not going to do anything with you.
32 days cold turkey. nothing. And it
said, "Can I choose another number?" And
I went, "Oh, that's so sweet. Of course
you can." "Yeah, go for it." And then it
replied and it said, "50."
>> So there's my there's my joke. All
right. Where's the up votes? Do we get
any up votes or not?
Yes. Yeah. Up votes. We got one up vote,
two up votes, three up votes. Here we
go. So hopefully it filters
with up votes and we can see which ones
are voted the most.
And then we'll have whoever that is come
on stage and let's just see what we've
got so far. Get your agent to create a
screenshot walkthrough of every feature
and then have it review changes before
every
ask it to first understand the code base
and fill the context window. Ah, I like
that, too. All right. Create an entire
workflow for the software development
life cycle starting with project manager
to architect to coding and QA. It can
run sub agents and have them. So, that's
good. I just don't know what that would
mean in practice. Uh, do centaur
reviews. What's a centaur? The human and
machine or human in horse. The AI
directs a human to pay attention to the
most important things.
All right.
Where we at? Which ones have the most up
votes so far? Is there a way to scroll
on this or no? Can we scroll? Is there
So, now would be the time to drop in as
many up votes as you want.
What's your best tip? Long-term memory.
And that gets Oh, here we go. Here's a
clear winner. Always start out with a
plan. Who did this one? Who is it? Get
up here and explain yourself. Here we
go.
What do you mean by this?
>> I'll go.
>> You're coming up all the way. Actually,
you can be right here and then we can
interact. You can use this.
>> Oh, okay.
>> All right, Raphael.
>> Um, I'm Raphael. Um, basically
everybody's talking about how like this
last December was the advent of like AI
agents, but it was really the year
before. And uh if you had been using
like plan MD files, just planning out
your code, what you want the agent to do
before actually having it code, you
could still you could have been getting
the results that you that we're getting
uh this year. Uh I'm an older developer
and older developers know remember when
you had to plan out your code because
you had to wait to compile and all that
stuff. So when people are just like vibe
coding and you know expecting the LLMs
to do everything correctly, that's just
not going to work. But if you always
plan whatever you do, coding life,
whatever. If you plan ahead, you will
always be more successful.
>> Hey, Raphael. Thank you. All right,
we'll take it. Any questions for Raphael
before he goes back to his seat?
Anybody? The planning plan mode? I'm
going to start doing that. I do have a
little bit of a question there is if you
can tell me what you add in the plan.
Anything specific?
Um, so I actually uh always have a a
two-part structure. First of all, um,
you want your plan to be clear,
actionable with code snippets. So have
the agent code out uh or like write out
the code in the plan MD. That makes it a
lot more accurate. But also add an
executive summary because AI can just
write a ton of stuff for you.
>> It can write out a ton of stuff for
you that you don't want to read. But if
you have it right an executive summary
at the top, it will tell you everything
that you need to know and you don't have
to read the rest of the stuff.
>> All right, I like it. Thanks, Raphael.
Let's keep it rocking. Now would be the
time to add more up votes. Where are we
at? What else do we got here? Can We
can't filter by up votes, can we? That
might be too much. Too much. I know
there was some fire ones below. If we go
It's okay. I don't want to put you on
the spot. We got one use broomie. All
right, but where else? Um, do you Rob,
you want to come talk about broomie? All
right, get up here. We got one up vote
here. And then there's plan early, plan
often. I think that goes with Raphael's,
huh? Plan early, plan often. I would
like the continuous life cycle of that
though. All right, Broomie, what is it?
>> Yeah, you mentioned when talking
earlier,
>> you gota you got to talk into that.
You mentioned when talking earlier that
working with parallel agents is often a
pain if you're using regular tools. I
agree is normally a pain. I've built an
open-source project called broommy.org.
That's like broom you sweep with with a
y at the end. It makes it super easy to
work with lots of agents at once. It
creates work trees for you. It works
with all the major agents. You can see
for all your agents when they're
working, when they're blocked, when
they're asking you for help, and it
automates things like having them do
merges, having them write pull requests,
having them review stuff, so all your
flows get pretty easy.
>> Oo, I like it. And you know, I'm a fan.
>> Any questions for Rob and Broomie?
Anything about parallel agents? All
right. I know some people might have
just come in, so if you don't have
access to this, sli
scan that QR code up there. Thanks Rob
for this. Thank you for talking about
Broomie. I appreciate it. Can we keep
scrolling through this and see what else
we got?
What was that? The biggest trip trick is
dangerously skip permissions every time.
Here we go. Get agents to record all
design decisions in design folders.
So feel free. We need up votes right
now. upvote so we can know which ones we
want to get on here or drop in your best
trick and we will have it there. Why
Centaur and not Robocop? I don't know
what this means. You got to be a I'm
like the agent with no context right
now. All right, so get your agent. I
like this one. Who did this one? Get
your agent to create screenshot
walkthroughs of every feature and then
have it review changes. Who was this?
Oh, get over here. Get back up here.
Tell us more. Tell us more. You all
remember Rob.
>> This this this one's super powerful.
This is what I use in multiple projects.
So like if you've got to do manual QA to
see if your agents broke stuff, that's
going to be such a bottleneck. But what
you can do is just have as part of your
instructions to your agents that
whenever it does any kind of userfacing
change. It creates a a sequence of
screenshots with a textual walk through
say all the flows which are affecting
what's supposed to happen. And then the
cool thing is that when you do your next
release as part of the process, it
replays all those screenshots at the
last release and the next release
snapshot. It looks at every screenshot
that changed. It analyzes what's
expected to change based on the PRs that
were merged and it highlights to a user
a prioritized set of things for human
review. This is a major accelerant.
>> But the screenshots are only in the
context window or also you're putting
them into git or what
>> the screenshots go their files. They
don't go into git because it can
regenerate them. So during the release
process you jump back to the last
release for the checkout. You run the
the scripts from playright to generate
all those screenshots. Then you jump
right forward to the new release tag.
You generate them again. You do a pixel
diff for everyone that differs. You get
another sub agent to say, "Okay, this
screenshot,
does this is this a thing you'd expect
to happen based interpreting the images
and and the intents of the things. And
then based on that, it prioritizes which
are high risk, lowrisk for human
reviewer." Massive accelerant.
>> Doesn't that slow down your CI a lot
though?
>> Slow down the CI.
>> I don't do it in CI. I do it in a in a
separate build box.
>> It it's it's really slow, but you just
do it for release. You don't you cannot
do this in PR merge. It's way too slow.
Just do just do it on release.
>> This is exactly why I wanted to have
this session cuz that right there is a
nugget of gold that I'm going to take
home and I appreciate you. All right,
Rob. Awesome. Yeah, that's right. Um,
did you put any other ones in? You want
to just come defend them while you
before you come back down?
Yeah,
>> you did put a few more. Do they have
fire emojis by them? Let's see what
else. What was the other one?
>> Always run your agent in a container.
Then you can dangerously skip
>> Yeah. Come over here. Get over. You guys
remember Rob, right?
>> Always run your agent in a container
because if you run in a container, you
can do dangerously skip permissions and
it's not dangerous. And if you've got to
approve all your tool use, that's real
hell. It's going to really slow you
down.
>> Uh, awesome. I guess I have something
for that one.
>> All right, get up here.
>> Thank you, Rob. That was a blessing
right there. I appreciate that.
>> What's your name? Where you calling in
from?
>> Yari from calling from San Diego Picnic
Health. Um, nice.
>> But yeah, we uh, you know, like
everybody here probably had the same
problem of like, yeah, the permission
stuff gets really annoying really fast.
And most of the time you're like, you
find yourself like approving the same
things and then with the latest model,
it got really good at coding things. But
then every one of those is a new script
and it's means a new prompt and you
can't pre-approve them. So added a hook
into the approval process and if it was
if it passed the regular checks it would
be prompted and then that would fire off
a LLM call with a specific prompt around
kind of the things that we wanted to
look for like dangerous things and then
it would if it felt like this was a safe
change uh it would actually approve it.
And so you you know as a user you would
see it briefly ask and then it would be
like approved and then it would just go
so you could just go walk away and and
and the other thing it would do is also
learn from itself. So it would keep a
list of history of what you've approved
and then kind of learn from that go oh
they're approving this so it must be
okay for this session and you could make
that session specific or uh you know be
broader and have it be specific to you
complete like across your sessions.
>> Nice. So let me just make sure I
understand this correctly. You add the
hook right before every like asking for
permission.
>> Yep. And then
>> so that calls an uh that basically runs
a prompt uh passing the
>> that's it
>> command that you're trying to run to an
LLM which has like other guidance around
it like you know evaluate it for
dangerous stuff like
>> make sure you're not leaking secrets
>> writing into our production database you
know make sure you prompt the user
things like that and then it does a you
know quick evaluation and then comes
right back and approves it.
>> Awesome.
>> Yeah. So that that's been huge.
questions questions here? No. Well,
that's great, man. I appreciate that.
All right, what else do we got here? Who
else has got some spicy stuff? Can we
keep scrolling down? Maybe use them. Use
agents, interact, work with agents until
you get code you want. Um,
teach it. Yeah. Uh there was one that I
saw about the context
asking it to review the I don't know
where it is but asking it to review the
codebase and then put that in the
context. Who was that? Rob, it better
not be you. Better not have been you.
Was it you?
>> No. All right. Who was that? Did they
leave?
Couldn't hold their attention. Where
Claude Max plan is 10 times cheaper
using than using the API. Yes, that
actually I have found that. Yeah, we've
all found that. All right, that's not
that big of a hot take. Okay, but that
is true. Use hooks.
Whose is this? Use hooks to force
limiting commits, tests, and
correctness.
Get on up here. You know what time it
is. Ooh, scrap and restart.
Yeah, I've learned that. Clear the
context. Okay, so
hooks are one that I just haven't played
with enough. I like this use case. I
like this use case. So, enlighten me.
What's your name? Where you calling in
from?
>> Uh yeah, my name is Josh. I am from uh
East Bay here uh near Berkeley. So uh
yeah I think um if you're using cloud
code I don't know if you know other
things like open code or codeex have
this but you know basically you have
life cycle hooks that let you
uh run scripts or you know follow uh
text instructions at various points when
it's doing things. So, you know, I don't
know about you, but often
if I have uh an agent working on a task,
it might quit early or it might try to
forego even if I put in my uh you know,
agent.md or claw.md like
>> ensure your lint rules all pass, ensure
that you know uh your typescript
compiles, ensure your tests all pass. It
will not do that. But you can use hooks
to actually enforce this. Uh you can
also have it like play sounds, send off
notifications to devices. Just digging
into that really helps your workflow a
lot.
>> Uh I also said don't be afraid to scrap
and restart. I mean that both in terms
of context clearing. I think like more
context is not always better. You start
seeing that like it doesn't know it has
no inherent sense of what is more
important. So having more information uh
can lead to less focus. Uh so don't be
afraid for that. But also like if you're
working on a feature and it's just like
not working sometimes just like starting
over and not being afraid to just like
lose that code in progress because it's
so cheap to start again is way better.
>> Yes. Wait, wait, wait. Don't go
anywhere. There's some questions. I was
just going to add that if you put your
context in the plan file, you can just
erase your
>> uh exactly and I think keep like make
sure your plan file also has your
updated tasks. I guess like Claude now
tracks C tasks. Uh but I think having it
written in a document so you can go
between agents and you know self uh
observe what's going on rather than
having like to ask
>> the agent itself where it is in its list
of tasks is easier.
So the TLDDR of the hooks are that you
use them to really enforce what you
really want to happen.
>> Uh yeah, absolutely. So um yeah, if you
need your you want to make sure your
tests are running or even just like you
start you give a prompt that has really
clear success criteria.
>> Uh you can force it to do that. I think
also like if you have a certain set of
tests that it cannot alter
>> because it like sub you know succeed uh
even if that means deleting or changing
the test like you know have a criteria
like you're not stopping until this
happens or you know what have you.
>> Excellent. Well, thank you for that. All
right, it looks like we've got another
one. Put your plan in plan MD rather
than plan mode. Was this you Rafa?
>> All right, get up here Rob. Go on.
What is this about? Just sit closer next
time.
>> This one helps a lot.
>> Rob, you all remember Rob, right? Huh?
Here we go.
>> This one helps a lot. So, if you use a
standard clawed code plan mode, it like
one, it like shows it in the really
awkward way in the terminal. Two, it's
like hard to discuss it in as good a way
and it's not quittes the repo. Awkward
in lots of ways. You can just tell it to
write its plan as a plan MD file. Then
you can view it and scroll it around
nicely in markdown. You can discuss
backwards and forwards edits to it. You
can commit it. It just tends to work a
lot better. And if you're using Broomi,
it automatically shows the plan MD in a
nice UI.
>> So you're specifically saying to it
always, or is that a skill that you've
created that like whenever it's in plan
mode, transfer everything, do a plan? So
basically rather rather than switching
to plan mode just tell Claude write a
plan to
>> and it directly writes the plan.
Basically it works as if plan mode but
does it as a file.
>> Yeah, I see that's cool.
>> It's much easier to edit it and discuss
it and view it.
>> I like that. All right, what else do we
got? And folks that just came in, this
is an interactive session. So feel free
to scan that bad boy right there. give
us your best tip for using coding agents
because we're it's we want to learn from
each other. Basically, we're learning
from Rob today uh a lot.
So, hit hit that, take a minute and tell
us what is your best tip. What tips do
you got? In the meantime, let's scan
through and see if we have anything new
that is coming. Uh yeah, I really like
that one about scrapping and restarting
on the actual feature. That is a cool
one. Uh what else? Starting a project
and defining use voice. Okay, who's
this? Who's this one? The voice
dictation. I've been all about that.
Get on up here. I I see that. Learn
T-Mooks if you haven't already. Was that
you, Rob?
>> That was not Who was that?
All right. Was it you Rafa T-Mooks? No.
Who was the T-Mooks?
Ah, it is good. All right. So,
>> so, uh, I think we have this tendency to
think like we we when you're typing, you
go slower. You have more polish to your
communication. And I think when you're
doing some parts of agentic coding like
that clear direct instruction is useful
but when you are first figuring out what
your project is what your specs are just
doing a free flow you know dictation
that is imperfect like one the LLM are
really good at summarizing and putting
uh you know finding connections between
what you're talking about but I think
also like a lot of what you're building
is like we're very bad at defining
intent. If we could just like describe
products well, inspect them well, you
know, we wouldn't have jobs really
honestly like everyone could just do
this stuff. But that's really hard and I
think you get a lot of intent by just
speaking freely and having that get
summarized. So when you're in that
planning stage, I think rambling is good
and beneficial. I am on the same page
100% because when you're in when you're
speaking with your voice, you just don't
even realize it, but you give so much
more context. I've noticed that even
with like externally facing agents. So
if you want a actual agent that is for
users and same thing if you can get it
with voice and you need that context,
you'll get it.
>> Can I ask a followup or two?
>> Yeah, of course. That's what we're here
for.
>> What What tooling do you
>> What tooling do you use? Uh, I use
Whisper Flow and uh, it's pretty good. I
think it's always I I usually just like,
you know, hold down whatever your
shortcut key is to dictate and then it
just goes into whatever text box. So, if
I'm using cloud code, it just like plops
in there. It's I use Vim mode then
because inevitably like some word is
misspelled or like especially like
proper nouns and contexts can get off a
little bit. So, it's like much faster to
edit for me at least in Vim mode uh
rather than having to just like use
arrow keys indefinitely. But
>> yeah,
>> use T-Max in Vim mode.
>> Do do you find yourself editing your
speech or
>> do you edit your speech?
>> I just would be worried that I'd be like
constantly like self-judging the words
just like I self judge the key.
>> Well, I think that's the thing. Wild.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I like
>> getting out of the habit of doing that,
like using it and seeing that it doesn't
matter. Like also like
>> y
>> at least right now your LLM is only
judging you if you send it off onto Molt
Book. So um you know like who cares like
if you're a little bit dumb that's fine.
Like I think it's a feature not a bug
that you can speak freely to it. you
don't have to worry about, you know,
judgment or what you say and then it
like responds and you can correct it
afterwards.
>> Yeah, I I agree. Highly recommended. All
right, that's a great hack. Use voice
mode, especially when starting. Thank
you, sir.
Um, what else do we got for the people
that just came in? I see some new faces.
Scan that QR code. Give us your best
trick. Can we scroll up and see what
else? And now if you've already given
your best trick, now it's time to upvote
so we know which ones we should have
come on stage. Who likes what? Have
Claude update all your MD files. No need
to write any instructions yourself. Get
Claude to do Hold on. Get Claude to do
product design research. Who's that?
Who's No. off, Rob. Are you
serious? What the hell, man?
Come on.
Good lord. Somebody upvote something
else besides Robs. All right,
>> this one's really powerful. If you're
trying to work out what to do in your
product, how to solve a problem. Claw
code isn't just good at like writing
code. Just give it a big open-ended
thing. Say research what the competitors
are doing. Research what you know about
user behavior. Really delve into the
data sets and come up with a good
proposal. And often it does a really
good job of just working out what you
should do.
>> Wow. So you're just telling it when
you're starting out a feature or when
you're starting a product like how big
of a scope can you give it?
>> It can be pretty big. Just give it a big
wide open question and tell it to do a
ton of research. I will warn you though,
this can really really swallow your
tokens
>> because if it's reading a ton of
websites and a ton of data sets, reading
a ton of papers, it'll often use a lot
of context and lot of tokens to do it.
But it can do a really good job. You get
some surprising insights you hadn't
thought of. It'll re like it'll research
your customers and find out their
history and their org charts and all the
different people and what they want.
It'll research all your competitors and
work out what they're doing, what their
weaknesses are.
>> And you're not specifically calling that
out like research this my competitors
and give me their org charts.
>> You given us that like open questions
and let it run.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But like it can do a really good job
with this.
>> And you're not saying like make sure to
remember to check archive
papers or that stuff. you just are
saying go for it.
>> There's there's advantages in throwing
some questions in there, but way I'd
recommend doing this, do it as a brain
dump. Let's say imagine you had a team
of a 100 researchers. Just write all the
overall questions you've got like what
do my customers want? What's the
history? Who are the key key people?
What do they want? What's the history?
What what do the users want? What
challenge they're likely facing? Just
spit out a lot of questions stream of
consciousness style and tell it to do
the research and assemble you something.
>> I like it. All right, Rob. I get the
feeling this isn't the last time I'm
going to see you. So, who's is this? You
can make expert skills about whatever
you want. Hey, Rafa,
get back up here. For folks that are not
participating, it is much more fun when
you do. So, feel free to scan that QR
code and give us your best tip. The the
idea here is we want to have um we want
to learn from each other. All right,
Rafa, what you got?
>> Yeah, so one of the things that I keep
forgetting about context engineering,
the way that I use context engineering
is to put rails on what I want my agent
to do. So I will write a plan MD file to
be like, okay, this is exactly what you
need to do. But another part about
context engineering is priming the
agent. So um the LMS are trained with
like almost everything on the internet.
Like they already have a universe of
information. So you can use skills to
prime the
um the LLMs to give you that expert
information that's already in there. So
if you take a look at the front-end
design skill um that cloth provides, I
thought it was going to be like a bunch
of guidelines about how to design
correctly etc. No, but it's only like 40
lines that says say you are an expert
designer um that doesn't use tacky AI
designs or something like that. It's
just very simple. So you can make
yourself a skill about whatever you need
to research or understand. Like if you
want to understand trademarks or how to
go to market or you know how to be a PM
or like something out there in the
world, the LMS's already trained on that
information. So you can just make
yourself skills about whatever you want.
>> That's cool.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So it's like just landing in
latent space. The skill is how to make
it locate itself.
>> Yeah. LLMs already know how to do
whatever a human does, whatever a human
does.
>> So, you just need to prime it.
>> Questions for Rafa? We're going to let
him go back to his seat.
>> Right.
>> Hey, there we go. What else do we got?
Trans.
>> Question. Oh, we got a question back
here. Hit us.
>> Why do you need to make a skill if it
already knows?
>> Uh, why do you need to make a skill if
it already knows?
>> Skills. Skills are a really nice
reusable abstraction. That's why um if
you go back to the days of uh prompt
engineering like uh you could always do
like you are an expert designer or you
are uh blah blah blah blah blah and it
will your response will be primed uh
with that context. But if if this is
something that you use a lot um that's
what skills are for. Um it's like your
way to make yourself a little reusable
expert. So in my own workflow, I just
have a bunch of different experts and as
I'm going through like my dayto-day and
if I have like different kinds of
questions etc like I'll use a skill to
ask the expert in that area and so it's
just the reusability like that's the
value of adding the skill
>> brilliant good satisfactory oh
>> all right
>> kind of though multiple ways to do
I think
your code.
>> Yeah.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. And I wasn't a believer in skills.
Uh but it's the reusability um aspect of
it that I that I really use. Now
>> I like this. I felt like we just had a
nice volley there. Let's keep that up.
Huh. So, there's one that's that was
just down. Can I see that again? If you
build off a new codebase, use
wellexecuted open-source projects to get
design prompts. Whose was this?
Well, get on up here
again. That is a good one. And then
we've got the rebuttal, I think, to
Rob's. Unless this was yours, Rob, if we
scroll up, but in the meantime, tell us.
>> So, I think like especially like I often
build things uh that have less uh common
good use cases or like if I'm building
like web audio stuff or like music
applications,
if I don't give it anything to work off
of, well, like there's a bunch of timing
stuff, anything that's nuanced. If you
know that there's already an open source
codebase that does this stuff, well,
build a skill or even just like when
you're building out your architecture,
like you can ask it to analyze someone
else's codebase to come up with that
stuff. So that way you get to build
things in areas you're not yet an expert
in and uh you know, get a little bit of
a head start.
>> Hell yeah. I love that. Any questions?
Anything? That is awesome. There's so
many tricks now that I'm going to have
to I'm glad we're recording this because
I'm going to have to remember them by
watching the video later. Okay, what do
we got?
Tell the agent to add documentation
comment to the top of every file. A good
read me to every folder and make sure it
stays up to date. Who's is that? No, you
got to be joking, man. Stop.
I'm telling you, it's more fun when you
participate. Look how much fun Rob is
having over here.
>> And you can use
>> this one's a killer. Like if you want
your agents to understand the codebase,
the codebase needs to be understandable.
Particularly if it's like using a gentic
search to find where stuff is. So it's
really valuable to have agents read
every file one at a time. Make sure each
one has a documentation comment at the
top really explaining how it works and
how it connects to other files and
simply have a read me for each folder
saying what all the files are in there
and how they work because then the agent
can work out how your code works.
>> Yeah.
>> And if humans do this, it's not viable
because humans don't keep yourself up to
date.
>> Yeah.
>> Agents do cuz just tell them to with a
hook.
>> Are you making sure that you're saying
always update the read me in in the
prompt? The way I do it is I've got a
validation skill that it does at the end
of every thing it submits.
>> And so one of the things it has to do as
part of validating its work is make sure
the documentation comments are up to
date.
>> Oh, awesome. Okay. All right. What else
do we got? Wait. Uh, whose was this? Use
deep research products like Parallel or
ChatG. Hey, we got somebody new. This
was this is similar to what you were
talking about, Rob, but it's a little
bit it's how to do that but save money.
So you don't just burn through all your
tokens, I guess. Get on up here. We got
a new contestant.
Fresh blood. Hey. All right. Tell us
your name and where you're calling in
from.
>> So I'm a I'm local. Uh I've used this
trick with Claude, the product research
thing that you mentioned, especially
with Opus 4.6. Just the tokens get out
of budget very quickly. There's this
meme of Pablo Escobar, the sad meme from
Narco show that people have seen
probably. Whenever you get rate limited,
that's how I feel these days where you
just don't know anything to do. So I
typically use uh and I have no
allegiance to perplexity or chat GBD,
but I do use them to do deep research,
construct a plan and then give that plan
to claude and that does allow me to
overcome.
>> So I'd recommend to give that a shot.
>> I have one other shout out or comment on
the previous thing. We're not going to
>> again no allegiance here, but Devon uh
has a really cool feature where if
you're using back end, it'll actually
produce UI screenshots and even videos
of how the change is going to look like
>> and you can actually look at it before
even approving PRs. And I would wish
like somebody like Claude code would
eventually add that feature because it
does help in just visualizing how
something is getting built in real time.
>> Should have been here earlier. Rob was
talking about that and how that works.
That That's awesome. Well, thank you.
What else do we got? I think we have one
more. Also, Christina Mikail is here for
the workshop. He just texted me, so we
might need to find him. All right. Uh, I
did like this one. What was Although, if
it is one of the three people that have
already been up here all day, the bug
tracker, whose was this? No. All right,
we're done. We're not doing that. Let's
get somebody else up here. Did anyone
else put any other trick? Anybody
something? No. What? What trick? Get up
here. Tell us about your trick. We're
trying to spread the love. What do you
got for us?
There we go. New newcomer coming
through. Tell us your name. Where are
you calling in from?
>> Chad. Uh, long time listener, first time
caller.
>> Uh, this is really basic and there's
like refining your plans and refining
your specs. There's tons of things to do
that. There's like BMAD and Cloudflow
and whatever else, but I do a really
simple thing. I'm like, "Okay, I've got
the seed of whatever of a plan or a spec
or something to start with." And then I
have one or more agents just it's a
skill that says, "Critique this and then
write it like my plan is plan V1." And
then it's like critique Opus V1,
critique
uh GPT V1 or whatever model or critique
human if it's something I wrote. And
then I have a revise skill that reads
those and it says, "Okay." And they'll
they'll always find new things.
And then there's a revised skill that
reads those and says, "Okay, I'm going
to update the plan, make a V2, and then
I'm going to write an acknowledgement
V1. Acknowledgement V1 for all of the
ones." And then you just repeat that.
And for simple things, it'll sort of
resolve and say, "No, this is good. I
don't find anything else." for bigger
things it will go as as much as you have
tokens but that's a good way to see it
refined and you when you have that
version history you can also say okay
look back and you can see maybe where it
got things wrong or it drifted so that's
the way I've been approaching just
refining the markdown files
>> I like that I like it well thank you sir
yeah any questions and yeah we got a
question up
>> are you is it doing it automatically or
you kind of trigger it yourself
>> is it doing it automatically
>> uh sometimes I do it manually I I made a
skill that looped over it and then that
burns several hundred worth of tokens so
I don't do that too much anymore.
>> Nice.
>> We got one.
>> All right, we got one.
>> Um,
>> where you calling in from?
>> I'm Tevia. I'm calling in from on stage.
Um, you won't burn through hundreds of
dollars of tokens if you use the max
plan because it won't let you. Um, I
burnt through like $800 of tokens and
then I realized I could have just spent
200 for the month. Um, it's literally 10
times more expensive on the API. I don't
know why.
>> Let me clarify that.
>> Say it again.
>> Personally, I use the max.
>> Okay. Employee. Anyway, don't use the
API. Um, my my workflow is kind of like
yours. I have I just specify really
simply using voice. it. I have an
architecture agent that writes up an
architecture plan, a reviewer that
reviews it, and then it goes in a cycle.
When it's done, it summarizes the
architecture for me, I usually have
comments and changes. But once I've
solidified the architecture,
that's pretty much all the review I do
because then there's a TDD agent that
writes all the tests. There's a coder,
there's a code reviewer, and then it
actually checks whether the code matches
the architecture plan. And if Claude
thinks it does, it's going to do a way
better job than I could ever do. So
really, all I'm doing is reviewing the
architecture. And then as long as the
tests pass, I just ship.
>> But you're not writing the tests. No,
I'm not doing anything really. Just
reading.
>> Yeah, don't tell many people that.
>> Awesome. All right, there's another good
one here. What? You got one? I see you.
Get up. Come on. Let's see what you got.
What's your best trick?
>> Name, and where you calling in from?
>> So, I'm I'm trouble. Uh I came from
Fresno
and uh I'm curious uh if you guys agree
with me but uh I said that handle your
agent almost as you would be it's the
therapist
and so this is not like okay I'm uh
doing a planning mode and whatever this
is generally how I conduct with the
agent because I know that the agent is
super intelligent
But at the same time it's dumb as well.
I also know that let's say I'm I'm not
stupid but I can also forget things and
and I can be stupid sometimes. So uh
when I'm talk with the agent uh let's
say I want the agent to conduct plan a
new feature or uh some new iteration on
it. I'm not necessarily instructing you
that do this uh let's say implement a
new graph algorithm uh with that
specific graph algorithm but I rather
try to ask questions like do you think
it would be good to implement this new
uh algorithm because then I give a
little u
express expressiveness a little
creativity to also critique
and maybe even come up with a new
algorithm I haven't known before. Um,
and so I I navigate this fine line of uh
dealing with uh psychopanty which is
much better now when it than it was. So
kudos to the big labs. They worked on
that. But it can be still psychopantic
and also to so to not instruct it too
hard to so it can blossom its own
intelligence but at at the same time
keep it under control uh if it would be
stupid.
>> So it's a fine line.
>> I like it. I I wonder if if you agree
because I know Swixs for example he he
he says that don't don't anthropom
anthropomorphize the agents and for this
you kind of anthropomorphize the agent.
Yeah. I I treat it almost like a a
human, right?
>> Yeah. Ask those questions. I like it.
Anybody got questions?
>> No. All right. I think we've got time
for one more. And since this layered
memory one, if it is not, don't tell me
it's you, Rob. It's not. All right,
we're going to go with the Hey, we got a
new caller. Get on up here. Let's see
what you got. So, I have a three layer
memory system. Memory MCP works on cloud
code and desktop. Cloud code newish
built in automemory for each repository
project. And Joplain, I don't know what
Joplain is, but give us a I know you.
Welcome. You you can use that mic. Tell
us what you're talking about. So this is
something that I have been doing for not
that long like a week or two but has
been very useful. Um first I started
using the memory MCP the most kind of
popularly available stock uh memory MCP
and that's nice because it uh the
memories are accessible both from cloud
desktop and from cloud code. uh so I
when I jump in between I I have you know
very similar resources available and
then cloud code maybe I don't know last
five versions or so released this
automemory feature where they
automatically create um files in the
dotcloud memory folder I think for each
repository or or project that you're
working on and so um and then third I I
personally use this markdown editor
called Joplain
>> which is very similar to Obsidian if
that's known to others but that's really
nice for
basically it's markdown native so it
speaks the language of LLMs and you can
you know pull content directly from uh
the output of of claude and it's nicely
formatted and easy to read and edit and
so forth. It's a little bit like
Evernote if people are familiar with
that. And so I have all of that and I
have um my cloud MD instructing cloud
code when to use each of these systems.
So
>> it uses memory and uh the memory MCP for
overarching memories
>> allows it to just default to its auto
memory for each repo and then exports to
Joplin if I want to save something. So
that's been really nice for me. And with
Joplin, you're throwing the whole
conversation into Joplin or you throwing
just the code?
>> No, I'm I'm um using it as a library. So
I'm essentially it won't write to Joplin
unless I explicitly tell it to. So if I
run research on something, I'll tell it
to output that to a Joplin note.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And then I'll at some later point if I'm
working on something, I'll say, "Hey,
see this Joplin note for resources." and
you know that might contain a list of
links or other things and then I'm kind
of ramped up on that subject even if I
haven't been active on it for a week or
two.
>> Nice. Okay,
thank any questions anybody?
>> We're good. All right, you're free to
go. Well, that was it. I think the next
question that I had in there was what's
your hottest take? I don't know if
anybody actually threw in their hot
take.
doesn't have to be on MLOps. It can just
be your hot take. We've got a few
minutes before the next talk, I think.
So, people should start filing in.
Anybody got a hot take they want to
defend in front of the crowd. Where we
at with the hot takes, huh? It's a
little cold in here. No spiciness,
nothing. What's your hot take? I see one
participant typing.
All right. So, we're not going to have
the biggest field. What? You got a You
got a hot take? The only safe job is
entrepreneur. Get up here and defend
that. Come on now.
I I I've been an entrepreneur for 3
years. And what I realized is it doesn't
matter how good you are at building
products, if you can't sell them, you're
never going to succeed. Um, and so now
it's even more unimportant because cloud
code can just build products all day
long. So
if you want to succeed, you have to
figure out how to get people to pay for
things. And Cloud Code can theorize
about that. But I don't know if it's
going to replace that ability. If it
does, it's going to just become the
world's richest
AI. Um, so yeah, I think everyone should
become an entrepreneur because we might
all be
>> unemployed soon.
>> You need to sell. I like it. All right,
so there's a few hot takes coming
through here.
Any rebuttals on the entrepreneur front?
No, we're good. Which one should we do?
Which one of these should we have?
Mustache contest. I like it. Where is
Dex? Is he around here? I'll get you,
Dex. Don't tell me that twice. All
right. Uh, the funniest one I thought
was if we scroll down a little bit.
Where's the
designer? Should be should have been
coding this whole time.
Yo, chill. Who is that?
Rafa, chill, dude. It's all right, man.
Go get some more Boba. We'll be all
right. The designers, they're doing what
they can. Rag does not equal vector
search. That's kind of hot. I like it.
Where? Who was that? Who was that? Oh,
you want to get up here and defend that?
You want to tell us why? No. Rag does
not equal vector search. You saw that
talk earlier. Is that what spurred this?
>> Perhaps.
>> Perhaps. All right. Come tell us why rag
is not vector search.
What do we got? And what's your name?
Where you calling in from? Uh Kareem
calling in from Los Angeles.
>> Hey.
>> Uh so Rag, you know, was popularized
around, you know, vector search and
vector DBs and so on. Oh,
>> that's the mic. Yeah.
>> Uh rag was popularized around vector DBs
and vector search and so on. And then
there was this idea that long context
windows make rag not, you know, a thing
that you should do anymore. Uh the thing
that frustrates me oftentimes is even
with a long context window you have to
retrieve something to put in that
context to augment the generation to get
the output you want. So I think people
got hyperfixated on a particular
implementation of rag and really in
generality you should be asking what
information retrieval or rexis
techniques do I need for the problem I'm
trying to solve. Oh,
how we feel? I like that one. How we
feeling about that? Yeah. Any questions?
Any anything? I like that. All right,
Kareem. Thank you, sir.
Now, we've got one or two more and Zach
should be up. We've got a
We've got the talk starting in four or
five minutes. So, I imagine people are
going to Three Three minutes. This guy
keeps the trains running on time. There
we go. So, which one, folks? We got to
upvote. Which ones are we doing? Last
one. I'm gonna ask everyone to upvote
what you've got here. Where we at?
Out of all of these hot takes, which one
do we bring up to defend themselves?
Where you at? Oh, specialization will
actually be more important. Early
adoption is not automatically better.
Huh.
All right, we'll see. More people decide
the AIS are conscious.
I'm not We're not going to do that one.
That That is a hot tick, but I'm not
doing it. Siloed roles are dead. We all
have to be ducks.
I like that. All right. Yes, we should
have mustache con. Okay. It um I think
we got to go back up cuz that got the
most up votes. Who did this one?
specialization will actually be more
important. Who's is that? Where you at?
All right, you come defend your hot
take. This is the last one and then
we're going to have the talk.
What you got?
Partially. I was just
inverting something that was already
there. But I do actually think um
>> increasingly when anyone can do anything
I don't necessarily mean specialization
in terms of coding although I do think
there are still going to be things there
like right now if you don't know
anything about security
and you want to build something
production ready like cuz
>> what you can you know vibe about or
agentically code and what is production
ready are not always the same thing but
I think like having specialization and
especially like building, knowing what
to build and how to build it becomes
like a specialization. Like if you know
an industry, you're much more likely to
be able to go and build the right thing
for that than to just say, "Oh, I see an
opening here and I'll do that." So I
think like general knowledge does will
still has a place. You can do a lot more
with a lot less, but knowing something
still matters.
>> He gets a clap. Hey, what question
rebuttal? What do you got?
>> Did you hear that?
>> Subject matter expertise can be
expressed in MD files.
>> Most of the questions could be
That's why
in some sense
but the new form of specialization will
will grow.
So we're taking you off mute right now.
>> All right.
>> Um so subject matter expertise that
could be expressed in one MD file is not
specialization but it is uh the most
that we currently have from the subject
matter expertise. specialization will
grow but the current form will extinct
>> different kinds of specialization. What
are you gonna say about
>> I I think you can you definitely want
this is not saying
don't build skills don't provide that
only rely on what you know but I think
having an edge of knowing a domain very
well will matter and those things are
not easily consolidated down always into
a skill. H a markdown file
>> or a markdown file.
>> All right, I like it. Can we hit the
bell to let people know that the talk's
coming so we can try and file them in
from the fun floor? AV team, any
possibility of hitting that uh bell so
that people in the other room can
>> I already
>> Oh, you did. All right. So, you heard it
hopefully. Can Oh, you weren't doing it
in here. That's nice. Nice feature. All
right. We're going to have two more
minutes and then we're going to bring up
Zack. Wherever he is. Where are you?
Hey, there he is, Zack. All right, we're
going to wait just two minutes. Is that
cool with you?
>> Okay, cool. So, oh, I lost my slido.
Last hot take I was hoping for. Can I
see the slido again? The last taste
matters more than anything. Not so hot.
Uh, base models are better before
instruction tuning.
Kind of hot.
Whose was that?
Get up here. Tell me what you Oh, is
that hot? No. Do I know you? I can't see
with the lights. I thought you were
somebody else. Forgive me. Get up here.
Tell us what you're talking about and
what kind of models you've been playing
with. Huh?
>> Um, okay. So I think that one of the
most like unexamined um like defaults
that has now been adopted is instruction
tuning which really hasn't evolved much
since like GPT3.5 instruct in the
original chat GPT. this idea that like a
model is something that I give
instructions and then like based on the
instructions it comes out and in the
process of doing this it just like nerfs
all the entropy and like gives you these
like really really predictable paths
which is like great when you're working
but there's like all these different
types of interactions that could exist
with models and so if you use base
models like you get out like um it's way
more of a slot machine but like you get
way more rich diversity iversity of
outputs and this is most visible with
creative writing because like creative
writing doesn't have to like compile or
run and things like that. So it's a
little bit like more fault tolerant but
it's just like you get this like really
rich set of ideas. You're like whoa I've
never actually thought about that. But
you can't do it in a natural pattern.
You can't be like write me a a story
about this. you have to say like you
have to do like the autocomplete thing
like
>> uh either like like the following is a
story about duh duh and you can kind of
do this with code too. So if you if
you're getting frustrated with the lack
of creativity or the lack or the like
overpredictability of models, you can
actually go and find base models like
particularly from the llama series or
some of the like open source ones and
like the the the types of stuff you get
out of them is like super wide and I
think it just means that like we have to
like think seriously about what like if
most people don't have compute for post-
training but at least like think about
what are the things we would ask of
models and like make that more diverse.
So those that do have setups for that
can like produce different things. And
so that's my take.
>> I like that. That was that was spicy.
Any rebuttals? Anybody want to say
anything about that? Jeremy,
>> are you coding with uh baseball?
>> Are you coding with baseball?
>> Very rarely. Mostly if I'm trying to
make like mostly artistic stuff. Like I
actually found my first vibe, one of my
first vibe coded things from 2021 cuz
like the original GPT3 could do like
JavaScript and CSS animations and
they're like super weird and blinky and
most of them were broken but like yeah
like it can do like front-end stuff with
the b the the latest base model. So
sometimes not when I'm trying to get
work done but
>> when you're trying to vibe I like it.
All right, Jeremy. Thank you.
>> Yeah, when I'm trying to vibe.
>> Here we go. So folks, I'm going to bring
up our next speaker. I am excited. He's
coming from the land of the Adobe
architecture. Can you put your hands
together for Zach, the founder and CEO
of Warp? Let's hear it.
And Zach, you got any hot takes for us?
>> You got a whole
>> whole presentation of hot takes. This
will be a hot take.
>> There we go. Are you miked up or you
want to use that mic? Use that mic.
>> Yeah, perfect.
>> I want to be able to do a demo. Will I
be able to do that?
>> All right, we'll try.
>> Okay,
>> I think we're going to do this.
>> Okay.
>> And you can give your talk while I
figure this out. How's that sound?
>> That sounds great.
>> Um, yeah, this doesn't need to go on for
a bit. So, I'll get started.
>> Yeah. Don't share the
things you don't want.
>> We need an adapter.
>> Okay.
>> Adapter.
>> All right. Um, hi everyone. I am Zach. I
am the founder and CEO of Warp. I'm
excited to be here. Um, I'm Thank you.
Uh, today I'm I'm going to talk about
agent orchestration, which I think is a
hot topic, an increasingly hot topic
this year. This is how I do the slides.
>> Yes, it is.
>> Okay, cool. Um,
I'm making a bold prediction that 2026
will be the year of agent orchestration.
So, what does that mean? Um, let me
start I guess with a little bit of I
don't know if it's a story, it's more of
a question, but the uh the way that we
are working now at warp I assume this is
true for a bunch of you is like
increasingly running multiple agents at
once and starting to run into the limits
of like what our laptops can do. So for
us, we have a codebase that's like
million lines of Rust code. I have maybe
four or five of these checked out on my
laptop. I am running uh agents in them.
Um typically we're running like warp's
own agent but this is probably happening
to people who are running cloud code or
codeex. It's the same thing everywhere.
Uh just like show hands are people is
this a thing that's happening to other
people or is this just us? So it's
starting to starting to slowly happen.
Um
what is like driving the overall trend
here? So, uh, there was an intro slide
for me, but but I've been an engineer
for over 20 years. I was a I used to be
a principal engineer at Google. Most of
my career has been spent writing code by
hand. Like, literally, you know, what I
would do every day is I would come in
and I would open up a code editor, an
IDE, and I would type code. And uh
sometime last year uh I've totally
switched the way that I'm working to be
writing by prompt and I'm still you know
even now I still ship software in warp
but I haven't written code in the last
six months. Um again show hands I assume
everyone in here this is a very
agentforward crowd is is this resonating
with people this how you code. Um,
and so from like a big picture
perspective, I think sometime in 2025,
uh, coding switched over from being, you
know, you writing code by hand to, um,
uh, to writing by prompt. And the way
that I conceive of the prompting that
most people are doing right now is
interactive. And so what I mean by that
is like if you want to fix a bug or
implement a feature, you open up your
terminal or maybe you open up uh your
IDE and you start typing something like,
you know, I want to fix this bug and
then you pair with an agent while it
does stuff. Um and then you might do
that uh with a second agent or a third
agent. And so um but the the key thing
is like you're you're there you're
guiding the agents and the agents are
doing the work while you like have this
conversation.
Um but my hypothesis and a thing that
we're working on at at warp and I guess
maybe I should have introduced warp for
people who aren't familiar. Warp is um
it's like an agentic terminal. So it's a
terminal that has agents built in but
it's more than that. we're actually um
moving into this, you know, the space of
how do you how do you orchestrate agents
that aren't tied to your terminal. Uh
but the issues that we keep running into
are things like literally it's the
laptop capacity like if you're running a
lot of agents. Uh but it's also like if
you're running an engineering team or
running a company, you you know all the
agents that are running on like your
engineers individual laptops, all of
their work is kind of just happening in
a place where um it's not visible like
uh you can't see what your engineers are
doing. So you don't have a sense of like
how does agent adoption look like? You
um you can't have a a clear view of like
do you have security holes with your
agents? Um, if agents are tied to your
laptop, there's an issue that those
agents can only run when your laptop is
on and connected to the internet. So,
there's all these sorts of problems that
are brand new problems that are only
occurring because we've moved to a spot
where you can truly run multiple agents
at once on your laptop.
Um, so what's what's this solution to
this? It's a picture of me on a on a
horse. We did a commercial where I was
on a horse. It was cool. Uh I think this
the solution to this is is that
companies and engineering teams over the
next year are going to want to bring
control to the chaos of like having
multiple just like having everyone run
all of their coding own coding agents on
their laptops. Um
and they're going to want to do this in
a way that doesn't ruin the productivity
gains. So you know it's it's awesome
right now that like developers are
trying out all these new tools. They're
trying out cloud code tools like warp
codeex etc. Um but it also is is
creating an untenable situation and it's
also just a limiter on productivity. So
you know
my prediction is this year there will be
solutions for this. There's one other
big important reason besides just the um
the issue of like you're hitting laptop
limits. It's also that
uh the actual like types of tasks that
you want these agents to do require them
uh to run for longer and also
potentially require them to like you
know run for um you know run as teams
not just run as individual agents. And
so for this there's there's like two
classes of things that we're going to
want to fix this year. One is just like
long singlethreaded agents uh that are
doing hard tasks. And if you're you know
if you're an engineer working on a hard
coding task right now with an agent you
probably are you know you're probably
sometimes hitting issues where the agent
um you know exceeds its context window.
Maybe you compact your agent context. it
starts to forget stuff and so you need
some sort of like primitives for doing
longer harder tasks. And then the second
thing that's going to happen this year
is you're gonna actually have agents
that are working together. Um and so
you're going to have a class of tasks
that are amendable to multiple to sorry
to multiple agents working on them at
once. So this is another thing that's
happening right now and uh there needs
to be infrastructure for it.
So what are the use cases? Um so it's
not just interactive coding tasks. One
big use case this year that's going to
become more and more common is
automations that are built using agents.
And so think of this as
um like every time we do a warp release
for instance, an agent looks at our
codebase and it looks at our
documentation and it comes up with a PR
document uh sorry to update the
documentation based on what's in the
latest release. Or there's another class
of automation which is like um we have a
agent that runs on a timer every week.
It looks for uh feature flags that are
basically guarding dead code that we're
never going to turn off. And so it it
can remove those. And so if you're
running an engineering team or if you're
an individual engineer, you're going to
want the ability this year to build
these kinds of automations, which is
another reason you're going to want
coding agents off of your laptops.
On top of that, there's like agents are
a new programming primitive. And what I
mean by this is that if you're an app
builder, uh whether you're building
internal apps or you're building
customerf facing apps, you're going to
actually want to be able to add agents
into those. So um you know, I I'll show
you an example of an app uh that we've
built internally at Warp where we triage
our GitHub issues. And it's it's
interesting. It's not like it's not an
automation. and it's an app, but within
the app you can launch agents to do
certain types of tasks. And so there's
all these use cases again where you're
going to want to basically take the
coding agents that everyone in here is
using all the time, whether again it's
like cloud code or codeex or warps
coding agent or whatever, and you're
going to want to be able to program
those to run off of your laptop. That's
the theme. uh I know I called it
orchestration and and orchestration is
part of it but I think actually you know
the other big part is just moving to the
cloud.
So if you want to do this type of
workflow where you're working with
coding agents and you're not, you know,
stuck to your laptop, um you might think
that you just want to build this
yourself. And there's a bunch of, you
know, there's a bunch of primitives out
there um that let you run agents in
cloud sandboxes. And that is one of the
primitives that you need. Um, and if
you're, you know, if you're a company,
actually several companies have been in
the news recently, like launching their
own internal agent orchestration
systems. I think Stripe launched one
called Minions. Uh, I think Ramp
launched one. Um, you might find that
you you want to build this and that's a
reasonable thing I think for a company
or an organization of a certain size.
Um, but you also might find that you
don't want to spend the time building
all this scaffolding for running agents
in the cloud. And if you don't like this
is a I mean uh I I'll kind of talk
through I think what the primitives are
that you want to sort of be able to use
off the shelf. And I I'll talk a little
bit about a product that Warp launched
in this space, but I'm not I don't want
to spend too much time on our own
products. Um
but what are the primitives and what
would it take if you wanted to build
cloud agents yourself? So I think the
primitives are things like um
environments. So you need some place
uh that defines like what the agent has
access to. So this is like what's the
tool chain, what's the uh what code does
it have access to? You need hosting. Um,
so these agents need to run on computers
somewhere in the cloud. And there's a
bunch of things like maybe Daytona or
E2B or Docker sandboxes or namespace.
These are ones that we use. Um, you're
going to want some ability to get
visibility into what the agents are
doing. Um, and so there's there is
actually a bunch to build here. I think
you definitely if you're going to build
a system like this want to build it so
that there's still a human in the loop.
And what I mean by that is like if um I
mean I think it's obvious what I mean
it's like you want the ability to see
what these agents are doing when they
run in the cloud. Uh even if they're
running as part of automations or app
backends so that you can uh you can
guide them you can step in if they only
do 80% of the work and make sure that
you finish it off correctly.
So we we just launched a product called
Oz which I'll demo in a bit which you
can think of as kind of like you know
Versel for cloud agents or Superbase for
cloud agents where we're trying to make
it super easy uh for developers and
development teams to move these
workflows off of their laptop. Um the
primitives I think this is interesting
whether you use Oz or not are like you
want a great coding agent. Um
uh or I actually think you want multiple
great coding agents. So one of the
things that we're working on with Oz is
the ability to run any agent harness. Uh
the harnesses have different pros and
cons.
You want something uh called like
tracking. We we call this feature of Oz
autotracking where no matter where you
launch an Oz coding agent and how you
launch it, you get a link to what it's
doing um and all the like artifacts of
the agent run are automatically
recorded. So if you want um to go back
and see what an agent did, uh if you
want to see how it reasoned, you get
that information.
You want handoff. So this is about human
in the loop. So if an agent is, you
know, working uh in a cloud system and
it can get only 80% of the way there and
you want an engineer to pick up what it
did, that should be easy. Uh I mentioned
earlier, you want some sort of
environment definition and hosting. And
then I think the final thing that you
want if you're building a system like
this is that you want it to be fully
programmable.
Uh, and so what I mean by that is like
you should be able to
launch agents via API or SDK or CLI. You
should be able to configure
environments. You should be able to pull
artifacts. You should be able to pull
conversation history. Um, and you should
do that not just for like human
programmers to use, but this is actually
these are the building blocks that will
allow agents to actually orchestrate
each other. And so our approach here has
been like, you know, build this all in a
very programmer first way.
So I'm going to switch over to doing
some demos. Hopefully this will work. Uh
where I show you, you know, what I what
I think of as like orchestration in
action and how it can be helpful. So let
me switch here and figure out how to do
the mic.
>> That one works.
>> This one will work. So should I
>> turn this one off or Okay.
>> All right.
put this down here.
Okay,
cool. Um, yeah. So, I'm I'm gonna I'm
going to show you a few different use
cases here. Um, and and it's all about
like agent orchestration. So, let me
first start here.
And for people who aren't familiar, this
is warp. Warp is it's a terminal with
agents built in. Uh the history of warp
is we started off building a sort of
modern terminal and then as uh you know
as agents have become more and more
popular we've built in features that
just make it super easy to launch agents
from directly within warp. Um within
warp you know I can I can sort of use it
as a terminal here. But what I actually
want to show you is how you can um do
multi- aent work. So I'll go here
and I'll show you a project that I've
been working on or actually someone from
my team has been building which is we
vibe coded our own version of Google
Docs and this is this is the uh product
that I used to I used to work on at
Google so it's pretty fun to work on
again uh we built this in a couple days
um but it's it's pretty incomplete and
so if you go over and look at our
version of the spreadsheet here it can
do simple formula formulas. So, it can
do like a sum formula, but if you go
over here and try and have it do uh an
absolute value formula, it's actually
not currently implemented. And so, what
I'm able to do now, go back to warp
here. Um, this will show you the use
case of like being able to do multiple
parallel agents in the cloud. So, I'm
going to go over here and I will I'll
first show you how like the regular
agent works. So with the regular agent,
I kind of just go into a new
conversation here. I could be like um I
could be like, you know, implement
all the formulas
that are missing that start with the
letter A.
And so this launches our interactive
agent. And so in the old way of working,
what I would do is if I wanted to do
multiple of these at once, I might pop
open another tab over here and basically
do um let me copy this for a second.
I might go over here and say implement
all the formulas that start with the
letter B. And I could do that, but I'm
going to start to run into these limits
of
um you know, just like these laptop
limits. So, the thing that we've built
in that I think people are going to
increasingly want is the ability here to
do this directly in the cloud. So, I'll
go here and this is instead of being a
local conversation has the exact same um
sort of UI, but this will launch it into
the cloud. And so, I'll do this and I'll
start this uh as a cloud job. Now,
what's cool is I can actually just kind
of go back here. You can see here this
one is starting up and I can go back and
look at it in a second. But you can also
um here this one's going over here and
doing the implementation which is cool.
Uh I can also go ahead and over here
launch the one that implements the the
formulas that start with the letter C.
Uh oops I didn't do this as a cloud
agent. I meant to. So we go back here.
I'll do this C.
And I'll do this one again. I'll do it D
and I'll do it again
E. And so I'm not sure if you all are
catching this, but what I'm able to do
is just like massively multi-thread the
work that I'm doing here by launching
these agents into the cloud. And so this
this is using Warp's built-in agent, but
uh the thing that we're working towards
is supporting this actually to work with
any agent harness. So that if you're
running a whole bunch of cloud codes or
whatever and you just want to be able to
launch them as a cloud, you can do it.
So if we go and like look at one of
these, I think the cool thing here, I
think this is another thing that that
you probably want with orchestration is
like you get a view. You'll notice that
looks identical to the one that's
working uh locally. But uh if I go over
here,
this is going into the Oz web app. And
this should give you a sense of what I I
mean when I talk about orchestrating. I
can see that all of these agent runs are
actually being tracked now across the
team. So this was launched locally. Um I
launched it and you can see that this is
like a run that was done by me. But I
can also see in here all the other
things that agents across my team are
doing, which is super cool. So I can see
something that my teammate Matthew was
doing. I can see something that my
teammate uh Ian was doing. And you can
see actually the artifacts that these
agents are creating as they go. So you
can see that this one created a PR. And
if I want, I could actually go in here
and I'll open this up. I could see the
work that he did. So to me, this is like
super cool. It's it's almost like a
Google Docs for agents type concept. Um,
and I can see exactly what the record
was of how this PR was produced. I can
go here and actually look at the PR and
um you know I can see that Ian made this
and so he could also again these things
don't have to be public but I'm running
this in such a way that is public but
it's all behind access control so your
all of a sudden building with agents
becomes a team sport. So this thing that
I started locally implement missing
formulas starting with E. Uh even though
it looked like I was running this on my
laptop, I can also
update the like open this up here um on
the web and see it working. And this
will be the identical view to what I was
doing here. I could open this on my
phone which is super cool. And I could
even steer it. So if I go over here and
I'm like you know actually
let's do E and F as the formulas
um
uh this should actually then adjust the
task. So again it's like you could be
away from your computer this is running
in the cloud. So this is one use case of
what I mean by orchestration. I think
it's super cool. It's more like just as
an individual, let me move these um uh
tasks off of my laptop. Having these
things in the cloud though opens up
other possibilities. So, I'm going to
I'm going to show you a a second use
case. Um and I'll try and leave some
time for questions if people have them.
But a second use case is that you can
actually define what we call um they're
kind of like let's see if this maybe
takes a second to load. live demo risk
here. You can define uh what we call
named agents. And so named agents are
like repeated tasks. And the way that
these work uh is pretty interesting in
in Oz where you basically define a
skill. And I know folks have been
talking about skills today. Um any skill
that's in any of your repos can become a
thing that is like a repeatable
automatable thing. So for instance, if
you look through these skills, you can
see here we have um we have a skill for
analyzing customer feedback. Um we have
a skill for fraud checking. Uh and these
named agent runs become something that
you can set up across your team. Uh you
can set them up on a schedule which is
cool. Um you can go ahead and look at
the actual skill. And so this is all
like from a version controlled skill
file. And then you can go and see all of
the runs that the skill actually um
executed. So if I I could find a fraud
run here.
Um and again, I think the cool thing
here is it's turning
it's turning agents from a solo
individual laptop sport into a team
thing where you can see everything
that's going on across your team. And so
these these skill-based agents can be
scheduled. So this one, I don't know
exactly how often it's running, but it's
something that runs on its own. Um, it
also will produce PRs and uh, so that's
one of the cool things about it being a
coding agent is it uses the coding
context to do its work. Um, I'll show
you one final use case and then maybe
I'll I'll answer some questions. But
there's another use case that I think is
interesting and important which is the
ability to use agents um as like an
intelligence feature that you put into
apps. And so this is an app that I
built. It's called Powerfixer. It's open
source so people want to play with it.
It's a it's a tool that we use
internally to triage GitHub issues at
Warp. And so if I go in here, I can hit
this issues view and I can see this is a
this is a live view of like warp's
GitHub issues. And um if anyone has done
a bunch of issue triage, we have like
thousands of issues here. Uh you know
there's a set of repeatable problems
that comes up. One is that I want uh to
know if there are duplicates. And so
what we have um Oz doing is
automatically dduping every issue that
gets filed. And again, I could go and I
could just kind of see this like ddup
run. But the other cool thing that I can
do is like if I find an agent, sorry, if
I find an issue as a triager that I want
to directly fix, I can just from this
TUI app that I built, um, launch an
agent to do a fix for it. And so, um, I
could add to the prompt. I don't have
to, but this is all using that exact
same infrastructure. So that when I
launch this agent to do the fix again,
you get something that is um tracked
across your team. So this will take a
second to to spin up, but this also
would show up in this same tracking
location. Um so let me just step back
for one second. So the let me grab the
mic actually.
Is this working? Cool. So yeah, the the
way to think about what we've built here
and the way that we're approaching this
is like it's a set of APIs for running
and managing agents in the cloud. And
the sort of next step for it is like it
lets people who are trying to build
multi- aent systems where the agents
talk to each other have the right set of
primitives to do that. So the the next
big thing that we're going to do on this
is not just like these like oneoff agent
runs in the cloud. It's more like how do
you go from a concrete plan for a hard
task that might benefit from multiple
agents to using all of these same APIs
to like coordinate sorry coordinate
those agents to accomplish that task. So
anyhow, let me let me stop there and I
think we're just about time and if folks
have any questions I'd be happy to
answer them. One question. Cool. Just
one question.
Yep.
Here
we go. So, everybody can hear you.
>> Um, have you tried GitHub agents? Uh,
they run effectively the same kind of
thing as cloud code in the cloud? I
haven't used them much myself, but I'm
just curious if that how that compares
to what you're doing.
>> I I I've used them a little bit. Similar
idea. Um I think uh yeah I couldn't do
like a feature byfeature comparison of
them but it's the same general principle
I think you're going to see with a lot
of uh people who are working on agents
of like how do you make it easy to have
these things on the cloud. the specific
areas that we're we're focusing on to
maybe really lean into are like how do
you make these programmatic especially
if you're um what we're finding when we
talk to a lot of companies is like uh
the existing systems for doing this tend
to be very rigid like you have to set up
a docker environment and like run it on
your you know in some cloud host and so
we're really trying to lean into like
you can bring the agent into your own
infrastructure and still get a bunch of
these uh tracking features Cool.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Yeah. Thank you all for having me.
>> And now I would like to introduce our
first speaker for our lightning talk, FA
John from Pinterest. All
right.
>> Where's the clicker thingy? Here. Right
here. Okay, perfect. Hi everyone. Good
afternoon. Um, my name is Fay. Welcome
to the lightning talk. How to
productionize a sub agents for LM post
training. Uh, I'm a tech lead at
Pinterest growth AI applications. Uh,
excited to be here with you all today.
Um so as we know that the uh clock code
or any code genen tool has accelerated
the software development from zero to
production ready in a matter of days.
But how about machine learning and AI
engineering? What does the model
training now looks like? Because no
matter what you're building is if it's a
agentic CRM tool or threat hunting
security products, you want your model
to be a line of what's what we called
good meaning the right reasoning, the
right time for tool calling and the
right persona to answer a customer's
question. So before clock code, we call
it BC, um our model training process
looks like this. It's a giant linear
process where you first define what's
your data look like with cleaning JSON
parquit and then download your hugging
face models with hyperparameters
choosing your Laura Qura full
fine-tuning process and define your loss
function and reward config and then you
start the big eval development uh
restart loop and once you have
productionized your model oftent time
you get user preference data and you use
uh reinforcement learning for DPO PO
type of training. So all of that is
incredibly
manual and takes four to six weeks.
Now introducing our new workflow which
just takes about a week uh using claw
code. Uh we effectively break down the
model generation of the training data
using claw code SQL injection and also
training parameters. um and all of that
task has been paralyzed using sub agent
structure. Now for full transparency we
did explore other agent architect as
well. So right now uh off the box claude
does support sub aents and agent teams
also known as agent swarms. Uh the
biggest difference is for sub agents you
essentially communicate with the sub
agents only via your main agent and you
report back once the task is done. But
for the swarm mode uh the agents share a
task list and then each teammate
communicate with each other and uh check
each other work until you move to the
next stage. So one might say hey the
second method works better right because
it sounds way more advanced but not
necessarily true for model p post
training. This is because we quickly
find out two bottlenecks. Number one is
context limitation. As you imagine each
model keep giving other models the
results of its own task and the context
window quickly expand exponentially. And
number two is the rigidness of the
orchestration. So right now claw code
doesn't support a dynamic scaling
meaning you will quickly run into what
we call the hot celebrity problem in
system design where one of the agents
become incredibly busy and bottled down
with a task and there's no way to easily
scale sub agents among that. Um, so we
started our journey with a sub aent
structure. And for a side note, if Opus
is way too expensive, I would highly
recommend Mini Max 2.5. It's a fraction
of the cost of 27 uh cents on the dollar
here. And also it's trained on PRL
uh preferency alignment reinforcement
learning. It essentially kind of solved
the second problem of the swarm agent
from Claude. it knows when to
dynamically scale your sub agent when it
needs to.
Um so in production we also quickly
realized there are a few patterns that
uh coding agent for post training often
fail. Um number one it's spec drift
meaning throughout the iteration of
training eval redo the model main
framework often forget what the success
metrics looks like and the second is
data distribution. Arguably this is the
biggest bottleneck to the success
training of the model where you have
very une data representation bias and
that's what leads to a training training
and loss uh graph over here. Um and the
third is memory collapse. uh once you
started to train your models after 20 30
to 100 epochs u the model essentially
forgot how to get the right memory
config from previous time and they
started to hallucinate um and lastly
tool misuse uh this has become less a
problem I think this year just because
as industries ourselves we learn how to
better define tool use for agents but
it's still something to watch out for
um I wanted to provide some fixes that
have improved the post training
mechanism. Uh number one is reinforced
the agent orchestration with agent SDK.
Uh the agent SDK from is open-source
agent orchestration tool. You're
essentially can define your full loop uh
beyond just the graph that chains. It
also have the nice hook mechanism where
you can gate each model output from your
agents as a machine readable artifact.
For example, for our data processing, we
will have agents write their own data
set report the representation of each
country, each user and etc. Um and uh in
the end we also have gated decision to
reject or ship instead of doing the
linear process that we previous have. Um
the two tip I want to quickly share here
number one is the structured skills.md.
Now we moved from a natural language
style MD to more structured uh
perspective. This is because we quickly
realized the better instruction you give
the agent itself. For example, you want
to kick start on the hyperparameter that
you want to choose uh the better the
agent align with the process. Um and if
you don't know where to start, I highly
recommend the MS model that is open
source to teach agents how to train your
LMS. Um and the second big get unlock we
see is actually implementing what we
call the uh two calling 2.0 two calling
2.0 uh essentially instead of giving
agent just back and forth information.
How is the data looking? Is it not good
enough? Let me redo it. We essentially
giving the agent capability to write its
own code to solve its question. So the
traditional path looks like this. You
have five requests, five response, but
just letting agent handle you one
response with the script and then have
the loop until it checks its own work
drastically reduce 70 to 50% of the
token consumption.
Now tips number two is customize your
agent memory. uh we all know how the
clock code SDK agent memory work where
you have the procedural memory and your
MD and also the episodic memory for each
training episode. So what we did
differently is because not all the
training log is helpful for us. We
developed our own memory API tool
meaning we add our own pruning and
compression logic on the server side to
decide what is useful to store and then
we also put a very lightweight reward
model for the agents of what kind of
memory gets written here. Now I do want
to claim that it is working in our
production now but very likely in the
next three to six months this is going
to become tech debt. It depends on how
fast our agent evolves.
Um and in the end I want to leave you
all like kind of an open question
thought what happens for long horizon
development memory. Um without long
horizon memory uh model often collapse
and then we see beyond clock code what
cursor is doing right now it's
essentially using a hybrid retrieval
semantic search uh and also compile its
uh constant constant reinct memory via
Merkel tree uh which is the backbone of
how cryptocurrency for example Ethereum
is is created um and also for open
source tool leta uh it's essentially
using the agent a blocked memory from
archive retrieval and also on top of
vector database. So the two papers I
read this month I thought it was quite
interesting is number one essentially
treat memory as a learned memory uh with
the agent and answer using PO and how to
answer using gRPO. Uh and then very
lastly a very interesting deep dive on
infraite where this paper uh condensed
the memory into hot domain and cold
storage via MCP. So thank you for the
time and I'll be down there if anyone
has any question.
Thank you so much Fay. Next we have
Yennis Hood from Scale AI. Let's give
him a warm welcome.
Um, I think I have this mic.
All right. Hello everyone.
Okay. Um, let me see if this work.
All right.
Okay. There's a delay. Cool. Hello
everyone. My name is Jiannis. I'm one of
the founder of SweetBench Pro. So in the
next a few minutes I want to quickly
talk about how we get to Sweetbench Pro
and what excites me when I think about
the next of coding agents.
So if we look way back there aren't much
change about how we code for almost 20
years but in the last several years the
change has been wide. We start seeing
cursor which is IDE plus AI and we also
start seeing foundational models start
competing on coding agent capability.
We also start seeing the development of
scaffolding which is basically tools we
given to agents to explore to run and to
write code. And later last year we start
seeing foundational model start training
with the scaffold.
On the measurement wise a team from
Princeton developed a benchmark called
sweet bench and it sets a cornerstone
for the entire coding agent
measurements. It used GitHub issue
resolution as the proxy to measure how
AI can do coding and then the entire
Sweetbench universe start diversifying.
There are basically different kind of
sweet bench testing the similar problem
on different kind of codebase but many
of them has a problem.
It is the contaminations.
As model grew larger and train on more
code,
data contamination become hard to avoid.
So it was natural for us to think, hey,
what if there's a benchmark, we can
create it with code that no model has
trained on.
That leads to the development of
Sweetbench Pro. And we started selecting
repos with a very strict license and we
realized hey that wasn't enough. We want
to be more extreme. So we start
acquiring company for their proprietary
codebase.
So beyond solving the minimal
contaminations we also have humans to
verify each problem has the right amount
of context. So it's both challenging but
also solvable. We also want to make sure
we have enough coverage into different
domain industry to make sure the problem
are being challenging but for a good
reason.
So that has been a pretty good success.
Sweetbench pro has become the industry
standard and different model release
start using speedbench pro as their
coding capability verification. And we
recently got a shout out from OpenAI
where SweetBench Pro was recommended
over OpenAI's their own benchmark.
However, there has been a question I
keep thinking about after the release of
Sweet Bench Pro. What is the next thing?
Should we keep building a harder problem
like Ultra Max Plus?
It might be helpful, but is there
anything else we can contribute?
Um, by a quick show of hands, I wonder
who here is or has been a software
engine.
Cool. That's lots of you. And please
raise your hands again if you have been
doing more than just Kithub uh issue
resolution.
That's almost the same group. So I think
here's my conclusion.
Coding is not just GitHub resolution.
There are a lot more to do being a
software edge. So what else is there? We
ran a quick surveys among engineers and
we found issue resolution is around a
quarter of time and that quarter has
been declining because of the coding
agent capability.
Sweet bench pro measured that quarters
which encouraged the industry to develop
in this direction. But what else? How
can we encourage the industry to measure
and build towards the rest of the
ecosystem?
So that's why we start building again.
So today is actually the first day we
are launching this one to the public. Um
the official launch of the first stage
release will be tomorrow but we are
launching a new benchmark that assess
how agent can understand, validate and
improve the software system in real
repository. So the first stage will be
tomorrow and each of the type of task
require more than just observation from
the codebase. We require coding agent to
actually go in explore and run the codes
in order to do the multi file reasoning.
Beyond just measurements, we also create
post- train data to help model builders
to improve this capability. And within
our benchmark, we have rubrics to help
different model builders to their
failure analysis.
I don't want to give give away too much
before tomorrow's launch, but I'm very
excited to see um this improvements of
coding agents in the new directions.
To end this presentation, I want to
quickly share about our insights about
next stage coding agents.
We start seeing a trend of coding being
the legs and hence for AI.
Our vision believe if we give coding
agents enough freedom, it will start
developing tools that it make more sense
to the agent themselves that's more
intuitive and effective. Actually, we've
seen some early signal
terminal bench which is another
benchmark developed by Stanford team.
They measures how AI can explore their
capacity through com command line.
And we have seen another signal which is
open claw. It's very popular nowadays.
We see agents start building their own
tools to solve a generic problem that's
not just software engine.
So in order to match our visions, we
have a road map which one of them is to
develop a more diverse playground for
the coding agents where agents can go in
and explore their own intelligence and
expand their capability.
And of course we don't want to leave
human behind. So we also want to
increase human agent interactions. We
strengthen agents capability to escalate
and call humans when it needs help.
where information are missing,
contradicting or is unclear.
We are also doing another collaborations
with the original terminal bench team to
develop the next generation of terminal
bench and we are expanding into
different professional domain such as
healthcare, finance, legal or different
kind of engineers.
To close this presentation, I want to
share that we never expect what we are
leaving to this world as the final thing
of coding agents, but we are very
excited to see what kind of a splash we
can make to this world.
We hope what we're doing can serve as a
stepping stone for this community to
build the next era of coding agents.
Thank you.
So, thank you so much, Jianis. Next, we
actually have Erin Ahmed from Clerk.
Please give a warm welcome.
Okay. Hey everyone, my name is Aaron.
Um, I'm the head of product at Cleric
and today I'm going to talk uh through a
little bit about what we've learned
building a learning agent.
So, let's start with what is a learning
agent? Well, it's the opposite of a
stateless agent. A stateless agent
starts a session fresh with no memory or
context of past conversations. Imagine a
co-orker that uh shows up to work every
day with no recollection of what
happened yesterday. That's the current
state of most of our agentic co-workers
today. A learning agent or a stateful
agent on the other hand um is one that
learns from experience and it adapts to
improve performance. And at Cleric, we
use agents to uh for every aspect of
building our own agent. And this is
where we see the puck moving. Um agent
capabilities are commoditized. This is
not this wasn't the case at this time
last year. And the next horizon of
differentiation is going to be learning
or self-learning. Um this is a a
conviction that we've built our product
around. Um the agents that earn their
place will be the ones that accumulate
knowledge about three things. your
environment, your team and how you work
and past outcomes and corrections. So
for cleric, cleric's an AI SRE. It
learns from every production incident.
You connect it to your infrastructure
and your observability and it
immediately starts building a model of
your environment. Uh you drop it into
your alerts channel and it learns from
your past incidents um and your your
channel history. uh and you use it as an
investigation assistant and it learns
your preferences and your procedures
over time. We've deployed it to
dozens of customers at this point and
what we've learned over months and to
you know now bordering on years of trial
and error is that there are essentially
three things um that make a good
learning agent. Uh the first thing is
good learning agents make it easy for
users to correct or to teach via
correction. Um, you know, wrong answers
are inevitable and accuracy is
important. Uh, but the agents that win
will be the ones that make it easy to
correct mistakes uh and not visibly
repeat those mistakes later. So for
cleric, this looks like proposing
memories uh that persist across
investigations. It looks like self-h
harvesting skills uh to encode learned
procedures um and capturing user ratings
on agent messages as uh an explicit
quality signal. Um, but the most
important part is the visibly never
repeating the mistakes. It's especially
important for a team-based agent like
Cleric where one user session and the
the corrections that are learned from
that apply to the next user session. Um,
and it leads into lesson two, which is
good learning agents reward corrections
with better performance. Um, you you
lose your users trust when they expend
the effort to teach the agent something
and that lesson is not retained. Um a
correction should do three things. It
should persist, compound and then be
visible. Uh by persist what I mean is to
the the agent applies that knowledge in
the same context. So for example if
after an outage um a user were to teach
cleric how to perform a customer impact
assessment uh you should expect the
agent to recall that procedure the next
time it's asked to do the same thing.
uh by compound I mean applying that
knowledge or sorry generalizing that
knowledge into a different context. So
perhaps there's something in that
procedure uh like some guidance about
how to distinguish between an internal
instance and a production customer
instance. Um a compounding effect would
be the agent using that context in a
different investigation like uh
automatically excluding internal
instances from uh you know an error rate
analysis of uh production customer
instances for example. And the third
thing is to be visible which is
essentially just the agent needs to show
its work. Um you know display the use of
knowledge and its actions and
reasonings. Um it does that does two
things. One, it gives the user the
visibility as to when a bit of its
knowledge needs to be corrected and it
also um shows them the impact of their
contributions which encourages them to
to contribute more.
But you can't rely on just the user to
correct the agent which leads us into uh
uh lesson three which is that good
learning agents absorb context
continuously.
um identify opportunities to put the
agent in the path of real work uh
automatically and absorb every source of
environment specific context available
so that learning happens ambiently and
doesn't rely on the user you know
calling on the agent explicitly. Um the
richer the model of the the the richer
the agent's model of the user's world
the the higher the utility.
Um and ultimately this you know all
three lessons apply to this single
learning loop and the current state is
uh you know individuals that use
stateless agents are only ever able to
to um complete the first section. You
use your your agent to act to do to take
an action to fix a bug to develop a
feature or even to investigate an
incident. Um but the missing piece here
is memory. It's operational memory.
That's what allows you to complete the
loop. Um,
and uh, the the three lessons um, they
all make up this this loop. You can't
have uh, one lesson without the other.
If you have um, if you make it easy to
correct, but you don't visibly improve,
then you lose the user's trust. If you
visibly improve, but you don't am
ambiently learn, then you're only ever
learning from where the user directs
you. It limits your learning. And if
you're ambiently learning, but you don't
allow the user to correct you, then you
run the risk of compounding errors. I
mean, think about all the dead code or
the outdated documentation that's just
laying in wait for the agent to stumble
on. Um,
so I would say that uh where I think
this is going is that the uh agents that
we'll be talking about uh at this
conference next year will be the ones
that are investing in this loop today.
So if you are building a learning agent
or you want to learn more, you want to
trade notes, um, come talk to me. I'd
love to talk to you. Thank you.
If there's anybody that has a question,
>> sure.
>> We do have time. If anybody has a
question for
us,
right back here?
>> Yeah, of course.
>> Run back. All
right.
Be speedy. Be expeditious.
>> Do you think everything you're
describing can be accomplished through
context engineering, or do you think you
need to do some kind of fine-tuning or
adjust the weights at some point?
>> Uh, we're not doing any fine-tuning, so
maybe that answers the question, but uh
I'm
Yeah, I think it's possible. Um, at
least today. And you know, as Peter
Steinberger says, these are the worst
the models are ever going to be. Um, so
I think that they will just like
continue to improve over time and this
will get easier. I think also the
foundation models are going to be
releasing a lot of these features and
that we'll we'll start to see um, you
know, we'll start to see these features
being available and not just in
specialized agents.
>> Oh, good. Okay. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
So, thank you so much again. Next, we
have Milan Williams from Simgrip. If
anybody have any questions for Aaron, uh
you can grab her afterward. She's
sitting over there. Let's give her a
warm welcome.
Sweet.
>> Awesome. Hi everyone. I'm Milan
Williams. Uh I'm a Oh, can you hear me?
Oh, perfect. Thank you.
Got it. Um I'm Milan Williams. I'm a
product manager at SEGRP. Uh Segrep
builds fast developer first security
tools um that are used by hundreds of
engineering teams. Um my day-to-day at
SGrep is really about how to make
security something that developers like
you all are excited to use. Um so in the
last 12 months my job has changed a lot.
Uh as you all have seen today uh AI is
taking on a whole new world when it
comes to uh code generation. It's not
just suggesting a few lines of code.
It's now hundreds of thousands of lines
of code that are mostly generated via
these long-standing mostly autonomous
sessions. Um, and with that shift comes
a pretty massive change in how security
is thought of. Agents are writing code,
but they're also running shell commands.
They're touching your file system.
They're doing all these actions with
elevated credentials and whatever access
you've decided to give them. And when
something goes wrong, unfortunately,
um, most people have really little idea
of what an agent is doing underneath the
hood. Uh, in the vast majority of cases
that I've seen with our customers, the
root cause is pretty obvious. It's that
most of us, myself included, spent what,
maybe five minutes, maybe 10, about 6
months ago, two years ago, setting up
their agent and then never really
stopped again after that to think about
all the access that we handed over. And
so in this very short talk, I want to
give you three very practical tips that
you can set up this afternoon to make
sure that if you go viral on Twitter,
it's for what you built and not for
getting hacked.
Cool. Uh the first tip there is uh
minimally scoped permissions. So before
you even prompt or set up any single
line of code, stop and ask yourself what
does the agent actually need access to?
Um most of us wouldn't hand a new intern
all of our production systems on day
one. And my view is that we should
provide the same guardrails to agents.
What's on the screen is instructions for
GitHub specifically, but you should know
that every major source code manager and
cloud provider gives you the ability to
downscope your access tokens. So if you
can avoid it in all costs, please don't
use your personal token or anything that
is an admin level access. Create
something that's scoped to what you
actually need the agent to do. The best
case, let's say the agent just gets
confused or worst case it gets hijacked
through a prompt injection or something
worse. Um, your blast radius is only
limited to the repo and environment that
you've given it, not everything in your
system.
The second one uh is uh setup logging.
It's not the most exciting thing, but
trust me on this one when I say in every
postmortem I've been in, the first
question is always the same, which is
just what happened. And if you don't
have a record, it is very very difficult
to figure out what the agent did, where
it went wrong, and how to prevent it
from happening again. Um, I do have to
give kudos to Cloud Code. They do a
really good job out of the box here. Um,
if you look in your uh projects folder,
you can see every single session and all
the actions that happened. Um, you can
also get more structured logs if you
want to pipe it to your SIM or any other
security tooling that you have. Um, for
any other tooling though, um, there's
not a lot here. So, I'm sure the rest of
the industry will catch up over time,
but, um, I think other folks talk about
it today, but most agents have some
concept of hooks that are built in or
scripts that are guaranteed to run after
every single agent action, no matter no
matter what. It's a deterministic part
of the product. Um, I've put together a
simple one here that's on the screen
that just shows um, it logs every single
shell command that cursor runs with the
timestamp associated with it. So, it's
just four lines. It's really simple. Um,
if you're on a team, you can distribute
it via an MD MDM. Um, just that way
every developer has it automatically,
but just some way so you have a record
of everything that happened. So, you
know, um, if things do go wrong, you
have uh, some some proof points to go
back to. Obviously, you can make this
way more advanced depending on your own
security posture and what you need, but
it really doesn't need to be
sophisticated in order to be useful if
something does go wrong.
And then the last one I've got for you,
great. Let's say your agent has built
something awesome. It's generated
thousands and thousands of lines of
code. One thing you need to be aware of
is how do you know if that code is
secure? Um manual code review is
probably not going to scale with uh long
running sessions. There are lots of
options for code scanning um for
enforcing vulnerabilities and for just
good coding practices. Um there are
language specific llinters like gok um
claude has their own built-in security
review bot. Really you can take your
pick. Um I work at SEGRP and I
specifically work on our MCP server. Um
what we've built integrates with all the
major coding agents. It integrates with
cursor, with cloud code, windsurf,
whatever you like. Um I think it's a
great tool for this because um in most
engineering orgs today, uh it's pretty
rare that every developer is using the
exact same agent. Someone's using
cursor, cloud code, another third thing.
Um, SEM grip is a really great way to
provide a deterministic set of security
checks that run regardless of what end
agent someone is using. It runs totally
automatically. It runs on every single
line that the agent generates. So, you
don't have to opt in or try to remember
to run it. It's totally free and the
docs are on the screen.
Cool. That's my quick takeaway. So,
three simple things. Downscope your
credentials before you start. It takes 2
minutes and can save you from a really
bad day. Um, wire up an audit trail with
hooks. That way doesn't need need to be
sophisticated, but it'll be uh save you
from knowing what's went on in your
system. And number three, scan the
product before it ships. There's lots of
free options, but give some grip a try.
That's it.
>> We have time for two questions. Anybody?
If not, uh, let's give her a welcome
again. I mean,
all right, we have our last speaker. We
have Ash Lewis from Fino.
Thank you.
>> Hey everyone. Um
uh so yeah, what I'm going to talk today
um about is choosing the right model.
It's a really hard thing to do. Um and
then once it's in production,
maintaining the model accuracy is even
harder. Um so I'm the founder and CEO of
Fino Labs. We work on a product called
Pioneer. Um and my company before this
was a company called Dev GPT, which um
which we were using GPT3 for that for
that dev agent. Um it went viral which
was great but then we spent $2 million
on OpenAI's system which wasn't so
great. Um but we learned a lot of
lessons about building agents. So we put
this company together. We're based just
down the road in Palo Alto. Most of us
are exh Stanford, Google Deep Mind and
Apple. And yeah, we're fixing this
problem of how do you actually put small
models into agents. Um so first of all
the reason why this is a difficult
problem is you know there's lots of new
models that gets released. we don't
really know which which model is best
for which thing and actually that
changes really often as well. So we
don't really know you know next week
which which model will be
state-of-the-art for a specific task and
because of the way benchmarking works
actually something that's for example
good at coding might not be good at your
very specific type of coding. Um so
other than that it's really hard to
actually fine-tune these models not
because it's necessarily difficult to do
but because it's time consuming. um it's
very difficult to get the data to
fine-tune the models um which it turns
out you have that data it's in your
inference logs but we just don't get it
from the LLM providers and then what's
even harder which again we have through
inference is uh is to evaluate the model
you know actually how how good is the
small model at your task um so uh we've
we're kind of we've put together a
solution for this called pioneer which
is coming out in a few weeks time it's
actually on a wait list right now um and
the idea of pioneer is we think that
deploying an open source language model
is actually the first step as opposed to
that being kind of the the final thing
you do after fine-tuning. Um so what I
mean by that is we deploy a model be it
be it llama quen deep sea kim K2 and
then we monitor the inference um from
from that model we collect and we label
that with with synthetic data we refine
tune and we re reevaluate the model
before redeploying the model. So the
idea is is that let's say that you've
put a model in place for um model
routing or or code generation. We're
actually going to be repeatedly doing
experiments on the background with an
agent that's checking can we actually
improve what is in in in situation
today. Um, and what that looks in
reality is that you end up with this
situation in which you've deployed llama
and it's actually getting more accurate
over time as opposed to the alternative
which would be that because of model
drift it's actually getting less
accurate over time. Um, and and so so
there's a couple ways best practices to
make this work. And the first one is you
need to partition your usage. So instead
of you using you know clawus 4.6 six for
everything. We actually say, "Okay,
let's use lots of different instances of
whichever model for lots of different
things." And then we can actually
improve all of those models um
independently.
Um so, so no longer do we actually
necessarily mind which model we're
selecting. It could be Kimmy K2, it can
be llama, it can be Quen. Um it actually
just it's just a description of the task
and then you know our agent will go
ahead and figure out while we're
inferencing what what's what's actually
best for the task. Um so a quick kind of
demonstration of how this works. Um so
you know if I was to go and ask for this
um model that turns weather information
into JSON blobs. Um again as a developer
I have no idea which model is best for
this. I definitely don't have time to
fine-tune a bunch of models and I don't
really have a benchmark for this. Um so
what's going to happen is our agent's
basically going to go ahead and figure
out the answer to the question of which
model we should be using. So in this
case, as you can see at the bottom here,
uh it's done experiments with Llama,
Gliner, uh DeepSeek, and it's giving you
accuracy reports for each one of those.
Um and more importantly, what's going to
happen is as we're inferencing, we can
use all that great inference data
because we know what your users are
actually using the model for to improve
the model's performance over time. Um
which has an added benefit of we can
actually reduce the cost and latency
over time as well because we might be
able to use a smaller model for the same
use case. Um so here we are digging into
the inference logs here um to actually
see uh to see what experiments the agent
has has ran on our behalf. Um you can
also fine-tune models on this platform.
On the left here we have like a caster
style agent where you can you can
fine-tune models for those use cases as
well. Um yeah this this model is in uh
sorry this this product is in private
alpha right now and we're launching it
in a few weeks time. So we'd uh we'd
love folks to to join the wait list. Um,
yeah, and that's about it. Got a couple
minutes left for for questions.
>> Yeah, sorry, a little bit fast.
>> No questions.
>> Great. Thank you so much, Ash.
Hello. Hello. How is everyone doing?
>> A huge shout out to everybody who just
spoke. It was a great lightning talk
according to me. How do you all feel?
Cool. Let's move on to the next set of
keynote speakers. So I will be calling
upon Ankut Ankit Matur from data bricks.
Um over to you and big round of applause
for him.
All right. Um, thanks everyone for being
here. Uh, my name is Ankit. I work on
infrastructure at data bricks. um
excited to chat today about uh coding
agents.
So
um representing a lot of work from
Arushi, my co-speaker. She wasn't able
to make it uh because of some travel
issues. Uh but uh let's let's get
started. Um
I feel like we live in one of the most
exciting times to be an engineer. uh and
and it's really incredible like for many
years the impact of technology has been
uh extremely substantial in the sense
that people are working super hard you
know technologies deployed in society
and it's creating incredible change but
what's been rare is having resources
like engineers who are really really
incredible and high output and now we
live in an era where it feels like every
time uh a new model comes out we have
just another kind of 10x engineer here.
Uh, and so there's lots of coding tools
out there. I'm sure all of you have
tried uh, several of them. Cloud code,
Gemini CLI, cursor, codeex, and you
know, Google actually has two. Uh, so
it's, uh, naturally, I think it's going
to become a huge challenge to figure out
how to actually get these things
deployed within your enterprise. So,
let's take a little bit of a different
perspective on deploying coding agents
today. Uh, and think about it from the
perspective of an IT admin.
uh even though we as engineers are
having some of the best times ever right
this solving this problem is actually a
lot of work for it especially at large
enterprises where data security is
important uh what are the main problems
right if you're actually using multiple
of these coding tools then you typically
are having to manage multiple different
vendor contracts different admin
consoles your billing is all over the
place you're getting charged by uh every
different kind of coding provider uh You
don't actually know who's using what in
your enterprise and it's actually
difficult to enforce critical security
policies like not having data be used
for training for any of these models if
you want to pass PII.
These are real problems that most IT
admins have to deal with. And so even
though for us as engineers it's awesome
to try out every new tool uh this is
something that actually is slowing down
the deployment of these incredibly
valuable resources these incredibly
valuable 10x engineers in today's
enterprise landscape.
When you take a security lens on it, it
it gets even more complicated, right?
These are some of the most privileged
users. They have you want them to
actually have access to everything. You
want them to be able to read the
description of a task in Jira uh action
on it based on uh your cloud
infrastructure and your code repository.
You want it to have access to external
APIs so that it can do a lot more
information gathering when you're
debugging an incident. uh and and you
want it to really be able to read about
the context of your company too. You
want it to know your code words and all
the different design docs that might be
in play. Uh so that's actually the power
of these tools. But at the same time,
you want to make sure that if only your
executive team has access to a document
that it's not pulled in when an API call
from an agent is being made.
So these are real problems that are very
hard to solve today. And I I actually
think these are some of the number one
reasons that people aren't using more
coding tools.
What do developers actually do in
enterprises? Um well, typically there is
uh some tool of uh that you know has
been blessed by it. That's the tool of
record uh and everyone uses that one.
But what's actually happening with how
fast today's landscape is moving is that
developers are taking a look at the
various complex nuanced benefits of each
kind of model and using them for
different use cases. So you might for
example use a different tool for
refactoring code than for writing tests
and maybe a different one to review the
code. uh like I myself use uh clawed
code to write my code but then I use a
different model usually codeex to review
it and I've found a lot of success in
that model because it it tends to be the
case that if the model wrote the code it
doesn't see fundamental design flaws
that might be in it I mean by the way
that's like kind of the same as humans
right so uh this is something that's
really uh a workflow that enhances
productivity right and I think that
first slide that we had that talked a
little bit about the leverage that these
coding tools buy is extremely important
to remember in this context. Before when
you used to bet on software, you'd pick
one and it would be mostly fine because
things were 10 15% better. Uh and you
know that's not enough to move the
needle on that kind of thing. But if
you're getting 10 to 15% more
productivity or better code, that's the
most kind of valuable asset that you can
have. So you should absolutely use the
best tool for your use case, even if
that's not the one-sizefits-all solution
that you have already.
So it's just extremely limiting as a
developer and I think this will become
more and more true as more models become
amazing at coding. Um it's already the
case that people's different harnesses I
mean we even saw a number of the talks
that we've seen today a lot of
investment and innovation is going into
harnesses on top of the models and so
for different use cases this is going to
continue to be true.
Now, if you take what this what what
happened here with the slide before that
where IT admins have a lot of trouble
just even managing procuring a few of
the tools and then you have all these
developers who are actually just trying
to use stuff on their own and and
they're probably going to work around
it. Uh you end up with a really really
challenging problem. And so this is and
and like you know for the reasons that I
said around security, this isn't a
trivial thing. This isn't a process
problem. This is a real issue that needs
to be solved. Um and so we call this
thing agent sprawl. Um and it's
happening everywhere. Uh as more and
more of us use these coding tools, I
really believe that coding tools are
going to be a top 10 cost driver for all
of these companies. So this is a really
important problem for us to solve. Uh so
today I'm going to talk a little bit
about uh a technology that we've built
to to address this problem and and how
we use coding tools at data bricks to to
maybe just share some learnings from
that.
What we built was this thing called the
coding agent gateway. Uh we really
believe strongly that developers should
be free to use whichever tools that they
want. Uh but in order to do that, we
need to meet admins and enterprise
admins exactly where they're at and help
them solve the important security
problems uh and procurement problems
that they have. And so we think a
gateway helps solve those things. Uh
what does the gateway do? Well, it just
provides observability, right? First
important thing is always to just
collect data on what's going on. Um, and
so you want to know which users are
hitting rate limits. Uh, who are the
people who are your power users because
they're probably also your biggest
champions to make coding tools more and
more popular in your engineering
organization. Uh, you want dashboards to
actually show all of this information,
right? If it's a top 10 cost driver,
inevitably uh, you know, your finance
team is going to care about it at some
point. Uh, and that's related to cost
controls, right? it it doesn't make
sense if you're using three tools to
have three different cost controls in
different places. Uh ideally you'd like
to be able to say hey like let this
person use let's say $1,000 a month but
across any coding tool that they really
want to
put freedom and control back in the
hands of the developer but you as an
admin can get a single bill from that.
Uh and then privacy, right? Like a lot
of people uh work at companies where
there's really critical data, there's
PII that people don't want to pass uh
into models and have it be trained on.
Uh you want to make sure that you're
controlling for that because that is
really really important to the
compliance posture of your company. Um
and and even though coding has gotten a
lot faster, compliance hasn't gotten any
easier.
So we think this is better for kind of
all sides of a company. And uh I'm going
to show you a little bit today of what
that looks like in practice.
Um let's see.
Okay, cool. So here I'm in my laptop,
right? Um and uh what does it look like
to have this like multiAI coding
gateway? Well, we have a very very
lightweight wrapper that just reports
metrics to our gateway and points coding
tools at it, right? And so all I need to
do is this and it logs in in one place
and boom, you've got cloud code here. Uh
and you can talk to it. Uh you'll notice
that it's point sorry what
>> can you increase the font size?
>> Oh yes absolutely. Sorry about that.
>> Um
okay hopefully that's a little bit
better.
There we go.
Um so you'll notice this is pointed at
uh this like data bricks opus 46. That's
because we're providing that capacity
natively within our serving platform. Uh
so you don't have to then go like kind
of yet a separate uh relationship with a
different provider. So that solves your
procurement problem. Okay, cool. So
let's say I wrote some code with cloud
code and I want to actually just review
it myself before I send it out, right?
All I need to do is something like this.
And boom, now I have codeex open. Uh and
I can do the same thing. Hey, please
review my code.
and it'll just kick itself off, right?
You could do now you can imagine doing
the same exact thing for for cursor or
uh for any of the many other coding
tools that are out there. And each of
these coding tools will have their own
strengths and their own weaknesses. And
I think that will continue over time. So
uh developers will typically like to uh
will will like to use the tool that's
best for the use case in that case,
right? Okay, cool. So I did all this
stuff, right? That's what it looks like
for the developer. super easy, not too
different from your existing workflow.
You're using the same harness that you
were using before. But what did it get
for the admin? Uh well, so we have this
thing that uh you know, it looks like an
AI gateway and it has uh a bunch of
frontier models in it. It has open
source models in it. I think there's a
lot of amazing open source coding models
that are extremely fast. Uh but
critically it has uh built-in dashboards
and reporting that goes into the same
place where all your other cost data
goes which is your data warehouse. Um
here you can see a lot of important
metrics like how many requests have been
sent? How many tokens am I using? Um
which coding tools are popular within my
company. Uh which are the users who are
using the most and which ones are they
using? And then if you actually uh are
ingesting all those metrics, right, you
can start visualizing them in one place
too. There's critical metrics like how
many lines of code you're adding, how
many sessions you're doing that are that
are important for people to track. Um
and so these kinds of things we feel are
extremely important to uh being able to
deploy these coding tools really really
rapidly. So when for example the codeex
models get better, it's not a debate
between developers and admins about
whether we should get it or not. You
just get it. You point it at the same
gateway and you have comfort that you
have the same observability that you did
before. Um let's go back to the slides.
So there is something I think that we
haven't talked about but is super
important. Um and I think it might even
be like the elephant in the room. It's
maybe the number one coding innovation
coding tool innovation that I have
experienced in the last couple months.
Um so what is it? Um
it's MTPs.
I think like you know these API
endpoints that people have giving access
to these MCP servers has dramatically
expanded what these coding tools can do
now rather than like me taking
information from my calendar and posting
it in explicitly. I can actually have
these agents work on my behalf in many
many capacities across work not just
writing code. Uh but in order to do
that, the typical setup flow involves
local token storage where you store
these things in like plain text. Uh
they're not necessarily rotated. They
might be c, you know, set up in a custom
way. And so that creates these like kind
of security concerns. And again, the way
that these things manifest is is that
they're just not a available inside of
lots of enterprises. Like there just
isn't a Jira MCP until there's a
reasonable story for how it would be
secured. Um, and so this is a problem we
also want to solve, right? But we don't
think it should be uh using any kind of
locally stored to uh tokens. And so
we've kind of just put this into the
same data catalog that people already
had. Uh it's fully encrypted. It's it's
fully managed. We have auto rotation.
And this way you're just able to point
at your API endpoints and you don't
really have to think about it. You owe
once into data bricks. You already did
that for setting up your coding tool and
now you have access to all of those
tokens that are either uh you know user
pass through so you kind of uh you know
are accessing accessing it as yourself
or they're a shared token and you're
accessing it as the organization um
that's kind of now in the control of
these admins and so this again enables
people to start having lots of MCP
tools.
So I wanted to talk a little bit about
this because I wanted to explain like
this thing is how we have deployed
coding tools at data bricks. Um and so I
wanted to just share some learnings with
the with the group and and you know uh
after this I'd love to talk to more
people and learn from all of you as
well. Um so what is what is a little bit
of about data bricks like we have a lot
2,000 plus engineers across lots of
different offices. um lots of code is
being written in at least seven
languages and usually someone is pushing
for an eighth or a ninth or whatever. Uh
so code's being merged all the time. So
this is a really really important
problem for us. Uh what was helpful for
us? Well, I I think like measuring
everything was really really helpful and
I'll show you a little bit of of the
dashboards that we've built. Um everyone
needed to be leaning in. Uh we have
awesome developers at data bricks but it
took a lot of effort to convince people
that they needed to spend all their time
learning how to use these tools. It's
not just like do the same stuff you were
doing before. Uh I feel there's at least
a little bit of learning curve on how to
actually use these things effectively
and to do that every single person not
just like uh the newest engineers needs
to lean into using these tools. Uh and
finally the industry is moving at just
an incredible pace. uh new models come
out every week that improve the frontier
and so it's no longer true that in order
to move the frontier you needed to do
five years of of research like the
frontier is moving every week um so you
need to move fast as well so what do we
what did we have that like kind of
developers can use we have this harness
like you know I showed it to you uh
locally we call it internally Isaac
um Isaac allows you to use any of the
coding tools but it's a single interface
that people can use to launch them so
that they get unified reporting on
metrics as I had shown as and so that
like uh a bunch of configurations under
the scenes for example MCPS and token
capacity can be configured.
So within Isaac we route the metrics
through our coding gateway as well as
our MCP login and the coding gateway is
then dumping that usage data in those
dashboards which I showed. uh the
capacity is pointed at a single place.
So we have one place where our finance
team gets all the the full bill for all
the different models. Um and we have
tool calls that go directly through this
gateway. So every day when I start my
work, I log into Isaac and Isaac ows me
to a new uh you know refreshes my token
and now I'm able to use all the MCP
servers I had connected.
So this is like one of the internal
dashboards that we have. I I um wanted
to show exactly how important this is
for us. The default the dashboard I had
shown you was the default but the
critical piece of data is that the that
dashboard is just built on tables within
data bricks and so you can reorganize
that however you want. Uh we have
executive views on the dashboard for you
know tracking how many what percentage
of the companies using coding tools
which ones they're using uh how many
lines are being written and then we also
have team level drill downs where you
know people can like look in within
specific orgs like who is using the most
tools um or the most coding tools. So so
this is really really critical and this
is the dashboard that our executive team
now reviews every single meeting.
Um in terms of MCPS right we've
registered them uh on one page uh and
when you log in you can actually
configure which connections you want
like do I want to be connected to Glean
Jira and Google or just a few of them it
is important to actually configure that
because if you just pick every MCP
server you're actually flooding the
input context of your requests and
making them slower and more expensive.
Um so that's a decision that users still
have to make today. Uh but then yeah,
like I said, right, all I do is when I
log in as a developer, I get this URL, I
click on it, I authenticate, and I'm
good to go.
Um, everyone needs to be leaning in. I I
I always like showing this slide where
uh this our our CEO Ali actually is
writing code now using Isaac and and and
modifying it as well. Um,
we would not have been as successful
deploying coding coding tools within
data within data bricks without explicit
executive like demand to deploy these
things. Um and so this is really really
critical I think to to expanding the
impact of this technology.
And finally, we think the bottlenecks
are shifting really dramatically. Um I I
I want to talk about like coding code
reviews. I I feel like it's much much
harder and uh the volume of coding code
reviews that you know at least I
personally now have is way way up and it
feels like the tooling hasn't been able
to keep up. So I think there's a huge
amount of open opportunity for better
code reviews and better tools to do
these things. Um but this isn't a solved
problem and I would now say that at
least at data bricks our velocity is
most bottlenecked by this one thing by
our ability to scalably scalably review
this code. Same thing with CI. If you're
deploying 10 to 100 agents per human, uh
you've suddenly made massive scalability
requests from your CI team. Uh and so
our CI is is now costing us way more
than it did before. And it's really
really painful when people mess up, for
example, the dependency graphs and lots
and lots of tests are running for every
change. So it's more important than ever
to have the right abstractions between
projects and between different services
so that this becomes less of a problem
and agents have a faster dev loop. And
the final thing is testing. Um the
models are still not like perfect at
animating code and at least one thing
that we have discovered is giving them
an explicit validation signal on the
code very early in the life cycle allows
quality to go up and allows the model
the model and the agents to enter
virtuous loops where they're improving
the code effectively. One of the things
engineers do is they have context on the
world in which their code will be
deployed and they reason about the way
that they write things in that way. The
models don't always have that context. A
lot of that is in our heads or in a
document somewhere and it takes a lot of
explicit effort to go and write that
down and then also to design shift left
kind of testing methodologies where
you're able to call command and have the
tool tested. So we for example uh had a
technology that was kind of like used by
some people that's now used by a lot of
people uh which allows you to like
develop a service and then swap it into
a staging instance. This is incredible
for the agents because they're able to
write their code and then you can swap
it into a realistic environment where
you can use the product. uh without that
like when without that thing in the
middle what we found is that the agents
were often writing code that was
completely unrealistic to deploy or was
extremely unperformant.
So more and more investment needs to go
into shifting this kind of testing left.
So we would love to just learn from
everyone here who's using coding agents.
Thank you for for uh listening. If you
build coding tools and want to
supercharge your users experience like
please reach out to us. uh we're really
focused on bringing things like
governance, observability, and privacy
for coding tools, and we really want to
help developers use all of them. So,
thank you very much.
>> I think we got time for we got time for
some questions. Who's got something?
Anything? Where are we at?
>> One in the back.
>> That was a That was a good talk. There's
one in the back. Oh, way back. All
right. Make me run for it. Here we go.
>> Yeah. Hey, thank you so much. Like the
talk. Um, love how you covered the MCPs.
Curious how you would integrate skills
and kind of the proliferation of skills
and knowing what's actually happening in
your indust organization, who's using
what skills and why.
>> Yeah, that that's a that's a great
point. Um and it and it's something that
we haven't really built out yet, but
which is super top of mind for us
because um yeah, as soon as skills
launched um they just like every team
has a skill now and most of them are
doing the same thing. Uh so it doesn't
feel like uh there's enough organization
yet uh where you know the organ where
people within engineering are able to
leverage the work other people did. Um
so I do think there's a lot of work to
do to be honest. I don't 100% know how
to solve that. Like one thing that would
be useful at least for me from my
perspective is if you could like when
I'm introducing a skill if if there was
some like way to know that there was a
very similar skill already um that would
be great cuz then I would just add to
that but it feels really intractable for
humans to read like thousands of
markdown files. So not sure the answer
to that but I do think skills are going
to be important part of governance.
>> Um just a quick question on Isaac. I
know you measure HTTP requests, but what
about actual tool calls on the computer
that's running? Do you have like any
performance metrics that you level up so
that let's say a particular command line
tool is being used a lot by the
organization? Uh do they get visibility
on that?
>> Yeah, great question. Um yes. So one
thing I wasn't able to show is that uh
but but which is there in production
already is that um with MLflow you can
actually trace all the cloud code
requests and we do that as well. So
we're ingesting, you know, thousands of
of tra tens of thousands of traces per
day. And one of the things we discovered
from that particular piece of data is
that uh cloud code for example like to
do a lot of file search. Um and we had
like a like we in our cloud environment
for some reason the standard one it
wanted to use was very slow. So at the
top level uh repo claude MD we actually
added a very explicit instruction which
was like please use RG to search for
stuff do not use anything else and that
was super valuable and would not have
been something people would have not
like figured out easily without that.
>> Thanks. Um earlier you had mentioned
that as part of the gateway you have to
pick and choose the MCPS so you don't
flood with context. So this leads to a
couple things. How do you curate the
MCPs which are allowed? And also at what
point do you need an MCP for your MCPs?
>> Uh yeah. Uh that's like really related
to this like title for like you know you
have this like meta um multiverse thing.
Um
yeah I I think that
>> for example some of the folks I know who
build harnesses have spelt have spent a
lot of time on this on on MCP tool
selection. So I actually think that uh
and and like recently Enthropic launched
uh tool search as a tool uh within uh
the model. So I do think the harness
layer is going to figure out soon how to
manage the MCPS today. I think it is
still true that developers are best off
managing it on their own like per use
case. I don't think that will be true
like even two months from now. Um I hope
we don't need MCPS for our MCPS because
that sounds pretty complex but um who
knows? I I don't think that will be
needed because uh MTP itself is kind of
just a wrapper on like existing APIs and
like a standardizing methodology for
existing APIs. So hopefully we don't
need a layer in front of that. I do
think we need like a governance layer
for those MCPs.
>> Um cool. One one of the things I've seen
I think the thing you mentioned about
being able to write code locally and
then hot swap it into a staging or
preview environment seems to be one of
the biggest bottleneck outside of like
overall lots of code to review and
things like this like what do you think
is what have you seen as
state-of-the-art in terms of like the
time it takes to go from one or more
repos with local changes to something
that a user can interact with? Um yeah,
I think this is uh something where each
like organization's build tools are
different and so it's like an area for
the testing teams to invest in. Um I
think historically one may have argued
that oh it's like why don't you just
write unit test and then deploy it into
dev. Um, so I think that it's an
investment everyone needs to make on
their own, but like for people for
example who use Docker based services
like not hard to swap in a new image.
Uh, but you do need like some way of
like routing to that service. And so for
integrating with this like hot swap
technology required our services to
actually update themselves. So we have
code in our services that basically says
if you're in swap mode like point at
some other thing in from a networking
perspective. Um so it took work to on
board to it.
>> Excellent. Thank you. Let's give it up
everybody. Thank you sir. That was
awesome dude. Very stoked on that
presentation. All right before I bring
up Dex I got to say I met James and
James Yeah. Can you stand up real fast?
James told me this morning that he is
going We can't see the QR code. You got
to hit it up. He's going to be having
dinner tonight and everybody's invited.
So, if you want to go, just scan that QR
code real fast and go hang out with
James. That's awesome. And that's what
we're going for here. That is great.
Yeah, you rock. Yeah, that's I like it.
I like it, too. Okay, so I'm going to
bring up Dex. Uh earlier somebody said
we need to have a mustache competition.
I don't think that's going to happen.
But I will say that he gave us 200
slides that he's about to present.
>> Whoa. Whoa. 158.
>> 158. We're going to keep him honest on
the timing. All right. So, let it start
now. Amazing everybody.
>> Let's do it. What's up, everybody?
>> Dex.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, I am Dex. Uh, this is a talk with a
very long title that I'm not going to
read because we're on the clock now. Uh
I have been talking about coding agents
for quite a while basically since like
August. Um we did a long talk in
November. Um there's this methodology
that we've been talking about a lot uh
called research plan implement. Um a lot
of up votes on hacker news. There's
probably 10,000 people who have gone to
our open source and grabbed our prompts
and are using them internally from small
startups up to the enterprise. Um it all
started with this guy. Um this guy has
anyone seen this talk?
>> Yes. Okay. So Eigor went in and he said
like okay cool. We're using a lot of
tokens. are spending a lot of money to
get AI developer productivity. But what
he found was that it actually tends to
lead to a lot of rework. Like you are
shipping 50% more, but half of that is
just cleaning up the slop from last
week. And the other thing they found,
and these are last year's numbers, so
this does not account for Opus 4.5. So I
would I would inflate this a little bit,
but like it's great for low complexity
green field tasks, not great for
high complexity brownfield tasks. Um,
and so I could give you a talk about RPI
and why it's great. Uh, but that would
be boring. And there's other talks. So,
if you haven't seen them, go watch them.
It'll give more context. But, uh, I'm
going to tell you everything we got
wrong about RPI today. Um, we thought we
had this AI thing figured out. I, uh,
am, uh, humble enough to admit when I
was wrong. Uh, so we got a couple things
wrong. Uh, one thing that's very
relevant if you've been on Twitter today
is, uh, I don't think it's okay to not
read the code. Uh, I also don't think
you should read really long plan files.
Those two are related. Uh, and no cloud
should not be allowed to if you if you
writing production code that is used by
users and you're going to get pageent 3
a.m. if it's broken. Uh, no slop. This
is the year 2026. No more slop. So,
we're all on this journey. We're all
figuring this out. We all are wrong all
the time. We did get get a couple things
right. Uh, there is no magic prompt. Uh,
do not outsource the thinking. You, the
engineer, are an important part of this
process. And seek leverage. There's a
lot of code being written. find ways to
make sure it's correct without having to
read all of it and resteer after the
fact. Um, so lots of people I'm sure
have heard of research plan implement.
Has anyone actually run this cloud
command research codebase? Okay, cool.
Leave your hand up if you've run it like
this. Tell me how this system works. Has
anyone run it like this of like, hey, I
want to build this thing. Go do the
research.
Okay. Um, or maybe go fetch a ticket or
something. What about the create plan uh
prompt? Okay, couple hands. Uh, how many
of you run it like that? you know, hey,
we got to go build this thing. Yes. Has
anyone run it like this? Work back and
forth with me, starting with your open
questions and outline before writing the
plan. Okay. Some of you found out about
the magic words. A lot of people didn't,
though. Uh, we'll get into why that's a
problem. Um, so since October, we've
basically worked with thousands of
engineers from tiny startups all the way
up to Fortune 500s. Um, and we would
find over and over again, we would give
these tools to an expert, uh, and they
would get great results. They would go
sit and talk to Cloud for 70 hours a
week and they would start shipping like
crazy. uh and then they would go give it
to their team and the results were not
always so good. Um and so people weren't
getting good results and so we got in
the trenches with our users and we went
to go figure out what was going wrong
and the first thing that was going wrong
was people were not getting good
research. Um so we talked about this in
November. This is uh one of the only
slides I'm reusing but you would pick a
zone of your codebase. You would say,
"We're going to build something over
here." And then you would launch at a
coding agent session to go send these
sub agents through these deep vertical
slices through the codebase for just the
context, compressed context about what
is the thing we're about to go build,
right? And we said keep things
objective, discourage opinions, don't
actually put any implementation details
in there. You just want to compress the
truth. What is true about how the code
works today? And a skilled engineer was
really good at taking, okay, here's my
ticket. let me write some questions that
will cause the model to go touch all the
parts of the codebase that matter. So if
it was, you know, add a new endpoint to
reticulate splines across tenants, we
would say something like, okay, tell me
how endpoint endpoints work and trace
the logic flow for everything that
touches splines and uh go find the
workers that do all the reticulation. Uh
so if this is your ticket, a lot of
people would run it like this. They
would just say, "Hey, research codebase.
Here's what I'm building." Um and the
problem is that good research is all
facts, but if you tell the model what
you're building, then you get opinions.
And we don't we'll get into why the
model shouldn't have opinions later
comes back to this thing that Jake from
Netflix came up with which is do not
outsource the thinking. Um the other
thing that wasn't working is people were
getting not great plans. Um and
basically there were these steps built
into this planning prompt uh that was
this single giant like monolithic thing
with 85 or more instructions and it had
these steps in it of like cool present
design options to the user uh get
feedback on the structure uh before you
actually go write the plan. And so a
good planning session would look
something like, you know, you have your
claude system tools and your prompt and
then you say, "Hey, create plan." Loads
the skill, looks at your ticket, loads
your research doc, launches a bunch of
sub agents to go find a bunch of things
that are true about the codebase, just
confirm some stuff that wasn't maybe in
the research. This is all one big
context window, by the way. Usually I'll
use these columns to mean separate
context windows, but today this is all
one session. I just slides are sideways,
so I had to put them on next to each
other. Um, but the agent would come and
ask questions. say, "Okay, here's our
options for question one." User would
pick an option. User would pick an
option. And then eventually it would
say, "Cool. Here's the order we're going
to do the things. Um, what do you
think?" And the user could say, "Well,
we need to add a testing step up front,
and I want to swap phases three and
four." Assistant would give the new
outline of the phases. Then the user
would approve it, and only then would we
write our plan file. Um, complex process
of aligning with the user on what was
what was going to be built. Um, but for
about 50% of people, maybe more, if you
didn't prompt it with this work back and
forth with me or Opus was just feeling
dumb for that that particular hour of
the day, um, it would just take the
stuff and it would just immediately go
and write the plan out. And so you would
get this and it would be like, cool, I
wrote the plan, didn't ask me any
questions, made all the decisions for
me. Yikes. So we gave the tools to
people and some people got good results
and some people didn't. And we dug in
and we were like, what's the difference?
Uh, and people would literally say this
to me, well, you have to say the magic
words. And I found myself in workshops
full of enterprise engineers
saying,"Well, guys, guys, guys, yeah,
here's the software, but don't forget to
say the magic words." It was, quite
frankly, it was embarrassing. But if you
said this, work back and forth with me,
starting with your open questions and
outline before writing the plan, then
the agent would ask you the questions.
And this isn't the user's fault. If you
built a tool that requires hours and
hours of training and reps to get like
good results from, go fix the tool. And
so I'll talk about how we did that. Um,
but why these steps were getting
skipped. The one of the big takeaways
I'll give you today is like you have an
instruction budget. Uh, my co-founder
Kyle is somewhere over here. He wrote
this really good blog post in December
or November I guess technically. Um,
that basically cited this archive paper
which again this is from last year. So
the number is probably a little bit
higher now, but that Frontier LMS could
only follow about 150 to 200
instructions with like good consistency.
anything more than that and it's kind of
half attending to all of them and you're
rolling the dice. So if you have a
prompt with 85 instructions and your
cloud MD and your system prompt and your
tools and your MCP
um yeah, you're not likely to get full
adherence to the workflow. So more on
how we fix this later. The other thing
that I think um really wasn't working
for people was like we advocated for
reading the plans that were output. This
is me on stage in November telling
people you have to read the plan
otherwise it won't work. Um some people
even would PR their plans and code
review them together. But a thousand
line plan tends to be about a thousand
lines of code within 10% or so. And
plans can have surprises. So you would
go and you would review the plan and
then you would go write the code and it
would be different. And so you're
telling you're asking one of your
co-workers like okay go spend an hour
reading this and tell me what's wrong
with it. And then you would go implement
it. It would be different. they have to
go read the code again and see what the
surprises were and what changed. Um, and
so this isn't leverage. Leverage is
about like do less work to get more
output. So the new advice, uh, don't
read the plans. Please read the code.
Uh, just because it's it's the same
amount of work and like look for
leverage elsewhere. And I'll talk about
how we found better leverage. Um, and
you may say, "Hey Dex, in August you
said don't read the code. You said the
plans are enough. Just don't just just
go just ship and let Cloud do its
thing." I was wrong. I am humble enough
to admit when I was wrong. Uh this is
actually a very big conversation right
now. Please please read the code. We
tried not reading the code for like six
months. Uh it did not end well. We had
to rip out and replace large parts of
that system. Um and you may say, "Hey
Dex, but other people don't read the
code." Beads 300,000 lines and counting.
Uh no one's read that code allegedly. Uh
OpenClaw Pete's like, "Okay, you know, I
know the structure and the pieces and
how they fit together, but I don't read
every line of every PR." Um, these are
OSS projects. They don't charge money.
Nobody gets paid at 3 a.m. if it's
broken. And no one gets fined millions
of dollars if it's done wrong. I will
also say though, these are OSS. They are
very, very cool projects. I am humbled,
deeply humbled by the accomplishments of
the maintainers and the stakes are still
high. Like if you break open claw, a lot
of people are going to be upset. But
they are different than if you're say
working in a regulated industry shipping
production SAS code. Um, so if you have
people who depend on your code, please,
I'm begging you, please read it. Please
read it. We have a profession to uphold.
2026 is supposed to be the year of no
more slop. Uh, literally everyone is
talking about the difference between
slop and craft. Uh, this is why I'm a
little mid on agent swarms and the whole
gas town thing because you still need to
be able to ensure quality and like going
10 times faster doesn't matter if you're
going to throw it all away in 6 months.
So shoot for 2 to 3x. That's actually
another talk of like how you measure
this and how you actually get there and
maintain like a near human level of
quality. Um but I'll talk about the
goals and like what you should think
about if you want to get there is you
should have high leverage planning. You
should not outsource the thinking read
and own the code and ideally we will
avoid uh magic words. So uh we got
better research, we got better plans, we
got better leverage. I'm going to talk
about each of those um as far as like in
general what we and like in specifically
what we did and also some general
concepts as you're building workflows
and systems around coding agents what
you can do. So we talked about a skilled
this is the least exciting one but
talked about how a skilled engineer
could detangle the ticket to the
questions to the research uh and then
the research would be very objective. Um
basically we just hide the ticket from
the context window that's doing research
and we do it deterministically. So
basically you have one context window to
generate questions and then a fresh
context window with no knowledge of what
we're building to go make your research
doc. Um this is pretty trivial if you're
familiar with the concept of query
planning. Um it's similar in concept but
for you know LMS reading through code
bases. Um so I've been hacking on agents
for a while and before we did the coding
agent stuff I wrote this paper called 12
factor agents which was uh allegedly the
first time anyone was like talking a lot
about context engineering. Uh there's
two ways to read context engineering and
most people jumped in. Is anyone
building like rag pipelines? Is it raise
your hand if you built a rag pipeline?
Okay, some people are feeling uh not
like not raising their hands today. Um
but it's like okay put more information.
You put too much information in the
model can't make sense of it. I actually
think the more interesting read of
context engineering is like better
instructions and simpler tasks and
smaller context windows. Of course, we
all know Jeff now. I don't have to
introduce him anymore. I used to have to
I used to have to tell people who Jeff
was when I was talking. Um we talked
about this like context window thing is
the idea of the dumb zone which is you
know you have about 168,000 tokens and
200,000 but some of them are reserved
for output. You have various things that
they're for and around like 40% on
average depending on what you're doing
and how much of your context is user
messages versus files and all of this
stuff. You hit this point where you have
degrading results. And obviously
sometimes you can get still get good
enough for you results at 60%. But the
less of the context window you use the
better results you will get. Um our
friends at data bricks were just talking
about you have too many MCPS the whole
context window is full of instructions
about how to use a bunch of tools that
you don't care about and then by the
time you're writing code the model is
like not good at following your
instructions. So you're not just giving
the model too much information. You're
also probably giving it too many
instructions.
And so the idea of what we're doing was
this thing like makes a lot of sense.
Use prompts for control flow. This is a
customer support example, but you know,
if it's a complaint, go do this. If it's
product feedback, go do this. If it's a
billing issue, go do this. Um, and what
you can do instead is you can instead of
using prompts for control flow, you can
kind of classify the input and then feed
it to a series of smaller, more focused
prompts where there are far fewer
instructions and far fewer actions to
choose from. I'm sure many of us have
already done things like this to improve
the performance of pipelines. Um, so
this was a single mega prompt with 85
instructions. Um, and if you did it
right, you would go through all these
different steps. All these different
phases were part of that. And if any of
the instructions didn't get followed,
you would skip the things that made this
really high leverage. Um, so we split it
across several prompts. And so like
before it was research, plan, implement.
Now it's questions, research, design,
structure, plan, work, tree, implement,
PR. We're actually not going to have
time to talk about the implement side of
the thing today, but um, we split up the
planning into a design discussion and
outline and a plan. And before it was 85
instructions. Now they're all less than
40 which is really exciting and I think
some of them could actually be even
smaller. We're still iterating on them.
The lesson is don't use prompts for
control flow if you can use control flow
for control flow. Like the if statement
is really really powerful and LM are
really good at classifying things. This
is not just true for coding agents. This
is any AI LLM based system you're
building. Um and it's really funny
because we were writing all this stuff
and we got on stage we said like full
fat agents don't work. Don't just call
tools in a loop. Do context engineering
and build workflows and graphs and micro
agents. We told everybody, "Don't do
this." And then we turned around in
August and we're like, "All right, but
this cloud code thing is pretty good."
And we turned around and we wrote this
giant monolithic prompt. So, we figured
it was time to actually go drink our own
Kool-Aid. Um, mind your instruction
budget.
How do we get better leverage? So, we
split things up to get better
instruction following, right? These
three different phases. But we also got
more leverage. And I'm going to talk
about why. Because even if the plan is a
thousand lines and the code is 1,000
lines, your design discussion might only
be 200 lines. And you get a lot of
opportunities to resteer in that moment.
And so what this looks like is basically
where are we going? What does the final
solution look like and it has, you know,
the current state, the desired end
state, it has the patterns to follow.
How many of you ever like sent off a
coding agent and it like found the wrong
way to do a thing in your codebase and
it followed the bad patterns. Yes.
Right. This is your chance to go read
all the patterns it found that it thinks
are relevant and be like, "Nope, that's
not how we do atomic SQL updates. That's
some engineer that doesn't work here
anymore and it's crazy and everyone
hates it. Go find the way we do it over
there.
Um, it'll keep track of resolved design
decisions that we've made. It will ask
open questions. This is sort of like
taking cloud code plan mode and the ask
user question tool and just brain
dumping it all to a single document that
you can interact with is like moldable
and flexible. Um, Matt Poco has this
idea, he calls it the design concept and
it's this idea of like the thing that is
locked up in this context window that is
the shared understanding between you and
the agent of what's being built and how.
Uh, so we put it in a 200line markdown
artifact. Um, and so we now have human
agent alignment. And the idea here is
like you're forcing the agent to brain
dump out all the things it found, all
the things it wants to do, all the
things it thinks you want and ask you
questions about things it doesn't know.
So you can do brain surgery on the agent
before you proceed downstream. And it's
all about do not outsource the thinking.
You want to give the agent every single
opportunity to show you what it's wrong
about before you go write 2,000 lines of
code. So uh 200 lines instead of a
thousand a little bit more leverage. We
also get better leverage from the
outline. So if design is like where are
we going the structure outline is how do
we get there? Or if you're an engineer
who is miserable because of sitting in
meetings all day, there's the like
architecture review and then there's the
sprint planning meeting. What are we
going to build? And then how do we break
it down into tasks? And so we take our
design and we take it to ticket and the
research. We build up a new context
window and we create the structure
outline. And this is basically highle
overview of the phases. Not the exact
code we're going to write, but just kind
of what it's going to look like, what
order we're going to do the changes in,
and how we're going to test it along the
way. Now, I don't actually test in
between every phase everything I'm
building. But if it's sensitive or if
it's hard or if it's complex, I want to
be able to catch it before it goes and
writes all the code. I want to make sure
each two, three, 400 line block is
correct. Um, and these docs mean lighter
reviews. Instead of reviewing the plan,
this is two things for the same feature.
plan eight pages structure outline
two-ish pages much shorter um I like to
think of this has anyone ever written a
C header file ah file yeah okay so if
the plan is the implementation the
outline is the C header files just
here's the signatures and the new types
that we're changing enough again for you
to see what the agent is thinking and
correct it if it's wrong um and the
reason why we do this is despite like
every single model and trying to prompt
this out and eval the hell out of this
we cannot get models to stop writing
horizontal plans or it like this is the
best way to fix their need to write
horizontal plans. And when I say
horizontal plans, I basically mean you
start with models love to like we're
going to do all the database and then
we're going to do all the services and
then we're going to do all the API and
then we're going to do all the front end
and before you know it, you're on the
other side of,200 lines of code and it's
not working and now you have to go
figure out which part is broken because
there was no nothing really to test
along the way whether the model is
verifying it or whether you the human
are jumping in and checking it's
correct. And so what we've seen work
really really well across orgs of all
sizes um is what I call vertical plans.
This is how I build when I like before
AI I would like make a mock API endpoint
and then get it working in the front end
and then wire that and then mock out the
services layer and then do the database
migration and then put everything
together. And so even though it's the
same amount of code you have these like
checkpoints where you can see if it's
working and if it's not you can pause
and fix it before you go try to do the
rest of it. So these are markdown docs
too. Like you can and should ask for
more detail. They start high level, but
like here's an example of like I don't
think you're going to get this right.
Tell me what you're thinking. And it
like dumped out the types and the
signatures.
Um and then getting better leverage from
the plan itself. I mean again like usual
like we've been doing. We just take that
artifact, we build it up with all the
previous artifacts and then we can go
build the plan. Um and it is the same if
you use create plan. It's the exact same
template, exact same setup, exact same
prompt, but this is a tactical doc for
the agent. we've already done enough
aligning that like I'm just going to
spot check this and then we save the
deep review for the actual code. And so
if you've used any of the RPI plans,
they look like this. It's the model
saying, "Hey, here's all the changes I'm
going to make." Um, the most important
part of this leverage is not just about
you and the agent, though. like human
agent alignment is important and knowing
what the agent's going to do and
correcting that is is good, but it's
also, you know, if you're working with a
team of engineers, we've found a lot of
value from taking these design
discussions, these structure outlines
and review. I said don't review the
plans, but these shorter docs are really
really good. Uh I I am not the code
owner of most of our code at human
layer, my uh co-founder is, and I send
him my design discussions on purpose. We
don't have a required step, but I want
to I want to know that when we get to
code review, it's just going to be like,
"Yep, that's that's what I wanted.
That's it. That's it." So any any of my
bad decisions are headed off on a
200line doc before I've gone and written
the code and gotten it working and I'm
attached to it. And so this is really
really powerful. Um before AI, we would
basically the way another way think
about this is like time savings. You
would say, "Okay, it's a two-day
feature. I got to do all this stuff. The
coding is probably 2 to four hours." If
you just pick up cloud code and use it
to ship for you, you do get some speed
up because now the coding takes 20
minutes. It's still a two-day feature
because I still have to like align with
my team on what we're going to do. I
still have to get a code review and fix
stuff. Maybe I'm working across repos
that I don't personally own and then we
still have to verify and test it. But if
you use AI to help you with your
planning and alignment, then you also
save time there. And I think you get
much better alignment. Um, and so your
code review and rework is also much
shorter because you already know what's
coming. the team that's reviewing it
already kind of like had their chance to
rest steer you and really good teams do
this. It's they have a meeting that's
called architecture review where we
decide, you know, what's our technical
design doc on how we're going to build
this. So, um, as far as testing and
verifying, sorry, I don't have a good
answer for you. It's a whole other talk.
If you went to Drew's talk downstairs,
go find Drew Brunick after this. He will
tell you all about testing and
verifying. Um, let's put this all
together. So, we have these five stages
of research and planning. Um, the
process is basically questions,
research, design, structure, outline,
plan, work tree, implement. Finally, the
pull request. Uh, that didn't make a
very good acronym though, so we just
picked the ones we liked. And, uh, we're
calling this crispy. Uh, so RPI to
crispy. That's the There you go. Um,
what's next? And what did I not have
time to talk about today? Um, three
steps was already a lot for some people
to learn and now there are seven. I
thought we were supposed to make this
easier for teams to learn this and adopt
it. we can talk about how we're like
thinking about that. Um the idea of how
do you measure the impact of doing this
um in engineering teams I think is like
we've been trying to measure developer
productivity for 50 years and we still
don't know how to do it very well. Um
and then it's like if you're a central
kind of platform team rolling out
changes to everybody in your org, how do
you make these prompts better? How do
you make this engineering system better?
I mean, um, we were just talking about
like, oh, every team has a skill now,
and we want to consolidate and make that
shared and let people benefit from each
other's learnings. How do you make that
stuff better without like breaking
somebody's workflow or regressing it for
some some team? Uh, if you want to help
us, if you're in San Francisco and
you're working on critical systems and
you want to like figure out how to get
coding agents to do more, uh, let's
chat. We're also hiring. Um, send us a
note either way. Founders at human
layer.dev.
Uh we're building an IDE that
orchestrates this stuff for you. Uh you
don't need this to get this value out of
this, but this is the kind of stuff
we're working on. Uh if you want to hang
out, I'm doing a sandbox research
hackathon on Saturday. We're going to
just get together with a bunch of cool
builders, test all of the sandbox
providers together, uh and see which
one's the best and then share our
learnings. I'll be also be at the
Daytona Compute Conference. Uh and if
you feel like coming to Miami, uh AI
Engineer Miami is going to be really
fun. will be giving uh the updated
version of this talk with more stuff
that I didn't have time to get to today.
Um, thank you so much to all of you for
your energy to Demetrios and the entire
organizing squad. Good luck.
>> Questions. Who's got a question for Dex?
That was super fast. I like it. I was
very doubtful that you were going to get
through it, but I like
>> All right. I'm I'm curious about reading
the code. Like, it's not scalable,
right? Like, are we are you going to be
saying the same thing in six months? I
mean, six months ago, I said not to read
it. Uh, and so I think everyone who is
saying don't read the code now is going
to be in six months being like, yeah, we
had to throw that out. There's something
there's something in the middle, right?
U we're binary searching through the
space uh of how much of the code should
you read. Um, I think yeah, the idea is
if you still read the code, you can
still get two to 3x speed up. And that's
actually better business outcomes than
uh than going 10x faster and shipping a
bunch of slop and hoping that you know
GPT7 will fix it for you.
>> Yeah, hit things stick. Uh awesome talk.
Um curious your thoughts on like the
software factory. I think it's like
strong DM that's saying the opposite
which is like never have a human read
either side of it. And I think that
pushes us further into eval.
So what is your thinking on that?
>> Yeah, there is a whole class of like
there's a whole rabbit hole you can go
down with like formal verification and
TLA plus or I talked to a guy who's
building a new TA plus that is TA++ that
is like okay what if we don't read the
code? How can we actually like formally
verify everything that's working? Uh, I
think there's a lot more to be built and
I think there's a lot of people right
now who need to ship like code to
production systems faster. So like maybe
someday, but like I used to site Sean
Gro's talk where he was like it's just
the spec. Just write the document that
explains the desired behavior and you
treat the code like it's assembly and
you never read it anymore. Um,
I do not endorse that. Let's put it that
way.
>> We got one more. All right, last one.
Uh I know you mentioned one of the
slides about the like context window and
uh the the dumb zone, right? Uh I know
you researched that like heavily a few
like have have you like gone back to
look at that again to see how true that
still is after certain like context
window especially with like all the
autocompaction they have now and other
methods for that. I mean, I think like
>> for if you have been using AI coding
agents for six to nine months and you
use them for 60 hours a week, like the
dumb zone is not a useful concept to
you. I will regularly go up to 60. I
will regularly like aggressively keep it
below 30. It depends on the complexity
of your task, the amount of instructions
versus information. So like your mileage
may vary. If you are using coding agents
for the first time, this is what I this
is what we teach people is like if you
don't know what to do and you haven't
developed that intuition, then like
shoot to keep it under 40 and if you get
up to 60, like think about wrapping it
up and like you can keep iterating on
the same doc. That's what's also nice
about these is like we don't use the
built-in compaction because everything
that matters is going into static assets
and so you can always resume from where
you left off without having to worry
about the quality of an autocompact or
manual compact.
>> Brilliant, Dex.
Well done, dude. work.
>> Thank you. Let's give it up for him.
Huh? Yes.
And now
the final act of the day. We've got
Harrison and Sam coming up. It's rare
that you get two folks of this caliber
on the stage at the same time. We
managed to do it. So, I'm going to
present Sam Parti and Harrison Chase.
get on up to this stage and let's give
them a big round of applause.
>> These guys need no introduction.
>> Welcome, dude.
>> Here's this for you.
>> Oh, I get the mic.
>> Way too nice of an introduction. Do I
need this?
>> Do I get a mic?
>> I think we both have mics.
>> Oh, I don't think I need this.
>> I don't need it. All right, we're
figuring this out live. Um, hello. My
name's uh Harrison Chase. I'm the
co-founder and CEO of Langchain and I
have the clicker here which I'm giving
to my friend Sam.
>> Thank you for announcing that. Hi, I'm
Sam Party. I'm CTO and co-founder of
arcade.dev. Uh, and today we're going to
talk about general purpose agents and
something that Harris and I have talked
about for a long time, which is why
coding agents
are actually the foundation for general
purpose agents. This might not
immediately make sense, but hopefully
over the course of the talk it does make
more sense.
So what is a coding agent? What does it
help you do? Things that we use every
single day, right? Cloud code, yada
yada. What does it have access to? A
file system. It reads and writes files.
It is able to over time over its
iterations keep and store not only
things like memory, but just task
execution data in a workspace local to
itself. And so in doing so, it's able to
keep and store things that as it's
working on, it can go back and reference
and keep not in its context window, but
in something that is a retrievable
object. And so this is a a paradigm that
you can extend not only through just
simple search like rag, but all the way
through tool calling. And we'll show
over the course of the talk how it
extends through a bunch of different
paradigms as well. Now, the point of the
talk is actually also to get you to a
general purpose agent. Not just
something that works on your laptop for
one user, but something that works for
an entire organization for all of your
users. And so, how do you do that? Well,
you start with a coding agent. And
that's the primary object of what
Harrison's going to talk about today.
So, what are we going to talk about?
We're going to talk about two things.
First, Harrison's going to talk about
the agent harness and why it's important
and why this gives you the coding agent
paradigm. why this gives you a basis for
what you need for that cloud code like
experience and then I will talk about
the tool runtime and what's necessary
there to make these two things combine
into what is necessary in our view for a
general purpose agent for your company
not only for yourself but for your
company for your friends for your users
what have you
these two things that we can say when we
put together make a general purpose
agent uh have different responsibilities
and they might seem like they're really
similar. It might seem like cloud code
calls tools and reads and writes files
through tools or that it extends its
memory through some interface through
the tool runtime when actually these two
things actually have very different
responsibilities and have an incredible
responsibility in the foundation of a
general agent. So first Harrison's going
to talk about that agent harness piece
and that is the foundation that gives
you that cloud code like experience and
then I will talk about the next piece
that brings it out uh the general
purpose agent as well.
Cool. So agent harness is a fun term to
describe the scaffolding around the
model that lets it interact with the
environment and do things. And so I want
to talk a little bit about how we think
about agent harnesses at Langchain. How
we've thought about building our own
agent harness called deep agents. Um and
then some of the things that we've added
into it which are very similar to things
that are in other agent harnesses like
cloud code or codecs or things like
that. So uh what is an agent? Most
people would probably technically define
an agent as an LLM running in a loop
calling tools. Uh so so what is the
difference between that and an agent
harness? Basically an agent harness adds
more things in. Um so you can think of
it as having more batteries included.
And so what are some of the things that
it adds in? One of them very commonly is
a planning tool or instructions for
doing planning. Um
another uh very common component is file
system tools. Uh so these are for
interacting with the file systems. These
can be to read and write um uh search
files, glob GP files, depending on the
hardness that you're using. It may have
a few of these. It may have a lot of
these. That kind of depends um on on
what else it has uh in terms of kind of
like code execution tools because
sometimes you can just execute code to
do the same thing. Um and and and the
file system is often times where the
agent definition is actually stored. So
you can represent an agent as basically
an agent.mmd and skills and an mcp.json.
And if you think about all these things
that you use in coding agents to define
the code to to kind of like guide the
coding agents to do things, I would
argue that's basically how you can
define a custom agent. You can kind of
think as your of your coding agents as
custom agents in some way.
Um, sub aents are another aspect of this
that can also kind of like be defined by
by files on disk or or or through some
other method.
Um, we build a bunch of open source
things at Langchain and that's kind of
evolved over the years as the whole
space has evolved. Um, we started off
with Langchain in the middle actually as
kind of like an agent framework and then
we actually built Langraph as a lower
level kind of like agent runtime. So we
think of a framework mostly concerned
with abstractions and integrations. Um
we we think of uh langraph our runtime
as more infrastructure almost. It has
durable execution. It has streaming. It
has human in the loop. It has
persistence. And then recently we
started on deep agents which we think as
as as this agent harness. And it really
has more of of these batteries uh
included things.
So what's actually in a harness? And I
want to talk about this in a little bit
more detail. Um so we talked about file
system. So these are the six that we
have in deep agents. We have uh list,
read, write, edit, glob, and gp other
agent harnesses. So this is pretty
heavily based off of cloud code. So it
actually has all of those. Codeex has a
smaller subset. So it I think just has I
think it just has read and write and
then it relies on uh using the bash tool
for for other options. So you can pick
and choose which ones uh you want here.
Um one of the really cool things that we
added in deep agents that is pretty
unique is that we have this concept of
what we call kind of like a pluggable
backend. So when you run cloud code, it
runs locally against your file system
like your real file system that you
have. What we have in uh deep agents is
is that file system. It it can be your
real file system or it can be a virtual
file system. So we can use a database to
store uh quote unquote files. So you
store it in a database but you represent
it as a file system to the agent because
that's what it knows and that's what it
interacts with. This also makes it easy
to run uh deep agents remotely because
you can just plug it into a sandbox or
something where the files are stored um
uh elsewhere.
Um we we have a planning tool in deep
agents. This is a really simple tool.
All it does is it asks the LLM to
generate a plan. It doesn't even save
the plan. It just puts that plan in the
in the LLM's context window. It kind of
it's like it's taking notes to itself as
it goes along. Um, this is pretty
heavily based off of Cloud Code's
planning tool as well. Other agents uh
do things where they actually write the
plan down to a markdown file. That's
obviously a much more persistent way of
of keeping it. Um, and uh but but a lot
of the planning tool is really just to
have the agent think about the plan and
put it in the context window so that it
informs future generations.
We have sub agents in uh in deep agents.
They work pretty similar to sub aents in
other agent harnesses. The um the really
useful thing that sub agents do is they
have this context isolation where you
give a sub agent a task and it just sees
that task. It doesn't see anything
previously and all the work it does. The
main agent doesn't see any of that. It
just sees the final result. And so
that's really good for spinning up a
bunch of these in parallel and having
them just work on things in a very
focused way and then they come back and
report the main result. Um fun kind of
like side note there there can
absolutely be communication issues here.
So, you need the main agent to be
specific about what the sub aent should
do. And the sub agent needs to respond
with the right info. Um, if there's
breakdowns in either of those, then this
doesn't work as intended. Skills. Uh, so
we support skills. Most coding agents
support skills. They're pretty cool and
a nice way to package up instructions
and tools in a way where you can kind of
like discover um them as you go along.
Um,
some of the things that we do around
kind of like context engineering that
are built into a harness. And again,
this is what I mean by harnesses comes
with more batteries included. This is
this is kind of beyond the LLM just
running in a loop calling tools. One of
the things we do is that I think other
harnesses do as well is offload large
tool results to files. So rather than
see like a massive JSON file that's
returned from a tool, we'll actually
just put that in a file, show you the
first 100 lines, say here you go. If you
want to see more, you can read the file
and then and then it can explore it that
way. So this prevents you from kind of
like blowing up your context window
quickly and and lets the LLM a lot of
this is in spirit of giving the LLM more
control over managing its own context
window. For compaction, uh what we do is
when you get to a certain uh point
relative to the context window size, we
do a compaction step. We save all the
original messages into the file system
so that if it wants to go look at those
later, it absolutely can. We're also
thinking about giving it a tool that
will let it trigger its own compaction.
Um, so again in the spirit of giving the
LLM more control over its own context
window. Human in the loop's really
important. We built deep agents on top
of uh langraph. Um, and so it naturally
supports pretty robust human loop
controls and so we have a nice little
config where you can specify whether you
want tools to interrupt before they are
executed or not.
And with that, I'm going to hand it over
to Sam to talk more about some tool
stuff.
>> Well done. So, human loop is actually a
really good jumping off point. Um,
because it's one of the points at which
the harness needs to communicate with
something that's other than the file
system of that agent. Um, and so what
you just heard from Harrison a lot was
how that agent can utilize those local
aspects of the computer. Um, from
everything from just writing and reading
a file to like something like computer
use, right? And so these are necessary
aspects that the harness provides. And
so where does the tool runtime come in
after that? What is necessary besides
that local aspect of a standard IO type
MCP server working with a a harness,
right? And really the essence is in the
multi-user and authentication
authorization and third party services
and that the things your users or you
want to be able to use. And so, how do I
access my data and secure uh my services
securely that aren't on my local
computer or that my users want to use
with my agent uh that aren't local to
their computer.
So, I'll give you an example of this. Uh
let's say you're booking a flight, okay?
And you you want to do so with an agent.
And I know this might seem not
realistic, but this is actually
something that an enterprise company of
ours does now with agents. Um, so you
have to check a calendar. How do you
know which calendar, Outlook or Google?
How do you sign in as that user? If
you're giving this agent to a company,
how does that company use their SSO to
sign into that agent?
Finding flights, do you have an
integration with that? You might have an
MCP server, but are you going to surface
all of the flights and the flights that
are particularly relevant for that
particular user? What happens when you
log into Amazon.com? It's your Amazon.
It's the one that has the relevant
results for you. It has personalized
results with your information curtailing
those specific results. Why don't agents
do that yet?
Book the flight, actually pay for it.
Payment mechanisms.
Notifying your team on Slack. Once
again, off integration, off integration,
off integration, off integration. This
is the necessary evil
that the tool runtime is responsible for
is the dirty work of making sure that
every system inside of your company,
every enterprise that uses this
particular oneoff OOTH server for their
one-off service and this integration
here, there and beyond all integrate
with your agent properly that's running
inside of the harness. This runtime has
that responsibility of both that
authentication and authorization layer
as well as that integration layer. These
two can't be separated because now the
agent is an intermediary that you can't
take out of the equation. It's no longer
just a web app with social signin you
can use a user token for. And why is
this? Well, there's two failure patterns
we see. One is a service token. So what
happens with a service token? Well, it's
either got incredibly elevated
privileges to the point where no CISO is
going to let your product be bought at
enterprise or it's got so low privileges
your agent's not useful and it's only
good for one maybe local user on their
laptop. And that could be helpful,
right, for that single user. But when
you want to deploy an agent firmwide,
how are you having that firm's SSO or
login making sure that that particular
user is using that particular agent? And
then even more than that, authorizing
them to access their Google. It's not
just the front door off C that is. It's
the authorizing
them to access their own Google. And so
there's two forms here that that
integration can't be separated from now
that the agent is an intermediary.
This ends up looking what like what we
call delegated agent authorization.
Essentially, you're not giving it a user
token. You're giving it a portion of
your user token for as many services as
there are. The way we've approached this
is that Arcade will hold uh hold one
token for the subset of permissions
you've authorized for that particular
agent at that particular time for that
user for that service. So we've covered
both of those doors such that the least
level of privilege is given to that
agent for that particular user in that
particular company. And in doing so,
it's the same model that you would have
had for a website with Octa in the front
door and had no off Z. But now an agent
has the exact same profile that a CISO
has approved for the last 15 years.
And so what does this actually look like
in code, which is what I always wish
people did in talks when they talked at
this kind of level. Uh what does this
look like in code? Well, this is an
example of a tool
to go to Reddit. And now, it actually
isn't the whole tool, okay? It's just
basically the function signature, but it
is the part of the tool that specifies
the exact level of privilege needed by
this action that the agent's going to
take. And in doing so, the agent now can
say, does this user have that privilege
for that service
in this database?
And in doing so, you can now say with
certainty that no agent will take any
action that an authorized user did not
authorize them to take and that you do
not have a log of them saying yes to.
And human in the loop of the agent
harness is a big part of this because
how do you surface when the runtime says
no to the user?
We do this in a Slack agent that a lot
of enterprises use. What if it's just
Yeah. So I forgot that I had animations
in this slide. It's not it's not the
user's token for that service. It's a
delegated subset.
You don't want to give an agent RM-rf to
your Google Drive. That's a bad idea.
Giving them delete is almost never a
good idea. And so why delegate them that
privilege with your user token you've
been sticking in your environment
variables on your laptop for a standard
IO server, which stopped doing that by
the way, but
please, someone posted one on LinkedIn
the other day. It's like, man, I can log
in as you right now. Um, but the user,
it's not the user token. It's a subset.
And even if it's just a secret, once
again, please don't put this
in your environment variables. Instead,
put them in a secret store. In the case
of Arcade, we've made it so that each
function can be labeled with the secret
name, and that can be for an org,
project, or a user. And so, you have
multiple levels of control over where
that secret gets applied.
Moving on, it's injected. It's not in
context.
But I'm gonna Well, I probably should
have paused there, shouldn't I? Uh,
contextual access is another part of
this. So, what if you already have an
arbback system? What if you already have
some way you do PII? If you already have
some way you do named entity recognition
and you don't want to replace it.
Well, what we can do is now take your
tools and say pre and postexecute,
what do you want to have happen? and in
doing so hook into your entitlement
system or your Keraro system that's been
there for 40 years. It's this leg work
that the tool runtime is responsible for
and takes care of when you actually want
to take your agent and go sell it to an
enterprise.
And so in doing so, it gives the agent
harness an ability to say, I'm positive
that this is that user at this time for
this action with this level of privilege
to go out into the world and take some
action on behalf of that user. Not just
for that user, but as that user. It's
probably the most important part. Doing
work for the user is good. Doing work as
the user is much better. in many cases
because in doing so you're doing their
work for them, not a bot, not a service
token that's over or underprivileged.
You're doing their work as them, which
is usually much nicer, sending the email
as you instead of making you copy paste,
for example.
What this ends up looking like is
something along the lines of this
diagram. I tried to make this as
uncomplicated as I could, but obviously
it's a pretty big system. So, I will say
there's a Helm chart you can read, which
for me is much easier. However, you can
see some of the things that are part of
the runtime here. I mentioned the
connection to enterprise systems, but I
feel like most people can imagine an MCP
server writing a tool that's privileged
for their system. What's a little bit
harder is actually those layers of the
registry access. How do I manage all of
these things? How do I do this at an
enterprise? Um, and that's what you see
in the core on the right hand side
there.
All of this of course connects directly
to those harnesses that you see. Put it
into lang chain, put it into langraph if
you're writing it from scratch or take
deep agents and just hook up the MCP
server directly. Put it in a skill name
the MCP servers and it works
immediately.
This is what that looks like. You can
basically just go inside of Arcade and
use our gateway, which essentially takes
multiple MCP servers and says, "I want a
new MCP server. Give me that tool, that
tool, GitHub, Google, Microsoft, this,
make an MCP server. Now serve it on the
internet securely." That's what a
gateway does. And it looks something
like that. And then you can take that
URL and that slug and plug it right into
line chain and use it immediately
or cloud code or what have you. Deep
agents is pretty great.
So bringing this all together and we'll
talk about something we've recently done
together to kind of bring this even more
together. But these two pieces are
distinct in the fact that they're
responsible for major pieces of making
an agent general. and the purpose of
that agent general. Hopefully that has
come through.
>> And so talking a little bit about uh
what this looks like in a general
purpose world. One of the things that we
have a really good integration for is
what we call agent builder and arcade.
So we talked about how this underlying
harness which is very similar to coding
agent harnesses is is can in fact power
general purpose agents. Um, I don't uh I
don't really think the interface for
general purpose agent is in the
terminal. Uh, I think that's um I don't
think my mom would use that. I think
there's a different interface that other
people would and I think you see some
ideas with this with with with Manis and
Claude Co-work kind of like pushing in
this direction of what does a more
userfriendly interface for these things
look like? And and so that's what agent
builder is. It's powered by deep agents.
You can connect to how how many tools
does arcade have? thousand
>> over 8,000
>> over 8,000. Okay. You can connect to
over 8,000 tools uh through there as
well. Um and uh and and what it is is
basically a way to create agents in in a
no code way by just chatting with them.
One of the things that's built into to
agent builder is this memory aspect. The
memory is just done by modifying the
files on the file system. We talked
about how you can represent agents as
files on a file system with agent.mmd
and skills and sub aagents and mcp.json.
And so when you talk to this agent, all
it does is it just modifies those files
and it it creates and evolves its
definition of an agent along the way. So
we have a number of very general purpose
templates here. Uh so the where is it?
The email assistant is one that I use uh
I use daily. I no longer check my email.
I check my email.
>> He actually does use it. I actually yeah
I I've been I' I was using it I've been
using it for like a year and a half. It
started
>> it's actually been a while since we did
agent inbox.
>> It's it's evolved a lot. It started off
on Langchain and then went to Langraph
and then went to Deep Agent and now it's
an agent builder and um and and and uh
uh LinkedIn recruiter is a good one as
well that that we use to kind of like
source candidates. We're hiring by the
way. Uh nice plug for that. Um
>> the social media one's fun too.
>> What?
>> The social media one's fun too. You can,
there's one that someone put out
recently to impersonate anyone you want
on social media, which may or may not be
a great idea, but it is very fun to do.
>> Um, this is the integration that you see
right here. Essentially, it's a very
similar page to what you've seen before.
This will be coming out soon, but
essentially, it'll enable this already
really easy to use interface to just
access all of the tools in Arcade.
Hence, giving all of the deep agents
that are inside of there with those easy
to use templates a ton of different
tools to be able to use. So, uh,
hopefully most people can see how
that'll be really fun. Um, and an easier
to use interface like your mom would
use.
>> Yeah. Yeah. We've done integrations for
a while, but this is definitely the
tightest one. And so, excited to get
that. And maybe just wrapping things up
with uh three real simple takeaways.
Tools really matter. Um, and if you want
to use tools in a productionready way,
use Arcade. Like the design around the
tools. You guys wrote a really I don't
know whether it was a blog post or
website, but you had like 80 different
like tips and tricks for tools.
>> Patterns you can check out online.
Basically just things we've learned
about building tools since the past two
and a half years.
>> Um two, the harness matters. So this is
this is what's powering the agent under
the hood. Um you can use lingchain deep
agents or the best part is it's fully
open source. So you can uh fork it and
then modify it as as you wish. We have
lots of middleware to hook in and
control that. And if you want to use
them together and you don't want to code
at all, but you want to get the power of
these agents, use agent builder. Um, and
yeah,
>> that's pretty much it.
>> That's pretty much all. Yeah. Thank you
guys for coming.
>> All right.
>> Nice.
Who's got a question?
>> We have 15 seconds left. Come on. That
was pretty good, right? We timed that
up.
>> Perfect. And funny story, the reason I
got Harrison to give this talk is I
prompt injected his little Google agent.
>> I can't believe you said that.
>> This is great, guys. And the combination
makes a lot of sense. I'm I'm curious
like how you think about, you know, the
issue of a legitimately authorized tool
used maliciously or with emergent
misalignment. You know, like Carrison,
if you're, you know, someone's sending
you a prompt inject in your email that
then does a thing that does a thing or
the agent gets confused. Yep.
>> And I'm just curious how you're
>> approaching that.
>> I can talk about some of what we do. You
can talk about what some of you do. I
think we both have different approaches.
So, um, one of the things that's in
agent builder is, uh, basically
guardrails about what tools can and
cannot get executed automatically. and
by default uh tools with write
operations um uh can't um and so uh yeah
like sending emails I'm still in the
loop I go in and improve um editing its
own memories um you can toggle and you
can toggle this on and off so if you
want to be riskier but by default uh
anything with a write operation is
generally human in the loop
>> it's a great example of how now uh once
again it they're both nec like the the
file system there that's controlling the
read and write right That's not in the
tool definition themselves. That's in
the agent harness layer. And then at our
layer, we have things like custom
verifier. So when someone clicks a link
to authorize, we're going to either make
you go to your IDP, us, or Langmith in
the case of agent builder, we're going
to make you go to something to say you
are you first, no matter what, and then
we'll make you authorized to Google to
send your email. And that was learned
the hard way. So it's a very good
question.
>> Yeah, thanks. Awesome talk. um you
mentioned kind of model or agent that
your mom would want to use very similar
to what Peter Steinberg says uh with
openclaw and so curious your thoughts on
how you see this space evolving if you
two are kind of converging and manis and
all of those it seems like this is going
to be the space for the next 90 days at
least
>> yeah well
>> it's actually a really long time thank
you
>> I mean It's funny that you say that
because like so we released agent
builder the first version in kind of
like um in whatever alpha beta thing uh
probably around the time like some
initial early version of open claw came
out but like before it exploded and uh
since then that's that's like informed
our northstar of where we want to go a
lot like I think they did a lot of
things really really well um I think
like uh
>> did a lot of things
>> yeah like chat being the primary
interface is is is I think a really good
one there I think this idea of like how
you expose the agent to the external
world is also really interesting. I was
chatting with Sam about like if I create
an agent and expose it to Sam does it
use does it use Sam's credentials as
like a pass through or does the agent
have its own kind of like identity? And
I think like with Open Claw I think we
saw actually these agents take on their
own identity which I think was really
interesting and not at all what we'd
seen kind of like previously.
Previously, we'd seen everyone always
wanted to pass their credentials
through. And now with OpenCloud, there's
this idea of like an agent identity and
it has its memory and it has its
credentials and that's really
interesting and I don't know what it
means and it'll probably figure out in
90 days or or probably more or something
like that. Um, but yeah, I mean I think
pretty clearly the agent of the future
have uh they have they have they have uh
they can write and execute code. They
have some aspect of memory. They're
connected to a bunch of tools. they're
exposed through different services.
I think there'll be two types. Some that
have their own identity, some that take
on their users's identity. Um where I I
guess like maybe uh one thing that I
haven't said that is more future
looking. One of the things that we do in
agent builder that is distinctive is we
have this concept of agents that are
triggered by events. So like running in
the background ambiently. And we have
this concept of an inbox where you go in
and you see all the agents that are
stuck and need human approval for tool
calls and stuff.
>> Well, it channels an open claw kind of.
>> Okay. I haven't I actually I should go
check that out then. Yeah, see I'm
already updating my belief today. So,
but but I think this idea of agents
running in the background and then
pinging you when they they need help
like kind of like uh yeah, they they
push things to you rather than you go in
and kind of like pull. I think I think
that's maybe where more and more things
will go will go.
>> I think what a lot of people saw with
Open Call too is that it was really
really cool, but the reason you need to
buy a Mac Mini is that there's things
that need to be figured out.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and we're still figuring that out.
The agent identity piece is really
important. Um, I think we're still in in
many ways learning how to deploy agents
that do stuff as you, right? I think the
agent identity is another piece that
needs to get figured out that in
addition to something like delegated off
we need to be able to do so that like
Harrison said there can be a remote
memory service that says oh it's that
agent for that user that is using this
service and they can pull that specific
memory only for that user or only for
the org but right now that is still an
early topic.
All right, before we get to the next
question, I just have a friendly
announcement.
>> I can't see anyone.
>> Me in the back over here. So, we've got
a booth crawl happening right after this
Q&A. Make sure to grab a ticket for
drinks when you're leaving. There's
going to be a few people handing them
out. All right, next question.
>> Right, thanks guys for the presentation.
My question is about off and with MCPs
and all. We I work in ITS ops. One of
the things we've seen is that when our
agent tries there's a case where there's
like a a manager that's taking care of
someone that went on vacation and they
need to run an anible like our agent
wants to run an Ansible playbook but
they don't have the permission so they
have to go through like procurement and
whatnot and have you guys seen a way
where you could the agent could say like
hey this person will definitely get
permission and we really just want to
run this one thing to solve and mitigate
the issue.
>> You should use arcade.
Um yes, we've seen that a lot. That is
that is a core issue. So essentially
what is being described as I believe it
is uh look this person is running this
workflow with this token and now this
person's on vacation. Now this manager
is responsible for it or something like
that and now I have no visibility or
chain of command over this workflow and
so now how do I see which user did what
and how do I do that now if they're not
there? Is that roughly correct?
>> Yeah. It's also like they don't have the
permissions. Yeah, exactly. So, even
worse, right, they haven't been
delegated those specific permissions.
Only that one person that you know
they've gotten fired or they're on
vacation or what have you. We've
actually seen that in both cases. Um,
and how do you change or revoke even
worse like if they got fired, how do you
revoke them? Um, that is functionality
that we've built again the hard way of
figuring it out. Uh, so you basically
need all of those things for your agent.
You need to be able to say that token
for that user is no longer viable
because they got fired or this person's
on vacation. I need to be able to have a
step up authorization flow that
authorizes a new user to do this exact
thing. Um, and delegating that token and
enforcing that at runtime um is a
non-trivial challenge. I will tell you
that it has been a lot of fun to learn a
ton about off. I'll tell you that. I'm
not being sarcastic at all. But yes,
that is a very common problem at
enterprises for sure, especially in IT
departments.
>> Hi,
thank you for um I'm back here too. For
um enterprises that are worried about
sending their private data to the public
AI companies, um can you run your own
LLMs on prem with all of this stuff?
>> Yes. So that is a big part of uh why we
can work well together is that there are
companies that deploy everything we're
talking about today entirely inside
their VPC. Um I don't think you take
care of models though. I mean
>> no we don't do models. The only thing
I'd say is like for a lot of these agent
harnesses the models do have to be good
enough to actually take advantage of all
the tools that they're given. Um we're
doing some stuff to benchmark different
open source models on on deep agents and
see where they see where they stack up.
But like, you know, to be honest, if
you're using OpenAI or Anthropic right
now, those are going to have the biggest
kind of like performance. Um, I am
really really excited for an open source
model that can reliably drive these
harness.
>> GLM Kimmy.
>> Um, we hooked it up the other day and it
wasn't amazing, but we're doing more
rigorous testing.
>> I've used GLM before. Uh, personally, I
I will say there's a severe deg if
you're going from 4.6 Opus to anything
pretty much right now. It's you're going
to have a tough time.
in my opinion.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey Sam, just follow up. You touched on
the Mac Mini. Um, which I saw something
walking in here that was really
interesting. Uh, they said that people
are actually buying Mac minis just for
access to iMessage.
>> Blue bubble.
>> Yeah. Right. And going through the CLI
interface to do that. So, I think
everything you touched on is cool, but I
think that's another avenue that's going
to explode, too.
>> So, skills, right? So, Bluebubble and a
lot of those work through skills, right?
and they use the CLI and I personally
when I I can I contributed a PR it got
closed by Claudinator automatically
somehow uh Peter's on it but uh the
thing that you're talking about with the
CLI skills a lot of people do also feel
uncomfortable with CLI access like shell
command access and that is also why
they're buying that which is a great
point I also bought a Mac mini for the
blue bubble part because uh of exactly
that thing so that is very through. I
will say it's a lot of fun. Channels are
a really interesting concept. Um, with
where we're going in agent builder, I
think that's going to be a really
interesting topic to be discussed. But I
think, uh, especially OpenClaw kind of
nailed it. Uh, it really scorched the
earth to be honest with you. If you look
at the code base, I mean, it is full.
Let's put it that way. Um, but that
concept of channels in particular that
allows you to do that like Bluebubble or
whatever iMessage thing that you're
using to be able to do that on the CLI.
Um, it's an important part of where
we're going. And it's not just MCPS.
It's also skills on the CLI. It's a good
point.
>> Thanks for doing this, guys. I
appreciate you so much. Give it up for
him. Huh?
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
Awesome. All right.
We've got the booth hangout. There's
food. There's drinks. I want to say
thank you all for coming. This was an
awesome day. I learned a ton. Hopefully
you learned a ton. And I'll let you go.
Maybe I could tell one joke. I told it
earlier, but there was only like five
people here. So I Dex is in. Okay. So I
was talking with Claude Code and I said,
"Hey, choose a random number between 1
and 50." And it said, "All right, 32."
And I went, "That's it. For the next 32
days, we're not going to talk." I cut
off all communication. You and I were
finished. And then it said, "Can I
choose another number?" And I I thought,
"Wow, that's so sweet. Of course you
can. Go ahead, choose." And it said 50.
So have a great day. You all are
awesome. Enjoyed the side quests that
are to come.
>> Okay, man.